<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:44:22 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:44:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 05</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 5 - Superstorm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The superstorm began long before social media, before radio, before the first stories flickered against cave walls. There was no narrative, no protagonist seeking revenge, no monster with intent. Only heat rising from water, vapor becoming cloud, air feeding on air until motion became inevitable - natural interactions as old as the planet itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For centuries the Gulf had warmed, each year storing energy, releasing it in fits, then resetting to a new normal a degree closer to ruin. The atmosphere - an ocean we live at the bottom of - moved according to laws more ancient than our knowing. Where it brushed the sea, a spiral began. From orbit, it thickened: a white convulsion swelling to blot the curve of the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellites recorded the pressure drop, numbers slipping past precedent, but the data could no longer describe what existed below. The language of measurement broke first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hurricane isn’t angry. It has no morality. No justice. It cannot be reasoned with. It doesn’t care about followers or forecasts. It simply is - vast, unalive, consuming without hunger - simple systems combining into incomprehensible design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the wind arrived, and the sky was erased. Color fled. Horizon dissolved. Roofs peeled like fruit skin, walls bowed, towers folded. Everything moved; nowhere remained. Roads liquefied into canals. Water and sky became one continuous violence, their boundary only the white teeth of the gusts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For twenty hours - though time had lost meaning - the storm held one unbroken note. Reality, as we comprehend it, wavered. Rain didn’t fall; it traveled sideways, carving trenches without reason, driving rivers from their beds into madness. Seawalls fell. Houses lifted and vanished. The ocean climbed stairs, found ceilings, pried walls apart. Yachts, shrimp boats, even freight containers skipped inland like stones and lay still, marooned of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From above, an eye that was not an eye opened: twenty-five miles wide, a perfect geometry, a stillness that could not last. Then the opposite wall made landfall, and the impossible resumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By morning, the Archipelago was a smear of mud and debris. The precise geometry of grids and cul-de-sacs erased. Canals redrawn by surge and silt. Mangroves, cordgrass, and pink houses - gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sea did not notice. It was beyond such negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, the Louisiana Branch of the Bureau of Truth issued a priority statement: 
	&lt;em&gt;“The Florida Archipelago Demonstrates Resilience After Historic Weather Anomaly - A Clean Slate for Growth.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alethia tagged it, “&lt;strong&gt;Highly shareable&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/21/HurricaneDavid-05</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/21/HurricaneDavid-05</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 04</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 4 - Calm is Contagious&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t so much a blue sky as a blue &lt;em&gt;dome&lt;/em&gt;, trapping the sun and moisture alike to unbearable degree. It was a brilliant sapphire color that couldn’t be looked directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dome didn’t allow for a single gust of relief. The air couldn’t get a breath in under all the intensity. The mangroves sagged under their own weight, their leaves glued together. Further up, a heron stood in the shallows, motionless as a lawn ornament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only ripple on the canal’s surface was from the autonomous drone, now making its way toward David with machine precision. David bent over the bodega boat and waved his ID in the air, vaguely over what looked like where its electronics might be housed. The drone, bobbing gently in the canal, beeped an affirmation and the lid slid back, exposing David’s order, doubled-bagged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package was warm to the touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat’s lid closed and the craft gracefully pivoted in the water, re-orienting itself toward the open end of the inlet before picking up speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the water higher? He couldn’t be sure; David was still getting used to the waterfront here. It was probably just the tides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked around him. As best as David could tell, he and the drone were the only moving things in the entire development. He exhaled in frustration. The entire damn region was in hysterics. He had watched, forlornly, as several of his neighbors boarded up their windows and fled before he could properly introduce himself. He’d have to have a conversation about the dangers of disinformation and the resulting panic cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d role-played a half dozen Bureau storm drills &lt;em&gt;this week alone&lt;/em&gt;. This “event” was trending strongly to just another coastal evacuation hype cycles; a bunch of data spikes that would be smoothed out in the following days as cooler heads prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David was surprised to vividly remember the last time he saw his mother. He was suddenly a teen again, watching her leave with other volunteers to shore up a sandbag levee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s watch chirped, pulling him from the memory. He’d configured Alethia to provide regular confidence level updates. Checking his wrist, he saw the probability for a positive outcome it was still holding above 50%; not great, but still no reason for panic, either. 
He turned and retraced his path to his new house. It was a small, but tidy, single-story coastal contemporary. Best of all, it was right along the water, like he had always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door unlocked satisfyingly as he approached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside, he kicked off his sandals by the door and crossed the terrazzo floor to the kitchen. After the Satan’s snow globe outside, the cool tile of the kitchen on his feet was heavenly. There were a couple items already on the island; the owner papers for achieving 100% vestment, with “Congratulations on achieving coastal residency!” headlining the stack. There was a new company credit card with its documentation. The welcome pack even had a ‘CALM IS CONTAGIOUS’ mug like the ones they had at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pushed those aside to make room for the takeout on his countertop. The bag’s crinkle echoed unsatisfactorily across unfurnished space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David leaned over the island. Taking in the empty expanse, he found it wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“House,” he said, addressing the room, “Call Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house acknowledged. The call rang once, twice, and then the sound of wind answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go for Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Declan, dude! Would you believe it? I’m calling from my own house! You should come over. What does your night look like?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a pause on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No bueneo” Declan finally answered, “I’m headed upstate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Upstate!? What’d you have going on with those panhandlers?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; know about the storm, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You bailed? Seriously? Over what, a little rain? I thought you were smarter than that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David, they’re saying this one is a Cat 5. Maybe bigger. Surge estimates are off the charts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cat 5? We don’t use those terms anymore. That’s sensationalist language. I see all the streams, I was cross-correlating expert sentiment just yesterday. It’s an over-reaction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The charts-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whose charts?! We make the charts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, we’re seeing a high probability of the inner eyewall weakening and collapsing before it gets anywhere near shore. There’s no way. &lt;em&gt;There’s just no way&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was silence on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And don’t even get me started about how inaccurate we’ve seen the tracking models.” 
Another pause. The house did its best to filter out the sound of wind on the other end, but pops and hisses still peppered the other side of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David, you should consider getting out, man, while you still can. I’ll see you when I see you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house confirmed the dropped connection in its neutral tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bah!” David exclaimed, rubbing the back of his head in frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David grabbed a beer from the fridge, snatched the bag of food off the counter, and stormed out the rear sliding doors. On the back patio he scanned the horizon. It was empty. Not even a container ship in sight. Just a few wispy, delicate streaks of white where the edge of the world met the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He checked his watch. No change. Still above 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David toasted the sky, and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 4 - Check back tomorrow for the final installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/20/HurricaneDavid-04</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/20/HurricaneDavid-04</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Vindication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analyst break-room coffee wasn’t better, but it came with a perk: instead of cardboard cups, they had real mugs, stamped with the Bureau’s slogan, &lt;em&gt;CALM IS CONTAGIOUS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam curled from David’s mug as he climbed the stadium seating of the command room - a college lecture hall as if it were built by defense contractors. The lighting was dim. The space was almost entirely lit by the floor-to-ceiling monitors comprising the front wall. It pulsed with blues and reds, trending terms, sentiment analysis broken out by geography, ideology, education, and any of two dozen more demographics summarized in pixel form; the sum total of the world’s anxiety abbreviated as light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the command center was quiet - the hum of the HVAC indistinguishable from whatever fan noise came from the dozens of computers in the room, the whir occasionally punctuated by flurries of keyboard assaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no assigned seats,technically, but people are creatures of habit. Maya was already at her usual spot, along the left edge and about half way to the top. She was staring intently at her space’s screen, tapping aggressively - summoning forth modals and then, summarily, dismissing them with a flick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David slid into the empty seat next to hers, its screen waking when it detected activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Miss me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya only grunted an acknowledgment, still pursuing something he couldn’t see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tilted his head toward the front wall. “How’s our girl today?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked up in irritation. “She’s being a drama queen. It’s been yellow alerts non-stop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as he logged in, an alert covered David’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The f-.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-see? It’s been like this since I started my shift at 5am. It’s got all the signs of an economic rumor cascade.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gulf side?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh. Home-grown and running hot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hmmm.” David skimmed the included detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was a seawall-crack shock clip. I cross-checked the footage. It is legit; it’s not doctored. The actual impact, though, is pretty slight. There is flooding in the lower 37th zone, but it’s contained; a localized, not systemic, failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But it looks bad, and the clip is breaking containment. It’s that time of year - old axes out again. Alethia keeps readjusting feed weights and dropping chaff. She’s managed to keep it off trending lists so far, but it’s starting to go viral on its own merits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sentiment acceleration?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look who’s been reading their manual! But yeah, could be big. People love any reason to short archipelago real estate for a quick buck. Hashtags are &lt;em&gt;#floridaFail, #sunkenAssets&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;#waterSoWet&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of what Maya was saying was huge. If the Archipelago looked unstable, insurers would re-price everything by the next morning. Markets would collapse. Panic had bankrupted just as many banks as storms did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, is there someone on the seawall video?” Alethia’s algorithm must have tripped over some threshold and started recruiting additional analysts for help. José, down in front, was scanning around the room for confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Over here-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got it,” David cut in, “Maya and I are tag-teaming it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked at David, skeptically. “You sure about that, rookie? Confidence index is at 62.5% and falling. We’ll have a sell-off on anything under 50%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked. “What, you scared?” He turned back to his screen and began launching his script agents; some boilerplate, others requiring brief field entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya weighed her options, then mockingly crossed herself and addressed José, who was still waiting for confirmation. “Override. I guess we got it. We’ll rope you in if we need it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned back to David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d started ID’ing mouthpieces for a credibility challenge. Not a whole lot of influencers active at this hour, but we’ve got a handful of puppets that might apply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s fingers were now flying. “Is the source dirty?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like I said, bona fides look clean. But something always turns up, if we dig long enough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do we have time for that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Probably not. There is the usual terms and conditions take down. Something, something public safety. Quick and clean-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-T&amp;amp;Cs are too blunt. Looks like a cover-up. The Streisand effect is the opposite of what we want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chyron scrolling across the bottom of David’s screen turned red. A neutral voice addressed the room. “Confidence index is below 60%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoa, easy, girl.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the play here, rookie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gathered his thoughts for a moment before speaking. He suddenly brightened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can use this, flip it.” David launched a volley of keystrokes, triggering an equal number of new dialogs. “It’s all about perception.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya made a prune face and leaned over to follow along on his screen. “Come again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So right now it is an infrastructure-fail that is playing.” David dismissed a few of the topmost related posts referencing the video, then pointed to the next in the queue, tapping through as Alethia sorted in real-time. “We’ve got climate aura farmers, government trolls, Florida haters… “ he rapidly swiped several more items in the carousel, “… a few members of Cirque du Soleil, for some reason-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rookie!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How often do they inspect the seawalls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can find out. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We reframe this footage captured of a maintenance test, or a drill. Something deliberate to test disaster response. Proof that the green plan of mangroves and cordgrass work as expected.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll need to dummy and backdate some work tickets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shouldn’t be. Alethia has access those county systems.” Maya started typing. “And the flooding?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Localized, right? We spin it as an unexpected byproduct. Cracking eggs to make an omelet. Invaluable real-world insights that will be used to refine and upgrade the entire system performance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya returned to her terminal and ran a probability forecast; the trend line stabilized, but not high enough. David, watching over her shoulder, leaned in and tweaked demographic and geopolitical targeting sliders by hand. The projections wavered a moment, then orange coded labels bled to yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya leaned back and crossed her arms. David looked at her expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From behind them, Jeter said, “That’s not bad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nearly jumped out of his seat. During his color-coding, he hadn’t heard Jeter approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The seawall leak, I presume?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forming an approach,” Maya answered, “We’re about to execute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Run it back for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked expectantly at David and David cleared his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We supercharge the spread.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter’s eyebrow twitched. “Unconventional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We frame it as proof of diligence - routine testing, proactive governance. Push hashtags like ‘StressTestSuccess’, or ‘MakingSafeHappen’ and run with whatever pops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter grunted affirmatively. “Shift the sentiment from panic to civic pride?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exactly! Like ‘Look at our proactive resilience’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya joined in. “It’s too cute, by a lot. Those tags need a pass or ten through sentiment refactoring. But it might work. The types that might otherwise spread it will back off; they won’t want to seem pro-gov. And it will be like catnip for those looking to clown on the climate types.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We bait a positive spin. It’ll be chum in the water.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter stroked his beard for a moment before speaking. “Alethia: projection?”
The manifested voice localized between the three of them. “Projected confidence recovery is 67 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Do it. Nobody leaves until we’re back over 65%. The markets don’t dip when they open tomorrow.” Jeter took in the rest of the room for a moment. Finding nothing else amiss, he told David good job before ambling back to the crows nest at the rear of the room.
David beamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey! We’re not out of the woods yet, &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt;.” Maya chided, pushing his coffee toward him. “We’ve got a long day of cleanup ahead of us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 3 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - Party On&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, David zipped down the marina ramp on an electric ride-share scooter. He was late for Declan’s party. Work had run over, and he was now having trouble finding the right mooring among the other stationary vessels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was uncomfortably muggy, per usual for Florida’s late summer. The afternoon didn’t have the courtesy of cooling things off, so David was stuck trying to keep sweat out of his squinting eyes as he scanned for landmarks. This close to the ocean, he could taste the salt at the back of his throat, and smell a faint trace of mildew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after more than few embarrassing dead ends, David caught signal and found his way to the sleek two-story white box on pontoons. It glowed at the end of the dock, LED light strings casting colorful reflections in the canal water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As David approached, music, punctuated by laughter and whoops, could be heard. And there was Declan, lounging at the end of the gangway. He was with a couple of hangers-on David recognized from previous parties. They sat on either side of the walkway, drinking beers from a cooler between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan waved and swung a sockless loafer over the barrier from where he had been straddling the rail. His tanned skin gleamed from days spent pretending to sail. He met David with mock disapproval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s Mr. 9-to-5! Bout time! I was starting to think the Bureau had revoked your public privileges.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never!” David tugged at where his shirt stuck to his back, and readjusted his fit.  “Would’ve been here sooner, but work’s been crazy. You know how it is when the Midwest thinks they have a bit of heat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan handed David a beer, “Ah, the joy of keeping the Karens calm. So chivalrous!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gratefully accepted the drink. The condensation had been almost instantaneous, making it slick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” Declan grandly gestured, “What do you think of &lt;em&gt;me casa&lt;/em&gt;? Isn’t she a ‘beaut?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David ran his eyes over the entirety of the illuminated craft, all 65-feet of pulsating brightness; a stark contrast to the fading twilight all around them. “I dunno, man. You couldn’t have bought something &lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bought?” One of the others laughed. “Hell no. Declan doesn’t buy shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lease,” Declan clarified. “Ownership’s a liability, man. Shows up on the balance sheets-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-and lawsuits-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan swatted the air, as if he was waving away something unpleasant. “I suppose that’s true, too. But like I was trying to say, real wealth is leverage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other two in Declan’s orbit chuckled. David nodded, taking a mental note to try and work out what they meant later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, bureau boy, come aboard. I’ll show you around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan and David crossed the gangway. On board, the crowd was Declan’s usual mix of high and low-brow, a clashing of class and culture. He seemed to do that on purpose; the greater degree of friction, the greater likelihood of free entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They slowly circulated, Declan making introductions or issuing orders to the handful of wait staff. As the night began to envelop them, the hot air seemed to grow heavier, more oppressive. Somewhere, on the horizon, there was a distant flicker of lightning; a late attempt at relief. But nobody seemed to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They climbed the ladder to the second floor, past the DJ and the makeshift bar. That’s when David noticed a woman by herself toward the stern, set apart in white against the railing. She didn’t look like Declan’s usuals. There were no designer logos, no gaudy influencer techwear; just a simple light cotton summer dress gently animated in what little breeze came off the water. Poised, but not performative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who is &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan turned and looked, his eyes taking a minute to adjust. He then laughed with recognition. “The granola? That’s Lucía, my second cousin. Mom thought I should invite her since she’s home between tours. ‘We’re family’, and all that.”
“Tours?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘Food Without Borders’ or something. Some kind of disaster recovery non-profit. Feed the poor, film the pity reels, make everyone else feel guilty for still drinking imported rum. All moral compass, pointing nowhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan looked back at David, who was still staring. “Ahhhh, nah-uh. Not your league, dude. Not even the same game.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh.” The challenge was made. David reached over and grabbed a pair of bottles from the bar. “I think I’ll go over and introduce myself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your funeral.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked and sauntered his way as casually as possible to the back of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía leaned on the railing, thick curls pulled into a loose bunch atop her head. She seemed to be intently looking at something while scrolling on her mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked up at his approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nodded and gestured to her device. “Something important?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing that can’t be handled by people on-site,” Lucía said, powering off the screen. “I’m doing a poor job of taking &lt;em&gt;a break&lt;/em&gt;, I suppose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Same. Except my boss calls it ‘field listening’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía seemed to smile, despite herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cold one?” David offered one of the beers. “I’m David, a friend of Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, David. I think I will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David handed her a bottle and took a spot next to her. He studied her as she twisted off the top and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Declan mentioned you do relief work? Is that, like, internationally?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I run field ops, sometimes overseas. But, lately, that has been a lot more stateside than most people realize.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cool. Where were you at last?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía turned to look out across the water, somewhere in the darkness. She took another drink, giving her response a moment to collect. “Tennessee to Ohio and back. The new tornado alley. Lots of towns there that don’t exist anymore, except on maps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh wow,” David said. “But fresh starts for the people there, though, right? Silver linings?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From somewhere across the water, there was a clap of thunder loud enough to be heard  over the DJ’s bass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía gave David a quizzical look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not really. Mostly grief.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just mean,” David picked at the edge of the bottle’s label, “that kind of thing can be a reset. People are freed up to move somewhere else, somewhere safer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line was smothered in damp silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David pivoted. “I think I remember some of what you’re talking about, though. Lots of pull-yourself-up-by-your-bootstraps stories the past couple months came outta that area.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was flash of lightening, illuminating the clouds building over the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That is certainly one take. What is it that you do, David?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He leaned in conspiratorially, “I’m with the Bureau.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bureau?” Lucía’s brow furrowed. “As in Bureau of Truth?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whoop rose near the DJ; someone popped a cork. The bass started again, with renewed vigor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened. “Not for me. I’ll sleep fine tonight. I can’t speak for you, though.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey - come on. It’s not so bad. In fact, you could say we do the same work-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía cut in, “Feeding people and filtering them aren’t the same.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took a sip while staring right &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tried to laugh it off. “We &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; help people. You-“ he said, gestured vaguely, “do what you do. We keep people from stampeding every time it rains.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s one way to describe propaganda.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David laughed. “Look, if we hit the siren every time the radar twitches, then shelves empty, freeways jam… I’ve seen it. Sometimes the calmest thing is… not shouting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She scoffed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t argue that there’s lots of people, here and overseas, looking to capitalize on driving people apart. Disasters-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía tried to interject, but David kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”-&lt;em&gt;Disasters&lt;/em&gt; are primed to be piled on and exploited. &lt;strong&gt;Somebody&lt;/strong&gt; has to have their hand on the brake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hand on the brake? Or across the lens?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another flash. The LED strings hiccuped. David reached for a response and found nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was in Lower Broadway, outside of Nashville, after the F4. The fuel we brought for the hospital generator ran out after 36 hours. We made call after call for help, only to be told that the ‘reported weather anomaly’ didn’t ‘qualify for disbursement’. We were accused of &lt;em&gt;running counter-Bureau narratives&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She exhaled, turning back to eye the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it was clear help wasn’t coming, we moved those who could be moved… but-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was thunder. She seemed to soften, slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David waited for the sound to fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s… a lot. You really carry it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s reality. Most don’t really get much of a choice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía remembered her drink, considered it for a moment, and then set it on a nearby table. A sudden gust blew off the water, pushed to shore by the advancing storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You seem like a bright guy, David. Really. You could do anything. But you choose to tell fairy tales. And people are dying because of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened her dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m tired. I’m going to find my friends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She brushed past him, her bare shoulder icy against his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around David, the music seemed to resume. The storm continued to build over the open water, closer now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s face felt flush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you, man,” Declan yelled over the crowd, his arm around some new acquaintance, “She’s not gonna go for no Bureau boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David forced a smile back, then turned from the railing and back to reassess the party drinking deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyst&lt;/em&gt;, he thought. &lt;em&gt;A Bureau analyst. Let’s see her try to dismiss that&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 2 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 0 - The Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A thrush was feeding on a myrtle-tree and did not move from it because its berries were so delicious. A Fowler observed her staying so long in one spot, and having well bird-limed his reeds, caught her. The Thrush, being at the point of death, exclaimed, ‘O foolish creature that I am! For the sake of a little pleasant food I have deprived myself of my life.’”&lt;/em&gt; - “The Thrush and the Fowler”, Aesop’s Fables, trans. George Fyler Townsend (1887)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - All Hands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Truth is a managed resource, and I am its steward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pledge to start the monthly all-hands droned through the atrium. It reminded David of the omnipresent air conditioning: steady, automatic, and operating at low-energy. The audience was already sneaking glances at whatever might be more of a dopamine draw before they were seated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda was the usual polite clapping for tenure milestones, process updates, and tepid pep-rally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…sentiment volatility down 12% year-over-year…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Truth’s Director of Narrative Alignment, over-slick and as passable as HR clip-art come to life, was speaking. Jeter performatively moved about the stage, hitting his marks like he was giving a TED talk. He was saying something about the de-amplification campaign done for the Midwestern heat dome. But you’d be hard pressed to tell this campaign from the half-dozen others running at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…localized anomalies successfully recontextualized as resilience narratives…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Maya, Chris, and David, seated toward the back, it couldn’t be more rote. Maya, who was already vested, must have endured dozens of these meetings. David tried to match her detached aloofness, her effortless indifference, and was failing horribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He flicked his smart watch. A chicklet blinked to life, replaced the idle screen. “94% vested” shone in bright letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six more points and the waterfront would be his. No more commute from inland, no more landlord, no more roommates. He would have his very own house in the Florida Archipelago. The daydream was so vivid he nearly missed the next part of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…and as we say goodbye to our team headed to the new, New Orleans office, we have some new roles available for the right kind of energetic, enthusiastic game changers…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nudged Chris. “Wait, what’s happening?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris shrugged. “Sounds like some analyst positions are opening up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really? How quickly do they vest?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya chewed her gum for a beat and regarded them with mock disdain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like it matters. They’d never let you sock puppet types anywhere near Alethia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s not,” David said while leaning in and dramatically pausing, “what your mom said last night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris covered his mouth, squelching his sudden laugh into a coughing fit as best as he could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group drew Jeter’s glare. He paused for a second to make it clear he was looking their way, and then resumed his slide with slightly more volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before we break, I wanted to remind everyone that we’re entering our seasonal period of elevated rain triage. I know some of the old timers might have heard these referred to as ‘hurricanes’ or used the 1-5 scale of the Saffir-Simpson categories. Just remember, these are now considered terms of terror. Avoid using in your comms. If you have any questions, please consult the new intranet resource that we’ll link to in today’s recap email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remember, ‘Panic is not a public good -‘”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David, in unison with the rest of the assembled employees, replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Calm is contagious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you, and let’s keep calm out there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 1 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 05</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 5 - Burn In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill unzipped his hoodie, which had served him well before dawn, and now would serve as a cushion. He spent PTO to take the morning off. When he got up, before the sun, there had been a chill in the air. But the temperature had been steadily rising since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap in the fence had been right where the bike girl had mentioned it. The walk down the bluff in the dark had been a bit treacherous; Bill didn’t want to use his phone to light his path for fear that it might give him away. There had been a few close calls, but he managed to make it without twisting an ankle (or worse).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill was surprised to find the drainage ditch, meant for storm water runoff, was wet. This, despite the fact that it had been at least a month since the area had any rain that amounted to anything. And, as Coeburn had mentioned, the area was still in a multi-year drought. In the growing light, he could see the slick discoloration, like this had been a regular occurrence for some time. It turned the concrete scar running parallel to the fence into a treacherous crossing - literally and figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had found a patch of scrub. It wasn’t the greatest cover, but it was better than any other alternative that he could see. And he waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first surprise happened well before 10am. There was a regular parade of light trucks starting their shift from 7 or 8, which was expected. What was a surprise was the large water tankers. Using his binoculars, Bill saw them being staged in a temporary area partially obscured by stacked shipping containers. Workers dragged hoses to and fro, coupling them to a row of valves along the data center’s flank. And it was &lt;em&gt;potable water&lt;/em&gt;, but from where were they siphoning drinking water from? When one truck finished, another would take its place - was this how they were attempting to bypass monitoring? It certainly didn’t meet any definition of “closed loop” Bill understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took pictures, noting the motor carriers and any USDOT numbers he could make out. That would be worth a follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second surprise was how the air seemed to intensify well in advance of the event. The data center always thrummed, 24-7, with a certain amount of unnatural, low-end wobble, a noise pollution that was felt, if not heard, for miles. But, in the last hour, there had been a noticeable increase in pitched whine, a grating screech that gave an unsettling, shrill accompaniment that only grew with the temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rumble intensified. Bill, through the binoculars, could see steam venting across the roof. The ground seemed to vibrate like a plucked wire. It was like the entire valley was trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continued well after ten, the relentless cacophony setting his teeth on edge. But, as the humming, whirring, and crackling began to recede, there was a new sound. Bill heard it before he could see it - an rolling static, jets of white noise somewhere further up the drainage ditch. The water got louder and louder until he saw it splash around the bend, flying down the channel toward whatever watershed lied beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he thought it was water. The speed made it hard to tell for sure, but it looked &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. There was a pearlescent sheen on the top, as if there was oil in the mix. The chaotic release and sloshing was also causing a foamy scum on the edges. Leaning forward, on his hands and knees Bill could smell something faintly metallic or chemical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no way this was storm water - or that it should be dumped without treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was it! This was his proof!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d analyzed numbers, filed reports, and attended hearings but he had never had a case so brazenly lie to his face before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grabbed his water bottle and hurriedly dumped the last of the contents on the thirsty ground beside his sweatshirt. Then, leaning out over the ditch, he reached down, taking care not to lose the bottle in the sudden rapids. A few seconds later, it was topped off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He carefully screwed the cap back on, and recorded some additional video with his phone. The water was beginning to slow but he had more than enough, in multiple ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then he heard the crunch of tires on gravel, above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crabbed walked the few feet to his scrub-shielded camp. He made out a light truck parked beside his own. A second later, both doors opened. The driver, walked around the front. He looked like security, with gray monochrome from head to toe broken up only with a high-vis vest. He looked out, across the valley, at some point at the far end of the data center, while reaching for the handset clipped at his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill couldn’t hear what was said. He still didn’t see the passenger. The driver circled the front of his vehicle and then stood looking at Bill’s license plate, for a moment, head arched to speak into his radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’d know whose truck it was soon enough. And what if they did? Bill could feel his initial fear and embarrassment turning to anger. He had every right to be there! What were they even doing patrolling there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill slung his bag over his shoulder and started up the faint switchback. By the time he reached the top, a second security vehicle had arrived, pinning his Tacoma. The two original uniformed employees stood near the open window of this new vehicle, discussing something as Bill crested the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey there!” Bill said, a bit winded but determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three private security employees looked up, surprised. One - the driver of the first vehicle, Bill thought - was first to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, is this your vehicle?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure is. Is there a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one to speak put his hands on his hips. “That’s private property. You can’t be down there. I’m gonna have to-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill interrupted the guard with his upheld hand. He put his bag on the hood of his truck, rifling for a second, and then produced his county government lanyard. He approached the trio, offering his badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m with the Washoe Planning Commission. As such, the entire community watershed, including the floodplain easement just over there,” Bill nodded below and to the west, “is my jurisdiction”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guards exchanged glances with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill recognized the hesitation - he’d seen it in a hundred zoning hearings - and pressed his advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You folks had quite the morning here, huh? Documented case of metering avoidance? Unauthorized discharge?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other standing guard, the one yet to speak, answered. “We’re an independent contractor. We just provide security. They don’t tell us what they’re doing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh, huh.” Bill put the lanyard around his neck. “Given what I just saw, you are looking at a half dozen regional and state environmental violations, not to mention your site covenants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two guards standing shifted, uncomfortably. The third, still in the second security vehicle, visibly stiffened in his seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you say you had nothing to do with this? Otherwise, I should probably get your names and any IDs for my report. Or - you’d probably make great collaborating witnesses if the state decides to launch an investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver in the truck called the lead guard over and said something inaudible. Bill couldn’t make it out, but the pickup started and then slowly backed up and left the parking lot, leaving the original two guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lead motioned for his junior to return to their own vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’d best move on, sir,” he said, the authority he spoke with before now gone. “It’s for your own safety. We don’t want to find you back here again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each guard carefully avoided eye contact as Bill watched them back out and drive further up the hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It crested the next rise and disappeared before Bill unlocked and got in his truck. He shut the door and exhaled - a massive, shuddering sigh. Outside, the valley continued to hum; inside, however, he could hear himself over it. His hands, draped on the wheel at ten and two were shaking, but he started to laugh. He whooped, punching the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After he got his breathing under control, he reached into his bag and retrieved the aluminum water bottle. Inside, he could feel the contents gently slosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill smiled. This was everything - not the proof itself, but the knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And that’s a wrap! Thanks for reading The Biggest Little Bill. If you’d like a downloadable version with collects all five parts into a single PDF, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the ‘Stories’ page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 04</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 4 - Infiltration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill drove his Tacoma down the road, carefully navigating the handful of switchbacks. “Because I live here, dude” echoed in his head. She lived here, Dom lived here, he lived here. Who didn’t live here? Osirtek employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A handful of t-junctions later, Bill was near the interstate on ramp and the industrial park’s only hotel. Finished in the last year, he suspected it was where Osirtek’s rotating cast of high-priced consultants and limited time project personnel likely stayed; it would be closer to work. And - for all the young, single men with too much money and too little sense- it was probably safer for the company to put their employees up here than in downtown Reno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he approached, Bill could see his intuition was right; at least a third of the vehicles in the parking lot had those cheap, temporary magnetic signs with the &lt;em&gt;OSIRTEK SYSTEMS&lt;/em&gt; logo on the door. Other than that, there weren’t any signs of life, the heat making any lingering outside uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill parked and studied the hotel in his rear view mirror, considering his options. The drone had been a bust. Dom would be laughing a week about that one. But maybe if he could talk to someone? Or maybe somebody that worked at the hotel might know something? He didn’t know what he was doing; only that he had to try and see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel was a casino in Monaco, inside was the mission, and he needed to be Bond, suave and capable. The only problem was that, in reality, he was a middle-aged man, sweating through his JC Penny button down, incapable of flying his kid’s drone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did a quick check in the mirror, attempted his most convincing poker face, and crossed the asphalt that radiated like a skillet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been to a chain business hotel, then you’ve been to this one. A drive underneath an awning before a set of double, motion-detected sliding doors. As Bill entered, he was blasted with the lobby air conditioning, the artificially sealed interior, fleetingly, doing battle with the high summer outside. Like the Osirtek waiting room, the furniture here was all clean lines and unsurprising color pairings; not boring, per se, but safe in the kind of way only design-by-committee can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill was about to move to the reception desk when raucous whoops and hollers broke out  at the far end of the room. The hotel bar was packed for an early evening. Behind the bar, several televisions were full on sporting. The room was full of twenty-and-thirty-somethings, most wearing Osirtek polos, chattering away excitedly. Their imported beers raised or were pointing at the center screen, while one of them - apparently the loser of whatever bet - glumly pulled out his wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their conversations rose and fell inverse rhythm with the action on the screen, loudly talking to be heard over the commentators in one second and then hushed in reverence as the action played out in the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill gave the desk attendant an acknowledging wave, and headed to the bar. There was a seat at the end, where the viewing angle was the worst. He sat down and ordered an ice tea from the employee behind the counter. “This could be a thing,” he thought, taking out his phone and pretended to scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Osirtek employees carried on like pledges at a frat house. There seemed to be lots of prop bets happening on the baseball game: whether the batting team would score a run this inning, number of strike outs in that time, etc. It made Bill nauseous how much money seemed to trade hands, only to be traded right back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It finished after what seemed to be an eternity, and the conversation seemed to turn to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, we’re pulling 280 megawatts like it’s nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Locals are freaking out about their water again, like their lawns matter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bah, if it looks like the aquifer is drying up, we’ll just use the new LLM engineering is training to figure it out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last one made Bill pause. He had been typing the most egregious statements into a text to himself so he could recall them later, but that one was beyond just tech bro bravado - it didn’t make any sense. If they sucked the valley dry their plan was… to have the computers make water? 
He heard plenty of nonsense in county meetings, but this was something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill’s confusion must have have been apparent. An engineer, the glum bet-loser, had stopped nursing his imported IPA at some point and was watching him, curiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Haven’t seen you before,” he said, turning slightly in his seat. “You with operations?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill stiffened and set his phone face-down on the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several other people within earshot of the question were also now staring, expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, um.” The meeting at Osirtek; he had emailed with a specific division; what was its name? “Yeah, I’m with facilities compliance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a moment while they sized him up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know - Coeburn?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glum engineer pulled a disapproving face. “You work with Coeburn?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the guys - one with a shaved head and beard, who couldn’t have been out of college more than a few years, broke into a huge grin. He laughed as he blurted out, “&lt;em&gt;Then you’re drinking the wrong thing, man!&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room seemed to think it was the funniest thing ever, and exploded in laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill lifted what remained of his iced tea and toasted the joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assembled group returned to their respective conversations. Bill paid for his drink and left via the side door thirty minutes later; he didn’t know if anybody was paying attention, but, if so, he hoped the side door would look like he was returning to his room. It seemed to work - he climbed into his truck without encountering anyone else. Before starting, he doubled-checked his notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some good stuff here. Other stuff he didn’t understand. But there was one line he repeated under his breath:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Redline burn-in - thurs. 10am.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever that was, he was going to be there to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was evening, and the sun was just beginning to set. As he went to pull away, he could see the canyon to the east, glowing unnaturally, the bright lights of the data center illuminating the valley like an artificial dawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 4 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05/&quot;&gt;Click here for the &lt;strong&gt;final&lt;/strong&gt; installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Reconnaissance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill pulled his Tacoma onto the rare level patch off the frontage road that locals used as a parking lot. On weekends, the bluff was filled with BMX kids and dirt bikers getting their thrills riding the dusty, ashy-blonde trails. But on a weekday afternoon, it was just him, the sun-blasted rock, and an unobstructed view of the Osirtek complex gleaming below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hummed the Mission Impossible theme to himself as he reached back into the rear seat. Next to the team softball bag was the black, nylon drone case. A gift to his oldest last Christmas, he had snuck it out of the house that morning for official county reconnaissance duty. Now, mid-afternoon, the heat was already starting to get oppressive, the shimmer snaking off the horizon’s asphalt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the drivers seat, he flipped open the container. Inside, the tiny gray plastic lump was about the size of his fist, rotors balled up protectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How hard can it be?” Bill muttered, examining the drone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got out, surveyed the surrounding hills to make sure he was alone, and then carefully unfolded the drone on the Tacoma’s hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill had made sure to download the app at work, but he wasn’t prepared for the litany of pop-ups that followed. Thankfully, it stopped just short of making him fill out a flight plan, although given all the legalese he clicked-through, who knew what he agreed to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After twenty minutes of fiddling, the drone was finally armed and ready. Bill squinted at the data center below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Target acquired.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill eased up on the thumb stick. Each of the blades along the slender arms began spinning, lifting the drone unsteadily off the hood and into the air, holding position a few feet from the metal. 
With a gentle nudge with his thumbs, Bill practiced rotating the drone left, then right. He then had it strafe along the edge of the overlooking ridge, almost hitting a boulder on the high side when he got aggressive and applied too much speed. Stopping just in time, it bucked with Bill’s overcorrection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill blew out his breath in relief, which he hadn’t realized he had been holding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He set the controller on hood and shook out his hands while the drone continued to hover where he had stopped it in a panic. He rolled his shoulders once, and picked the controller back up. Time to see what the public sector can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the power vested in me by the Washoe County Planning Commission,” he muttered, as he nudged the drone’s path over the edge of the cliff, “I hereby deputize you, Agent D.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the droning plastic disappeared down the hill, he watched its camera feed in the app. The megacampus, with a roof spanning at least a dozen football fields, grew larger. It was an unbreakable expanse of white tiled off into the distance, its uniformity broken at regular intervals by massive HVAC units, each sprouting countless ductwork. Heat vented from several of these, causing their own shimmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheesh, it was hot. Was it the day or was he really that nervous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill snapped a picture, then another. The drone was still outside the perimeter and if he could just zoom in a bit, he might be able to see something more conclusive. As he reached to pinch in the app, however, he bumped the thumb stick. The feed from the camera spun dizzily. Bill snapped his head up, trying to see where the drone had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried to regain control but with his lack of experience, he over-corrected, jerking left, right, and then diving directly straight toward the perimeter fence. A gust of wind finished the job, the distant buzz of the rotors whining slightly higher pitched for a second before cutting out completely. Only the sound of baking shale remained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, no, no!” Bill shouted as he ran to the edge of the parking lot’s rim, over-looking the scene below. “Shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was painful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill snapped back toward his truck. Next to it was a kid astride a well-loved dirt jumper, scratched helmet in her lap, shock of pink attitude swept across her head. He recognized the look from his own kids; a mix of curiosity and disdain that only a middle-schooler could manage, 12 or maybe 13 years old. With all his focus on the drone, he hadn’t heard her roll-up behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” Bill straightened, unsure of what to do with the controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you, um, saw that practice flight, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl looked incredulous, and walked her bike toward the lip so she could get a better look. “Practice for what? Crashing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She peered down the bluff while shading her eyes. Bill was still trying to decide how to answer when she suddenly pointed. “It’s just on the inside of the fence, just on the edge of the drainage ditch, I think. There. You want me to go get it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill hesitated. “You can get down there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. There’s a service gap about a quarter mile down. Everybody rides through there to cut across the west end. Nobody cares. It’s all empty. Expansion or something. The serious cameras and fences are further inside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill squinted at her. “How do you know that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because I live here, dude.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen minutes later, the kid pedaled back up to where Bill had been pacing. She swung the drawstring off her back, producing ‘Agent D’. It was a little dusty, and maybe scratched where it had skidded across the rocks, but otherwise in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wow, I can’t believe it! You have no idea- Thank you!” Bill reached for his wallet. “I think I have a $20. I really appreciate-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nah”. The bike girl reshouldered her bag. “Keep your money.” She aimed her bike back down the hill. “Just.. Uh, maybe don’t mess with Mordor unless you’re serious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill laughed, partly from the unexpected reference and partly because his intent has been so obvious even to middle-schooler. He gestured a thumb toward the data center. “Mordor, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It makes noise all night. And the lights never go off. Makes sense to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the kid rode away, Bill turned to look again at the data center. Even from atop the ridge, he could hear the faint humming; an entire valley vibrating mechanically in time with the heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 3 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - The Ballpark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And then what happened?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And then,” Bill said, knocking the dust off the base before putting it in the metal box outside the dugout, “she starts gaslighting me on the county’s methodology on the way out the door. ‘Outdated’ and ‘Not fit for purpose’ she says.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic laughed and shook his head, ruefully. He leaned against the chain link backstop. 
“Anyway,” Bill continued, “thanks for covering. I didn’t think it would take that long but between the wait and getting over here it took a lot longer than I thought. Probably for the best - meant I had a chance to cool down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No problem, happy to get practice started” Dominic said. The other parents had already picked up their players and headed for home, but the coaches’ kids - their kids - continued throwing pop-ups to each out in center field. It didn’t seem that long ago that Bill done that exact thing, on this exact field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic broke his brief revelry. “Aye yai yai. So what’s next?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Next?” Bill closed the lid on the equipment storage and put the padlock on, “I’m not sure what you mean. I put together the report, I gave it to Osirtek. I’d think it was on them now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic drawled out a “Yeahhhhhh,” slow and questioning. “I’m sure they’ll get right on it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill chuckled, shook his head, and bent down to gather bats and catcher’s gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bill, have you looked at your power bill the last few months?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Power?” Bill looked up, “No, Stace does the utilities. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic crossed his arms. “Ours has gone up every month since the beginning of the year. And not by a little - by a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s been a hot summer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bill, we’ve known each other since middle school. I’ve lived here for at least as long as you. I know summers are hot. This is something different.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic sat down on the bench which doubled as a dugout at the city park. He leaned in, elbows on knees. “I went back and looked, at least the last few years, man. Something’s off. &lt;em&gt;Way&lt;/em&gt; off. And nobody is talking about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill could feel his jaw clenching again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our water’s been fine, same as yours,” Dominic continued, “but my cousin lives over on that side of town, near Osirtek. I don’t know if they share a main or what, but they’ve had to start buying water, at least the stuff they drink. They don’t have the money for that! And they can’t do laundry or dishes in the afternoon; there’s no pressure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you think it’s the data center’s fault? Higher power, no water, cats and dog sleeping together, the whole bit?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic blew a raspberry and rocked back, looking back out to center field. “Listen, man, that place isn’t right. It’s making things worse, not better.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dom, I’m not sure what you expect me to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You figure things out, remember? Like in high school, our senior year - homecoming? What was that guy’s name?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jeremy Devlin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“JEREMY! That’s right.” Dominic whistled to get the girls attention, and waved his daughter in, “Guy was trying to steal the homecoming king election, and you caught him red handed. You noticed something that even slipped by the teachers. You pick up on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And that place is miles long, like the size of a secret villain lair. And you’re telling me there’s nothing to see?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic shouldered his daughter’s softball bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyway, we gotta go - it’s nugget night. Tell Stacey I said hi, and take another look!”
Bill waved goodbye, picked up the softball gear, and turned back to the outfield. Beyond the fence, the automated sprinklers hissed loudly, before settling into their evening water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. If you’d rather download a collected version of all five parts, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the link on the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - The Brushoff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital assistant on the television behind the desk looked up and attempted to make eye contact approximately every three and a half minutes. Bill knew, because after waiting an hour, he had spotted looping pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a weird, memory-filled drive to the new, valley-spanning Osirtek Systems complex - 438 acres of concrete and glass built alongside what used to be a dusty back road.  Now it was all multi-lane asphalt running down the heart of the Tahoe-Reno Industrial Center (or TRIC). However, Bill still remembered it as the county cut-across his father took when they went hiking across the tawny, sun-bleached hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Times had certainly changed. Outside, northern Nevada baked in August heat. Inside, the mile-long(?) data center was as chilly in tenor as in temperature. The clean white walls were spartan, featuring only the “Osirtek Systems” company logo, with its generic swoosh and unoffensive font writ large. The air smelled faintly like ozone and carpet glue. The overhead lights buzzed in such a way that made him begin to feel like a bug under a lamp, and it was beginning to give him a headache. Either that, or he had been clenching his jaw too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the generic, unoffensive gray couch he was sitting on, there was a desk against the opposite wall. The “assistant” seemingly sat behind it. If looked at straight on from the entrance, it might have almost passed as normal. However, with any sort of perspective the illusion evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What looked like a desk from the front was really just a facade, with the human simulacrum on an edgeless TV mounted behind it. The background on the edgeless TV carefully color-matched to the wall. From head-on, the presentation was almost perfect - it really did seem like there was a person diligently manning their station. But moving slightly left or right, the illusion evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And given how long he had been waiting, with the regularity of the ticks, Bill was now almost certain that what he was seeing was not, in fact, ever an actual person. This seemed much more like an hyper-realistic software creation, albeit one passable for human; not some clever video mashup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shot a text off to Dominic. At this rate, Bill was going to be late for practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hour and thirty-seven minute mark, the assistant’s idle state changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Hoppern, thank you for your patience. Ms. Coeburn will see you now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill thought about sighing a “FINALLY” as he stood, but thought better of it; something, something discretion and something valor. It felt good to stand. He had been sitting too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please step through the door and follow the lighted path on the floor. Ms. Coeburn is waiting in her office, down the hall and third door on the right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What were the social norms here? Are you supposed to thank a screen saver? After a moment of hesitation, Bill thanked her anyway, checked that he had all his manila folders for the thousandth time, and crossed the threshold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn rose to greet Bill as he entered her office. She smiled broadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Hoppern, good to see you. I apologize about the wait. It has been an absolutely &lt;em&gt;frenetic&lt;/em&gt; afternoon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please, call me Bill.” He shook her hand, trying to match the level of agreeableness, and then took the chair she gestured towards. “I was beginning to wonder if I had the wrong day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn playfully scoffed, “Yes, well, at Osirtek Systems, we always try to make time for the county planning commission. We may be the nation’s premier hyperscaler, but we’re happy to meet with our partners.” She paused, trying to remember something, and then the smile was back. “How is Peter, in economic development?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mostly good, I think.” That was an understatement. Last time Bill saw Pete was at Pete’s “retirement” party. Pete left his government job as county economic adviser when SilverRange Partners, a private equity company, came calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hear he’s really moving up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m so &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt; to hear that,” Coeburn said, with just a little too much relish. “We’re thrilled to be part of this community. Peter was one of the first to welcome us and we are so thrilled that the commission continues to play such an important role in ensuring both of our continued prosperity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill didn’t spend the last several weeks researching, pulling together charts, and waiting the last hour and a half to dwell on Petie’s &lt;em&gt;lame and obvious conflict of interest&lt;/em&gt;. “Ms. Coeburn, I know you’re busy. I don’t want to waste your time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill tapped the folders on his lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The county has been trying to reach someone here at the data center for the last several months regarding irregularities in your water metering. In fact, I thought I was meeting today with someone from your engineering audit team. Will they be joining us?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“May I take a look?” Ms. Coeburn held out her hand. “Our engineers are so very busy, but I’m happy to help where I can. Let’s see what we have here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She opened the folder and began to skim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On top is the July usage report.” Bill opened his own copy and pointed to a line item toward the bottom. “We’re seeing July volume exceeding the drought contingency cap by at least 20 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn slowly turned the page next page, making a good show of furrowing her brow and looking thoughtful before moving on to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s after some odd aberrations in the month before, and another double-digit overrun in May.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn continued to give a cursory glance at a few additional pages, making the occasional “hmm” sound while making a show of letting her finger linger on a line, then  drifting to a different spot on the page, feigning interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I see the problem,” she said, eventually looking up, “I can understand how that might look alarming if you’re not familiar with our systems. But Osirtek runs on a closed-loop cycle. What we drew in May was primarily a one-time fill to balance the cooling lines. After that, the water recirculates. It’s apples and oranges to compare May with later months.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, that might be true,” Bill began, “but residents don’t care about that nuance when their taps are running brown. We’re seeing unexplained pressure drops across significant stretches of our main lines.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coeburn chuckled softly and leaned back in her chair. “That tough, I won’t deny it. But, if I remember my history, the Reno-Sparks region has had rain shortfalls the last four out of five years. We didn’t bring the drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you know as well as I do, agriculture in this valley uses thirty times what  we ever could.” She folded her hands in her lap. “Our footprint, compared to that, is a rounding error. Meanwhile we employed seven hundred people during construction, and another two hundred jobs on an ongoing basis. That’s real prosperity for Reno families.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill gripped his folder so tightly, his knuckles were white. And the lights in this place really were annoying; his migraine was full on raging. He could barely make out the framed photo on the credenza behind Coeburn’s desk; it was definitely Coeburn in a ribbon cutting ceremony with… is that… the governor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I get the jobs thing, but I want to stay on the water numbers. I’ve spent the last month reviewing the numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And I’d hate to see you spend another month chasing whatever this, &lt;em&gt;reporting quirk&lt;/em&gt;, is.” Coeburn closed her folder and pushed it to the side while keeping her eyes, and smile, fixed. “Rest assured, I’ll pass this to our experts on the sustainability team. Until then, let’s keep our focus on the bigger picture - growth, opportunity, and diversifying opportunities for everyone in Reno.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 1 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>