<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Reinbold, formerly of Vox Pop</title>
    <description>This is the website for Matthew Reinbold, the Lead for the Capital One API  Center of Excellence. Much of what appears here dated prior to 2017 was  previously published at VoxPop.co and VoxPopDesign.com. There's also a bit  of legacy detritus from older experiments like mutednoise.com,  miltiantgeek.com, codeaway.org, etc. Yes, I am the adult male that still plays with Lego. You should too.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 16:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 16:24:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recapping RESTfest  &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;RESTfest happens every year in Greenville, SC. Despite its small size, it always is a source notable REST events. In this edition of REST API notes, I cover a handful of announcements, including Erik Wilde's &lt;em&gt;linksets&lt;/em&gt; proposal. This, and more, in the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-18&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/18/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/18/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,Erik</category>
        
        <category>Wilde,RESTfest,linksets,hypermedia,Stephen</category>
        
        <category>Mizell,Mark</category>
        
        <category>Foster,microservices,GraphQL,Dennis</category>
        
        <category>Walsh</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fielding's Reflection on REST  &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Roy T. Fielding was the author of the original paper outlining the REST architectural style. He recently revisited his work in a paper, and subsequent presentation that is covered in this week's REST API Notes. I also cover Equifax, and allegations that the breach was because of a REST exploit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-11-roy-s-reflections&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-11-roy-s-reflections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,Roy</category>
        
        <category>Fielding,Equifax,Java,Struts</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revisiting GraphQL (Again)  &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in September of 2016, I [spent a portion of the REST API Newsletter carefully considering GraphQL](http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2016-09-15-graphql). I'm back at it a year later. Has anything changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-05-graphql-again&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-09-05-graphql-again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/05/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/05/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,GraphQL,Arnaud</category>
        
        <category>Lauret,Sumit</category>
        
        <category>Sarkar,Mark</category>
        
        <category>Boyd,Abraham</category>
        
        <category>Maslow,Scott</category>
        
        <category>Bellware</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>API Versioning, Integrations, and Microservice Podcasts  &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;REST API Notes for 8/28 is out! In it I have stories on Stripe and their versioning, Zapier on integration success factors, and two recent #Microservice podcasts. In addition, I take a moment to acknowledge the shuttering of the Stormpath API. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-08-28&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-08-28&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/28/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/28/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,microservices,Stripe,Zapier,Wade</category>
        
        <category>Foster,Sam</category>
        
        <category>Newman,Stormpath</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Microservices Patterns, Doubt, and You are not Netflix  &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Newman, author of the O'Reilly book, &quot;[Building Microservices](http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920033158.do)&quot; pumps the brakes on microservice hype in the latest edition of REST API Notes. The Open API Spec is now, officially, 3.0.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-08-14&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-08-14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/14/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/14/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,microservices,Sam</category>
        
        <category>Newman,Microsoft,Stephen</category>
        
        <category>O'Grady,AsyncAPI,OpenAPI</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Logan, Westerns, and a Civilized Internet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you seen the movie, &lt;strong&gt;Logan&lt;/strong&gt; (2017)? There’s no shame if you saw the promos and, previously burned by X-films, relegated it the whenever pile. However, it is quite good. Hugh Jackman, a fan-favorite onscreen character despite uneven vehicles, gets a moving, if dark, sendoff. It has the kind of depth that resulted in it featured on Wisecrack’s “The Philosophy of” series:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tHLw7ox458c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the video points out, Logan is less a superhero movie, and much more a &lt;em&gt;western&lt;/em&gt;. As articulated by Will Wright in his book, &lt;em&gt;Six Guns &amp;amp; Society&lt;/em&gt;, the typical western follows a predictable arc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our hero, usually a man from the wild, is embraced by encroaching civilization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The hero is dragged into conflict to protect his new, civilized friends; this struggle is often the clash between new and old worlds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He saves the day, sometimes becoming part of this new group; other times discovering that the very uncouth means to save the new world have no place in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The struggle between new and old worlds is key. The video references “Enclosure”, the 500-hundred-year old English practice of taking communal lands, which were free for anyone’s use, and &lt;strong&gt;enclosing&lt;/strong&gt; them. This creates private farms. The idea is to take something perceived as wild and uncontrollable and &lt;em&gt;order&lt;/em&gt; it with ownership, rules, and law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effects of enclosure on the typical western hero aren’t great. As Jeremy Hsu &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/lovesick-cyborg/2017/03/24/logan-westerns-and-technological-optimism&quot;&gt;says in his review of the film&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“None of the surviving heroes in those classic Westerns truly enjoy a happy ride into the sunset. But they do all seem to recognize themselves as relics of a dying era. Their individual stories reflect the larger narrative of the Wild Wild West giving way to civilization marching in lockstep with technological progress.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider myself fortunate having come of age along with the internet. My internet wasn’t Facebook, Amazon, YouTube or even Google. It was the crazy hallucinogenic potential of the early cyberpunk authors, the fevered nonsense of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mondo_2000&quot;&gt;Mondo2000&lt;/a&gt;, and embarrassing, unpolished attempts at self-expression on GeoCities, web forums, and 1x1 transparent spacer GIFs. It was wild. Unpredictable. Raw. I really didn’t understand the meaning of the word “madcap” until I had a student account and an unmonitored college computer lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly, but surely, &lt;em&gt;enclosure&lt;/em&gt; has come. Like the encroachment of a western’s civilized society, there’s always a benefit: predictability, safety, and comfort. Towns got a sherrif, pastor, and schools. The internet got commerce. It gave us information. And law was passed that wasn’t just good, but necessary; case in point, Title III of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fredlaw.com/news__media/2017/06/14/1548/first_federal_trial_on_website_accessibility_winn-dixie_violates_ada&quot;&gt;Americans with Disabilities Act&lt;/a&gt;. Some taming of the wild was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enclosure can go too far. “&lt;strong&gt;Zero rating&lt;/strong&gt;” is the practice of network access providers not charging customers for data when they use specific internet services. Implementing a zero rating scheme upholds the letter of net neutrality; products or services aren’t blocked. However, in a world of data-capped plans - particularly on mobile - it certainly violates the spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network access providers have been playing a very long game. They’ve diversified, going from being “dump pipes” to international media conglomerates. Comcast bought chunks of NBCUniveral from 2009 to 2013. Verizon bought AOL in 2015 (Huffington Post, Techcrunch, etc.), Yahoo in 2016, and its built its own Go90 exclusive. AT&amp;amp;T is attempting to buy Time Warner and pair with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2016/11/29/13774648/fcc-att-zero-rating-directv-net-neutrality-vs-tmobile&quot;&gt;previous DirecTV purchase&lt;/a&gt;). Even with more modest players, like TMobile, bundle services like Spotify, Apple Music, and Pandora together in an “unlimited” package. You can still &lt;em&gt;roam&lt;/em&gt; to other places… &lt;em&gt;but it will cost you&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than compete on service or speed, content that doesn’t count against a datacap is the new competitive edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the rough-and-tumble of the early internet is gone, and today’s current category leaders (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recode.net/2017/5/31/15720268/netflix-ceo-reed-hastings-net-neutrality-open-internet&quot;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/21/15816974/verizon-tumblr-net-neutrality-internet-politics-david-karp&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;!) are crowned with &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/02/03/trump-fcc-zero-rating-att-verizon/&quot;&gt;the new administration&lt;/a&gt;. And that’s a problem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newamerica.org/oti/blog/zero-rating-plans-are-a-serious-threat-to-the-open-internet/&quot;&gt;A statement, made last year by the previous FCC chairman, points out that zero rating practices&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“present a serious threat to the Open Internet: they distort competition, thwart innovation, threaten free speech, and restrict consumer choice — all harms the rules were meant to prevent. These harms tend to fall disproportionately on low-­income communities and communities of color, who tend to rely on mobile networks as their primary or exclusive means of access to the Internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to take on an incumbent? Now you not only have to provide a better service or site than they do; you also have to overcome the deals they have with network access providers. How many orders of magnitude does your offering need to be for someone to, knowingly, edge toward their data cap?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2017/07/logan.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2017/07/logan.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A screenshot from the Logan movie. Kind of how I'm starting to feel about these net neutrality fights.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People may not change, but the world’s frame of reference does. I recognized that my perception of what the internet is may be very different from someone who has always ever viewed it with an Instagram filter. Perhaps I am a relic from the old world that, having helped civilize it, now no longer has a home here. But maybe I have a fight or two left before I return to the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logan is a great movie. It is about control: the struggle in seeking, maintaining, and relinquishing it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jul/11/what-is-net-neutrality-threat-trump-administration&quot;&gt;July 12 is a day of protest&lt;/a&gt;. Given the political climate, there’s outrage fatigue. I get that. But if we don’t have a free and fair medium for expression, collaboration, organization, and the subsequent reporting thereof, then tackling those other challenges will be impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on the caustic effect of the current direction, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/7/12/15715030/what-is-net-neutrality-fcc-ajit-pai-bill-rules-repealed&quot;&gt;check out this piece from the Verge&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in getting involved, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/&quot;&gt;BattleForTheNet.com&lt;/a&gt;. There’s more at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dearfcc.org/&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF)&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like to leave a comment on the current FCC net neutrality plan, try &lt;a href=&quot;gofccyourself.com&quot;&gt;GoFCCYourself.com&lt;/a&gt; and mention you want to see strong oversite of ISPs (just don’t &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedailybeast.com/fcc-radio-silent-on-stolen-identities-writing-love-letters-for-telecoms&quot;&gt;use stolen customer identities to stuff the comment box&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if this all seems rather dull and boring, here’s what John Oliver had to say about Net Neutrality a few months ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/92vuuZt7wak&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 7/12/17: Turns out, I’m not the first to make the connection between the internet and the physical American frontier. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/tech/elements/net-neutrality-and-the-idea-of-america&quot;&gt;Tim Wu, coiner of the term “net neutrality”, covered similar territory in his 2014 New Yorker piece.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 7/19/17: Wired &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/keep-net-neutrality-fight-going/&quot;&gt;has a great piece on how to keep the fight for net neutrality going&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 8/24/17: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K2Sn_wN2p44&quot;&gt;The praise for Logan keeps coming.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/12/Logan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/12/Logan/</guid>
        
        <category>Logan,</category>
        
        <category>Hugh</category>
        
        <category>Jackman,</category>
        
        <category>Westerns,Enclosure,FCC,EFF,John</category>
        
        <category>Oliver,</category>
        
        <category>Jeremy</category>
        
        <category>Hsu,Facebook,Amazon,YouTube,Google,Netflix,Tumblr,Yahoo,AOL,AT&amp;T,Comcast,NBC,Verizon</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>API Versioning, DevEx, and Microservice Design Canvas &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There's an eclectic, yet powerful mix of stories this time in the REST API notes. First, I cover the API versioning strategy employed by Goolge, get into API developer experience requirements, and then end with Matt McLarty's newly published *microservice design canvas*. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-07-05&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-07-05&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/05/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/05/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,microservices,Dan</category>
        
        <category>Ciruli,Google,Matt</category>
        
        <category>McLarty,IBM,Lorna</category>
        
        <category>Mitchell,Amanda</category>
        
        <category>Folson</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>underconstruction.gif</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2017/07/voxpop-circa-2009.png&quot; class=&quot;lightbox&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2017/07/voxpop-circa-2009.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A screenshot of my Wordpress site in 2009. Yes, I am a fan of Aidan Hughes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-brief-bit-of-context&quot;&gt;A Brief Bit of Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2011, shortly after moving to Denver, Colorado, I relaunched my blog. I had been, happily, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/&quot;&gt;self-hosted Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; for a number of years. However, I felt I was missing out on a learning opportunity by not making a CMS for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I had switched to writing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; for personal note taking. I was also interested in exploring a non-database approach; blog posts would be written as flat files. I had some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/products/coldfusion-family.html&quot;&gt;ColdFusion&lt;/a&gt; framework scaffolding for application management I wanted to further noodle with and responsive web design was begging to be explored. In short, I didn’t just want a place to dump words; I wanted a sandbox to play in. Viola! A Blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot, which was the point. But, as time passed, there were a number of wrinkles that didn’t have easy fixes without effort and/or host changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;URL’s maintained the “*.cfm” ColdFusion extension, something that was increasingly dated. URL rewriting was possible, but that seemed like a workaround for what should be naturally occuring behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure, encrypted communication (“HTTPS”) was problematic on my shared host, even in the age of &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. Given that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/i-wanna-go-fast-https-massive-speed-advantage/&quot;&gt;HTTPS actually is served &lt;em&gt;faster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I was increasingly bothered I was not only insecure, but &lt;em&gt;slower&lt;/em&gt; than I could be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hadn’t gone far enough with the “static site” approach. Writing the articles in markdown was a start. But then processing them through a server continued to have all the security risks while netting none of the performance upside. Very little of what I was doing required run-time processing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deployments felt dated. While development teams I collaborated with in my day job had shiny, new deployment pipelines, I was still setting up FTP (not even SFTP!) and overwriting files. This is minor (I don’t believe every passion project needs the complete continuous-integration-laptop-sticker-sheet). But it &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; dated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-site-rendering&quot;&gt;Static Site Rendering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefits of static site rendering are numerous:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPEED&lt;/strong&gt; - There’s no processing server side; posts have already been reduced to the essential atomic units of the web: HTML, Javascript, and CSS. There’s something poetic to me about that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; - While not so much an issue with my own coded CMS, I lived in constant fear of missing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero-day_(computing)&quot;&gt;zero-day&lt;/a&gt; Wordpress exploit patch and finding myself, along with clients, compromised. Reducing the number of moving parts significantly &lt;em&gt;decreases&lt;/em&gt; the places where something might go wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting&lt;/strong&gt; - Rather than having to find, research, and deploy to increasingly rare ColdFusion hosts (or port to another language), I can post my content to anywhere that supports HTTP/JS/CSS.  hosting. This becomes &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; compelling given that &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, one option, is &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jekyll_(software)&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is great. Feed it html and markdown and out comes a blog. Moving over my custom pieces, already organized as one file per post, was trivial. It was just a matter of changing my custom XML, used to define titles, tags, etc. to Jekyll’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/&quot;&gt;Front Matter YAML&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is written in Ruby but, for my purposes, it really doesn’t matter; I fire up a command line, capture my word-junk, and Jekyll does the rest. &lt;a href=&quot;http://kinlane.com/2016/04/23/the-potential-of-jekyll-as-a-static-data-engine/&quot;&gt;Kin Lane has been estolling the virtues of Jekyll for awhile&lt;/a&gt;. I’m just now catching up. &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll is free to download and run locally on your machine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-new-writing-process&quot;&gt;My New Writing Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finish a piece, I push the resulting changes, rendered by Jekyll into static content, to a Github repo. This not only gives me a record of changes over time; it also populates a Github page. This means my blog is able to leverage the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dev-sec&quot;&gt;hardened infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; that Github uses to run the rest of its operation. &lt;strong&gt;Github Pages is a free service for public repos&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github page sites, understandably, have Github URLs by default. Maintaining my own domain name is important to me. If I should ever move, for whatever reason, I should be able to change the host without requiring everyone to update their links. A custom host, registered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hover.com/&quot;&gt;Hover.com&lt;/a&gt;, is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/using-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;abstraction that allows me to do that&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Github Pages don’t easily enable SSL for custom domain names. For that, I added Cloudflare to the mix. Cloudflare is a CDN, or Content Delivery Network. They own a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of hardware and geographically scatter it about. They then replicate content distributed through them to each of these nodes. When you make a request, the content is returned from the closest server, not whatever server the content originated from. The result is &lt;em&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt;. But, not only that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/set-up-ssl-on-github-pages-with-custom-domains-for-free-a576bdf51bc&quot;&gt;Cloudflare can be configured so content can be delivered through its network via HTTPS, and not just HTTP&lt;/a&gt;. Given my needs, &lt;strong&gt;Cloudflare usage is free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I can render a static site from markdown with Jekyll, deploy new updates via Git, host it on Github Pages, point to it with a custom domain, and secure it with Cloudflare. The last hurdle is take requests mistakenly made to HTTP URLs and reroute them to HTTPs (and thus avoiding the dreaded ‘mixed content’ browser nastigrams. Thankfully, &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170536-How-do-I-redirect-all-visitors-to-HTTPS-SSL-&quot;&gt;Cloudflare saves the day here, too&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve got a smoking fast, secure, and reasonably sound site &lt;em&gt;for the cost of a domain name and some elbow grease to put the bits together&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-left-to-do&quot;&gt;What’s Left to Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have, in fits and starts, been porting over previous content to the new site. I have content from 2015 and newer moved. References to the REST API Notes newsletters go back to the beginning of 2016. More to do there but having a couple years worth of the most recent material is not nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is spartan, at the moment. I’ll probably let this grow organically, as the need arises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also am missing sub-navigation dynamically driven by a tag. For example, in an article about APIs, I could drop in some script that would create in-line navigation that would link to my other pieces about APIs. If I wrote a new piece and used the specific tag, the navigation would be updated automagically. I still need to figure out how to make this work in a static-site generated workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doesnt-medium-already-do-all-this&quot;&gt;Doesn’t Medium Already Do All This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a thousand words, I’d assume the rational question would be “Why not just get a Medium blog”? &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; is great for enabling discovery. I also have load of respect for Ev Williams and his track record in making the web a great place for creators (Blogger, Odeo [which was ahead of its time], Twitter, and now Medium). But, increasingly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/01/04/medium-layoff-announcment-ev-williams/&quot;&gt;Medium seems like a failing experiment and less like a finished product&lt;/a&gt;. In trying to find a business model that works, Ev &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/05/20/technology/evan-williams-medium-twitter-internet.html&quot;&gt;has acknowledged that successful web monetization pushes publishers to ‘all car crashes, all the time&lt;/a&gt;’. That &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; makes me nervous about the longevity of any content contributed there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am privileged. After decades of practice, I can suss out the techno-gobbledygook and cobble together a working site. A vast majority either can’t - or won’t. We need more viable options, not experiments, for the creation, hosting, and discovery of ideas. Until one of those happens, however, I’ll continue to be here, figuring out how to make this work on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 7/19/2017: Troy Hunt has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/cloudflare-ssl-and-unhealthy-security-absolutism/&quot;&gt;a fantastic piece on CloudFlare and unhealthy security absolutism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 7/20/2017: Another Troy Hunt piece, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/life-is-about-to-get-harder-for-websites-without-https&quot;&gt;discussing why the web is quickly going to &lt;strong&gt;secure by default&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I had heard about non-secured sites being punished in search engine rankings, but the browser implications are as compelling reason as any.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/04/SiteUpdate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/04/SiteUpdate/</guid>
        
        <category>Aidan</category>
        
        <category>Hughes,Coldfusion,Github,Git,Jekyll,Cloudflare,Wordpress,Medium,Ev</category>
        
        <category>Williams</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>API FAQ and Microservices Roundup &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest REST API Notes has been published. I highlight a great, introductory guide to RESTful API basics from Diogo Lucas written FAQ format. Then I highlight a number of authors that have shared their various perspectives on microservice development. Interestingly, their work builds off of one another in a way that gives a &lt;em&gt;complete&lt;/em&gt; perspective on building microservice APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-06-19&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-06-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/19/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/06/19/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,Diogo</category>
        
        <category>Lucas,microservices,Matt</category>
        
        <category>Stine,Phil</category>
        
        <category>Calcado,Jeremy</category>
        
        <category>Miller,InfoQ</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>API Info Comes in All Forms &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The newest version of the REST API Notes is now available. In this edition, I cover two pieces on microservices: one a podcast covering the broad landscape of challenges, the other a video that dives deep into the cultural ramifications. Switching gears, there's also a slide deck on the need for a capability approach to API design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-06-01&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2017-06-01&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/RESTAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST</category>
        
        <category>API</category>
        
        <category>Notes,microservices,API</category>
        
        <category>Design,Daniel</category>
        
        <category>Bryant,James</category>
        
        <category>Higginbotham,Cassandra</category>
        
        <category>Shum</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
