<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.comfeed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:18:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:18:48 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Vindication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analyst break-room coffee wasn’t better, but it came with a perk: instead of cardboard cups, they had real mugs, stamped with the Bureau’s slogan, &lt;em&gt;CALM IS CONTAGIOUS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam curled from David’s mug as he climbed the stadium seating of the command room - a college lecture hall as if it were built by defense contractors. The lighting was dim. The space was almost entirely lit by the floor-to-ceiling monitors comprising the front wall. It pulsed with blues and reds, trending terms, sentiment analysis broken out by geography, ideology, education, and any of two dozen more demographics summarized in pixel form; the sum total of the world’s anxiety abbreviated as light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the command center was quiet - the hum of the HVAC indistinguishable from whatever fan noise came from the dozens of computers in the room, the whir occasionally punctuated by flurries of keyboard assaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no assigned seats,technically, but people are creatures of habit. Maya was already at her usual spot, along the left edge and about half way to the top. She was staring intently at her space’s screen, tapping aggressively - summoning forth modals and then, summarily, dismissing them with a flick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David slid into the empty seat next to hers, its screen waking when it detected activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Miss me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya only grunted an acknowledgment, still pursuing something he couldn’t see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tilted his head toward the front wall. “How’s our girl today?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked up in irritation. “She’s being a drama queen. It’s been yellow alerts non-stop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as he logged in, an alert covered David’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The f-.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-see? It’s been like this since I started my shift at 5am. It’s got all the signs of an economic rumor cascade.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gulf side?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh. Home-grown and running hot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hmmm.” David skimmed the included detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was a seawall-crack shock clip. I cross-checked the footage. It is legit; it’s not doctored. The actual impact, though, is pretty slight. There is flooding in the lower 37th zone, but it’s contained; a localized, not systemic, failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But it looks bad, and the clip is breaking containment. It’s that time of year - old axes out again. Alethia keeps readjusting feed weights and dropping chaff. She’s managed to keep it off trending lists so far, but it’s starting to go viral on its own merits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sentiment acceleration?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look who’s been reading their manual! But yeah, could be big. People love any reason to short archipelago real estate for a quick buck. Hashtags are &lt;em&gt;#floridaFail, #sunkenAssets&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;#waterSoWet&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of what Maya was saying was huge. If the Archipelago looked unstable, insurers would re-price everything by the next morning. Markets would collapse. Panic had bankrupted just as many banks as storms did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, is there someone on the seawall video?” Alethia’s algorithm must have tripped over some threshold and started recruiting additional analysts for help. José, down in front, was scanning around the room for confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Over here-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got it,” David cut in, “Maya and I are tag-teaming it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked at David, skeptically. “You sure about that, rookie? Confidence index is at 62.5% and falling. We’ll have a sell-off on anything under 50%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked. “What, you scared?” He turned back to his screen and began launching his script agents; some boilerplate, others requiring brief field entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya weighed her options, then mockingly crossed herself and addressed José, who was still waiting for confirmation. “Override. I guess we got it. We’ll rope you in if we need it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned back to David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d started ID’ing mouthpieces for a credibility challenge. Not a whole lot of influencers active at this hour, but we’ve got a handful of puppets that might apply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s fingers were now flying. “Is the source dirty?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like I said, bona fides look clean. But something always turns up, if we dig long enough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do we have time for that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Probably not. There is the usual terms and conditions take down. Something, something public safety. Quick and clean-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-T&amp;amp;Cs are too blunt. Looks like a cover-up. The Streisand effect is the opposite of what we want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chyron scrolling across the bottom of David’s screen turned red. A neutral voice addressed the room. “Confidence index is below 60%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoa, easy, girl.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the play here, rookie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gathered his thoughts for a moment before speaking. He suddenly brightened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can use this, flip it.” David launched a volley of keystrokes, triggering an equal number of new dialogs. “It’s all about perception.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya made a prune face and leaned over to follow along on his screen. “Come again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So right now it is an infrastructure-fail that is playing.” David dismissed a few of the topmost related posts referencing the video, then pointed to the next in the queue, tapping through as Alethia sorted in real-time. “We’ve got climate aura farmers, government trolls, Florida haters… “ he rapidly swiped several more items in the carousel, “… a few members of Cirque du Soleil, for some reason-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rookie!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How often do they inspect the seawalls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can find out. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We reframe this footage captured of a maintenance test, or a drill. Something deliberate to test disaster response. Proof that the green plan of mangroves and cordgrass work as expected.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll need to dummy and backdate some work tickets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shouldn’t be. Alethia has access those county systems.” Maya started typing. “And the flooding?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Localized, right? We spin it as an unexpected byproduct. Cracking eggs to make an omelet. Invaluable real-world insights that will be used to refine and upgrade the entire system performance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya returned to her terminal and ran a probability forecast; the trend line stabilized, but not high enough. David, watching over her shoulder, leaned in and tweaked demographic and geopolitical targeting sliders by hand. The projections wavered a moment, then orange coded labels bled to yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya leaned back and crossed her arms. David looked at her expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From behind them, Jeter said, “That’s not bad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nearly jumped out of his seat. During his color-coding, he hadn’t heard Jeter approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The seawall leak, I presume?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forming an approach,” Maya answered, “We’re about to execute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Run it back for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked expectantly at David and David cleared his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We supercharge the spread.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter’s eyebrow twitched. “Unconventional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We frame it as proof of diligence - routine testing, proactive governance. Push hashtags like ‘StressTestSuccess’, or ‘MakingSafeHappen’ and run with whatever pops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter grunted affirmatively. “Shift the sentiment from panic to civic pride?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exactly! Like ‘Look at our proactive resilience’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya joined in. “It’s too cute, by a lot. Those tags need a pass or ten through sentiment refactoring. But it might work. The types that might otherwise spread it will back off; they won’t want to seem pro-gov. And it will be like catnip for those looking to clown on the climate types.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We bait a positive spin. It’ll be chum in the water.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter stroked his beard for a moment before speaking. “Alethia: projection?”
The manifested voice localized between the three of them. “Projected confidence recovery is 67 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Do it. Nobody leaves until we’re back over 65%. The markets don’t dip when they open tomorrow.” Jeter took in the rest of the room for a moment. Finding nothing else amiss, he told David good job before ambling back to the crows nest at the rear of the room.
David beamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey! We’re not out of the woods yet, &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt;.” Maya chided, pushing his coffee toward him. “We’ve got a long day of cleanup ahead of us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 3 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - Party On&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, David zipped down the marina ramp on an electric ride-share scooter. He was late for Declan’s party. Work had run over, and he was now having trouble finding the right mooring among the other stationary vessels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was uncomfortably muggy, per usual for Florida’s late summer. The afternoon didn’t have the courtesy of cooling things off, so David was stuck trying to keep sweat out of his squinting eyes as he scanned for landmarks. This close to the ocean, he could taste the salt at the back of his throat, and smell a faint trace of mildew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after more than few embarrassing dead ends, David caught signal and found his way to the sleek two-story white box on pontoons. It glowed at the end of the dock, LED light strings casting colorful reflections in the canal water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As David approached, music, punctuated by laughter and whoops, could be heard. And there was Declan, lounging at the end of the gangway. He was with a couple of hangers-on David recognized from previous parties. They sat on either side of the walkway, drinking beers from a cooler between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan waved and swung a sockless loafer over the barrier from where he had been straddling the rail. His tanned skin gleamed from days spent pretending to sail. He met David with mock disapproval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s Mr. 9-to-5! Bout time! I was starting to think the Bureau had revoked your public privileges.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never!” David tugged at where his shirt stuck to his back, and readjusted his fit.  “Would’ve been here sooner, but work’s been crazy. You know how it is when the Midwest thinks they have a bit of heat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan handed David a beer, “Ah, the joy of keeping the Karens calm. So chivalrous!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gratefully accepted the drink. The condensation had been almost instantaneous, making it slick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” Declan grandly gestured, “What do you think of &lt;em&gt;me casa&lt;/em&gt;? Isn’t she a ‘beaut?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David ran his eyes over the entirety of the illuminated craft, all 65-feet of pulsating brightness; a stark contrast to the fading twilight all around them. “I dunno, man. You couldn’t have bought something &lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bought?” One of the others laughed. “Hell no. Declan doesn’t buy shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lease,” Declan clarified. “Ownership’s a liability, man. Shows up on the balance sheets-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-and lawsuits-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan swatted the air, as if he was waving away something unpleasant. “I suppose that’s true, too. But like I was trying to say, real wealth is leverage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other two in Declan’s orbit chuckled. David nodded, taking a mental note to try and work out what they meant later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, bureau boy, come aboard. I’ll show you around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan and David crossed the gangway. On board, the crowd was Declan’s usual mix of high and low-brow, a clashing of class and culture. He seemed to do that on purpose; the greater degree of friction, the greater likelihood of free entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They slowly circulated, Declan making introductions or issuing orders to the handful of wait staff. As the night began to envelop them, the hot air seemed to grow heavier, more oppressive. Somewhere, on the horizon, there was a distant flicker of lightning; a late attempt at relief. But nobody seemed to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They climbed the ladder to the second floor, past the DJ and the makeshift bar. That’s when David noticed a woman by herself toward the stern, set apart in white against the railing. She didn’t look like Declan’s usuals. There were no designer logos, no gaudy influencer techwear; just a simple light cotton summer dress gently animated in what little breeze came off the water. Poised, but not performative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who is &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan turned and looked, his eyes taking a minute to adjust. He then laughed with recognition. “The granola? That’s Lucía, my second cousin. Mom thought I should invite her since she’s home between tours. ‘We’re family’, and all that.”
“Tours?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘Food Without Borders’ or something. Some kind of disaster recovery non-profit. Feed the poor, film the pity reels, make everyone else feel guilty for still drinking imported rum. All moral compass, pointing nowhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan looked back at David, who was still staring. “Ahhhh, nah-uh. Not your league, dude. Not even the same game.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh.” The challenge was made. David reached over and grabbed a pair of bottles from the bar. “I think I’ll go over and introduce myself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your funeral.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked and sauntered his way as casually as possible to the back of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía leaned on the railing, thick curls pulled into a loose bunch atop her head. She seemed to be intently looking at something while scrolling on her mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked up at his approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nodded and gestured to her device. “Something important?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing that can’t be handled by people on-site,” Lucía said, powering off the screen. “I’m doing a poor job of taking &lt;em&gt;a break&lt;/em&gt;, I suppose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Same. Except my boss calls it ‘field listening’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía seemed to smile, despite herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cold one?” David offered one of the beers. “I’m David, a friend of Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, David. I think I will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David handed her a bottle and took a spot next to her. He studied her as she twisted off the top and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Declan mentioned you do relief work? Is that, like, internationally?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I run field ops, sometimes overseas. But, lately, that has been a lot more stateside than most people realize.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cool. Where were you at last?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía turned to look out across the water, somewhere in the darkness. She took another drink, giving her response a moment to collect. “Tennessee to Ohio and back. The new tornado alley. Lots of towns there that don’t exist anymore, except on maps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh wow,” David said. “But fresh starts for the people there, though, right? Silver linings?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From somewhere across the water, there was a clap of thunder loud enough to be heard  over the DJ’s bass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía gave David a quizzical look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not really. Mostly grief.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just mean,” David picked at the edge of the bottle’s label, “that kind of thing can be a reset. People are freed up to move somewhere else, somewhere safer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line was smothered in damp silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David pivoted. “I think I remember some of what you’re talking about, though. Lots of pull-yourself-up-by-your-bootstraps stories the past couple months came outta that area.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was flash of lightening, illuminating the clouds building over the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That is certainly one take. What is it that you do, David?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He leaned in conspiratorially, “I’m with the Bureau.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bureau?” Lucía’s brow furrowed. “As in Bureau of Truth?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whoop rose near the DJ; someone popped a cork. The bass started again, with renewed vigor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened. “Not for me. I’ll sleep fine tonight. I can’t speak for you, though.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey - come on. It’s not so bad. In fact, you could say we do the same work-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía cut in, “Feeding people and filtering them aren’t the same.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took a sip while staring right &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tried to laugh it off. “We &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; help people. You-“ he said, gestured vaguely, “do what you do. We keep people from stampeding every time it rains.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s one way to describe propaganda.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David laughed. “Look, if we hit the siren every time the radar twitches, then shelves empty, freeways jam… I’ve seen it. Sometimes the calmest thing is… not shouting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She scoffed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t argue that there’s lots of people, here and overseas, looking to capitalize on driving people apart. Disasters-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía tried to interject, but David kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”-&lt;em&gt;Disasters&lt;/em&gt; are primed to be piled on and exploited. &lt;strong&gt;Somebody&lt;/strong&gt; has to have their hand on the brake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hand on the brake? Or across the lens?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another flash. The LED strings hiccuped. David reached for a response and found nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was in Lower Broadway, outside of Nashville, after the F4. The fuel we brought for the hospital generator ran out after 36 hours. We made call after call for help, only to be told that the ‘reported weather anomaly’ didn’t ‘qualify for disbursement’. We were accused of &lt;em&gt;running counter-Bureau narratives&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She exhaled, turning back to eye the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it was clear help wasn’t coming, we moved those who could be moved… but-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was thunder. She seemed to soften, slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David waited for the sound to fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s… a lot. You really carry it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s reality. Most don’t really get much of a choice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía remembered her drink, considered it for a moment, and then set it on a nearby table. A sudden gust blew off the water, pushed to shore by the advancing storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You seem like a bright guy, David. Really. You could do anything. But you choose to tell fairy tales. And people are dying because of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened her dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m tired. I’m going to find my friends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She brushed past him, her bare shoulder icy against his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around David, the music seemed to resume. The storm continued to build over the open water, closer now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s face felt flush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you, man,” Declan yelled over the crowd, his arm around some new acquaintance, “She’s not gonna go for no Bureau boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David forced a smile back, then turned from the railing and back to reassess the party drinking deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyst&lt;/em&gt;, he thought. &lt;em&gt;A Bureau analyst. Let’s see her try to dismiss that&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 2 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. For more on the story’s background, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 0 - The Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A thrush was feeding on a myrtle-tree and did not move from it because its berries were so delicious. A Fowler observed her staying so long in one spot, and having well bird-limed his reeds, caught her. The Thrush, being at the point of death, exclaimed, ‘O foolish creature that I am! For the sake of a little pleasant food I have deprived myself of my life.’”&lt;/em&gt; - “The Thrush and the Fowler”, Aesop’s Fables, trans. George Fyler Townsend (1887)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - All Hands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Truth is a managed resource, and I am its steward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pledge to start the monthly all-hands droned through the atrium. It reminded David of the omnipresent air conditioning: steady, automatic, and operating at low-energy. The audience was already sneaking glances at whatever might be more of a dopamine draw before they were seated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda was the usual polite clapping for tenure milestones, process updates, and tepid pep-rally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…sentiment volatility down 12% year-over-year…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Truth’s Director of Narrative Alignment, over-slick and as passable as HR clip-art come to life, was speaking. Jeter performatively moved about the stage, hitting his marks like he was giving a TED talk. He was saying something about the de-amplification campaign done for the Midwestern heat dome. But you’d be hard pressed to tell this campaign from the half-dozen others running at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…localized anomalies successfully recontextualized as resilience narratives…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Maya, Chris, and David, seated toward the back, it couldn’t be more rote. Maya, who was already vested, must have endured dozens of these meetings. David tried to match her detached aloofness, her effortless indifference, and was failing horribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He flicked his smart watch. A chicklet blinked to life, replaced the idle screen. “94% vested” shone in bright letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six more points and the waterfront would be his. No more commute from inland, no more landlord, no more roommates. He would have his very own house in the Florida Archipelago. The daydream was so vivid he nearly missed the next part of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…and as we say goodbye to our team headed to the new, New Orleans office, we have some new roles available for the right kind of energetic, enthusiastic game changers…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nudged Chris. “Wait, what’s happening?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris shrugged. “Sounds like some analyst positions are opening up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really? How quickly do they vest?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya chewed her gum for a beat and regarded them with mock disdain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like it matters. They’d never let you sock puppet types anywhere near Alethia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s not,” David said while leaning in and dramatically pausing, “what your mom said last night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris covered his mouth, squelching his sudden laugh into a coughing fit as best as he could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group drew Jeter’s glare. He paused for a second to make it clear he was looking their way, and then resumed his slide with slightly more volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before we break, I wanted to remind everyone that we’re entering our seasonal period of elevated rain triage. I know some of the old timers might have heard these referred to as ‘hurricanes’ or used the 1-5 scale of the Saffir-Simpson categories. Just remember, these are now considered terms of terror. Avoid using in your comms. If you have any questions, please consult the new intranet resource that we’ll link to in today’s recap email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remember, ‘Panic is not a public good -‘”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David, in unison with the rest of the assembled employees, replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Calm is contagious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you, and let’s keep calm out there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 1 - Check back tomorrow for the next installment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 05</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 5 - Burn In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill unzipped his hoodie, which had served him well before dawn, and now would serve as a cushion. He spent PTO to take the morning off. When he got up, before the sun, there had been a chill in the air. But the temperature had been steadily rising since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap in the fence had been right where the bike girl had mentioned it. The walk down the bluff in the dark had been a bit treacherous; Bill didn’t want to use his phone to light his path for fear that it might give him away. There had been a few close calls, but he managed to make it without twisting an ankle (or worse).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill was surprised to find the drainage ditch, meant for storm water runoff, was wet. This, despite the fact that it had been at least a month since the area had any rain that amounted to anything. And, as Coeburn had mentioned, the area was still in a multi-year drought. In the growing light, he could see the slick discoloration, like this had been a regular occurrence for some time. It turned the concrete scar running parallel to the fence into a treacherous crossing - literally and figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had found a patch of scrub. It wasn’t the greatest cover, but it was better than any other alternative that he could see. And he waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first surprise happened well before 10am. There was a regular parade of light trucks starting their shift from 7 or 8, which was expected. What was a surprise was the large water tankers. Using his binoculars, Bill saw them being staged in a temporary area partially obscured by stacked shipping containers. Workers dragged hoses to and fro, coupling them to a row of valves along the data center’s flank. And it was &lt;em&gt;potable water&lt;/em&gt;, but from where were they siphoning drinking water from? When one truck finished, another would take its place - was this how they were attempting to bypass monitoring? It certainly didn’t meet any definition of “closed loop” Bill understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took pictures, noting the motor carriers and any USDOT numbers he could make out. That would be worth a follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second surprise was how the air seemed to intensify well in advance of the event. The data center always thrummed, 24-7, with a certain amount of unnatural, low-end wobble, a noise pollution that was felt, if not heard, for miles. But, in the last hour, there had been a noticeable increase in pitched whine, a grating screech that gave an unsettling, shrill accompaniment that only grew with the temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rumble intensified. Bill, through the binoculars, could see steam venting across the roof. The ground seemed to vibrate like a plucked wire. It was like the entire valley was trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continued well after ten, the relentless cacophony setting his teeth on edge. But, as the humming, whirring, and crackling began to recede, there was a new sound. Bill heard it before he could see it - an rolling static, jets of white noise somewhere further up the drainage ditch. The water got louder and louder until he saw it splash around the bend, flying down the channel toward whatever watershed lied beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he thought it was water. The speed made it hard to tell for sure, but it looked &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. There was a pearlescent sheen on the top, as if there was oil in the mix. The chaotic release and sloshing was also causing a foamy scum on the edges. Leaning forward, on his hands and knees Bill could smell something faintly metallic or chemical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no way this was storm water - or that it should be dumped without treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was it! This was his proof!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d analyzed numbers, filed reports, and attended hearings but he had never had a case so brazenly lie to his face before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grabbed his water bottle and hurriedly dumped the last of the contents on the thirsty ground beside his sweatshirt. Then, leaning out over the ditch, he reached down, taking care not to lose the bottle in the sudden rapids. A few seconds later, it was topped off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He carefully screwed the cap back on, and recorded some additional video with his phone. The water was beginning to slow but he had more than enough, in multiple ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then he heard the crunch of tires on gravel, above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crabbed walked the few feet to his scrub-shielded camp. He made out a light truck parked beside his own. A second later, both doors opened. The driver, walked around the front. He looked like security, with gray monochrome from head to toe broken up only with a high-vis vest. He looked out, across the valley, at some point at the far end of the data center, while reaching for the handset clipped at his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill couldn’t hear what was said. He still didn’t see the passenger. The driver circled the front of his vehicle and then stood looking at Bill’s license plate, for a moment, head arched to speak into his radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’d know whose truck it was soon enough. And what if they did? Bill could feel his initial fear and embarrassment turning to anger. He had every right to be there! What were they even doing patrolling there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill slung his bag over his shoulder and started up the faint switchback. By the time he reached the top, a second security vehicle had arrived, pinning his Tacoma. The two original uniformed employees stood near the open window of this new vehicle, discussing something as Bill crested the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey there!” Bill said, a bit winded but determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three private security employees looked up, surprised. One - the driver of the first vehicle, Bill thought - was first to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, is this your vehicle?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure is. Is there a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one to speak put his hands on his hips. “That’s private property. You can’t be down there. I’m gonna have to-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill interrupted the guard with his upheld hand. He put his bag on the hood of his truck, rifling for a second, and then produced his county government lanyard. He approached the trio, offering his badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m with the Washoe Planning Commission. As such, the entire community watershed, including the floodplain easement just over there,” Bill nodded below and to the west, “is my jurisdiction”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guards exchanged glances with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill recognized the hesitation - he’d seen it in a hundred zoning hearings - and pressed his advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You folks had quite the morning here, huh? Documented case of metering avoidance? Unauthorized discharge?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other standing guard, the one yet to speak, answered. “We’re an independent contractor. We just provide security. They don’t tell us what they’re doing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh, huh.” Bill put the lanyard around his neck. “Given what I just saw, you are looking at a half dozen regional and state environmental violations, not to mention your site covenants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two guards standing shifted, uncomfortably. The third, still in the second security vehicle, visibly stiffened in his seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you say you had nothing to do with this? Otherwise, I should probably get your names and any IDs for my report. Or - you’d probably make great collaborating witnesses if the state decides to launch an investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver in the truck called the lead guard over and said something inaudible. Bill couldn’t make it out, but the pickup started and then slowly backed up and left the parking lot, leaving the original two guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lead motioned for his junior to return to their own vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’d best move on, sir,” he said, the authority he spoke with before now gone. “It’s for your own safety. We don’t want to find you back here again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each guard carefully avoided eye contact as Bill watched them back out and drive further up the hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It crested the next rise and disappeared before Bill unlocked and got in his truck. He shut the door and exhaled - a massive, shuddering sigh. Outside, the valley continued to hum; inside, however, he could hear himself over it. His hands, draped on the wheel at ten and two were shaking, but he started to laugh. He whooped, punching the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After he got his breathing under control, he reached into his bag and retrieved the aluminum water bottle. Inside, he could feel the contents gently slosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill smiled. This was everything - not the proof itself, but the knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And that’s a wrap! Thanks for reading The Biggest Little Bill. If you’d like a downloadable version with collects all five parts into a single PDF, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the ‘Stories’ page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 04</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 4 - Infiltration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill drove his Tacoma down the road, carefully navigating the handful of switchbacks. “Because I live here, dude” echoed in his head. She lived here, Dom lived here, he lived here. Who didn’t live here? Osirtek employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A handful of t-junctions later, Bill was near the interstate on ramp and the industrial park’s only hotel. Finished in the last year, he suspected it was where Osirtek’s rotating cast of high-priced consultants and limited time project personnel likely stayed; it would be closer to work. And - for all the young, single men with too much money and too little sense- it was probably safer for the company to put their employees up here than in downtown Reno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he approached, Bill could see his intuition was right; at least a third of the vehicles in the parking lot had those cheap, temporary magnetic signs with the &lt;em&gt;OSIRTEK SYSTEMS&lt;/em&gt; logo on the door. Other than that, there weren’t any signs of life, the heat making any lingering outside uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill parked and studied the hotel in his rear view mirror, considering his options. The drone had been a bust. Dom would be laughing a week about that one. But maybe if he could talk to someone? Or maybe somebody that worked at the hotel might know something? He didn’t know what he was doing; only that he had to try and see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel was a casino in Monaco, inside was the mission, and he needed to be Bond, suave and capable. The only problem was that, in reality, he was a middle-aged man, sweating through his JC Penny button down, incapable of flying his kid’s drone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did a quick check in the mirror, attempted his most convincing poker face, and crossed the asphalt that radiated like a skillet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been to a chain business hotel, then you’ve been to this one. A drive underneath an awning before a set of double, motion-detected sliding doors. As Bill entered, he was blasted with the lobby air conditioning, the artificially sealed interior, fleetingly, doing battle with the high summer outside. Like the Osirtek waiting room, the furniture here was all clean lines and unsurprising color pairings; not boring, per se, but safe in the kind of way only design-by-committee can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill was about to move to the reception desk when raucous whoops and hollers broke out  at the far end of the room. The hotel bar was packed for an early evening. Behind the bar, several televisions were full on sporting. The room was full of twenty-and-thirty-somethings, most wearing Osirtek polos, chattering away excitedly. Their imported beers raised or were pointing at the center screen, while one of them - apparently the loser of whatever bet - glumly pulled out his wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their conversations rose and fell inverse rhythm with the action on the screen, loudly talking to be heard over the commentators in one second and then hushed in reverence as the action played out in the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill gave the desk attendant an acknowledging wave, and headed to the bar. There was a seat at the end, where the viewing angle was the worst. He sat down and ordered an ice tea from the employee behind the counter. “This could be a thing,” he thought, taking out his phone and pretended to scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Osirtek employees carried on like pledges at a frat house. There seemed to be lots of prop bets happening on the baseball game: whether the batting team would score a run this inning, number of strike outs in that time, etc. It made Bill nauseous how much money seemed to trade hands, only to be traded right back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It finished after what seemed to be an eternity, and the conversation seemed to turn to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, we’re pulling 280 megawatts like it’s nothing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Locals are freaking out about their water again, like their lawns matter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bah, if it looks like the aquifer is drying up, we’ll just use the new LLM engineering is training to figure it out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last one made Bill pause. He had been typing the most egregious statements into a text to himself so he could recall them later, but that one was beyond just tech bro bravado - it didn’t make any sense. If they sucked the valley dry their plan was… to have the computers make water? 
He heard plenty of nonsense in county meetings, but this was something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill’s confusion must have have been apparent. An engineer, the glum bet-loser, had stopped nursing his imported IPA at some point and was watching him, curiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Haven’t seen you before,” he said, turning slightly in his seat. “You with operations?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill stiffened and set his phone face-down on the bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several other people within earshot of the question were also now staring, expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, um.” The meeting at Osirtek; he had emailed with a specific division; what was its name? “Yeah, I’m with facilities compliance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a moment while they sized him up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know - Coeburn?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glum engineer pulled a disapproving face. “You work with Coeburn?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the guys - one with a shaved head and beard, who couldn’t have been out of college more than a few years, broke into a huge grin. He laughed as he blurted out, “&lt;em&gt;Then you’re drinking the wrong thing, man!&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room seemed to think it was the funniest thing ever, and exploded in laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill lifted what remained of his iced tea and toasted the joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assembled group returned to their respective conversations. Bill paid for his drink and left via the side door thirty minutes later; he didn’t know if anybody was paying attention, but, if so, he hoped the side door would look like he was returning to his room. It seemed to work - he climbed into his truck without encountering anyone else. Before starting, he doubled-checked his notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some good stuff here. Other stuff he didn’t understand. But there was one line he repeated under his breath:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Redline burn-in - thurs. 10am.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever that was, he was going to be there to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was evening, and the sun was just beginning to set. As he went to pull away, he could see the canyon to the east, glowing unnaturally, the bright lights of the data center illuminating the valley like an artificial dawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 4 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05/&quot;&gt;Click here for the &lt;strong&gt;final&lt;/strong&gt; installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Reconnaissance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill pulled his Tacoma onto the rare level patch off the frontage road that locals used as a parking lot. On weekends, the bluff was filled with BMX kids and dirt bikers getting their thrills riding the dusty, ashy-blonde trails. But on a weekday afternoon, it was just him, the sun-blasted rock, and an unobstructed view of the Osirtek complex gleaming below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hummed the Mission Impossible theme to himself as he reached back into the rear seat. Next to the team softball bag was the black, nylon drone case. A gift to his oldest last Christmas, he had snuck it out of the house that morning for official county reconnaissance duty. Now, mid-afternoon, the heat was already starting to get oppressive, the shimmer snaking off the horizon’s asphalt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the drivers seat, he flipped open the container. Inside, the tiny gray plastic lump was about the size of his fist, rotors balled up protectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How hard can it be?” Bill muttered, examining the drone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got out, surveyed the surrounding hills to make sure he was alone, and then carefully unfolded the drone on the Tacoma’s hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill had made sure to download the app at work, but he wasn’t prepared for the litany of pop-ups that followed. Thankfully, it stopped just short of making him fill out a flight plan, although given all the legalese he clicked-through, who knew what he agreed to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After twenty minutes of fiddling, the drone was finally armed and ready. Bill squinted at the data center below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Target acquired.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill eased up on the thumb stick. Each of the blades along the slender arms began spinning, lifting the drone unsteadily off the hood and into the air, holding position a few feet from the metal. 
With a gentle nudge with his thumbs, Bill practiced rotating the drone left, then right. He then had it strafe along the edge of the overlooking ridge, almost hitting a boulder on the high side when he got aggressive and applied too much speed. Stopping just in time, it bucked with Bill’s overcorrection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill blew out his breath in relief, which he hadn’t realized he had been holding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He set the controller on hood and shook out his hands while the drone continued to hover where he had stopped it in a panic. He rolled his shoulders once, and picked the controller back up. Time to see what the public sector can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the power vested in me by the Washoe County Planning Commission,” he muttered, as he nudged the drone’s path over the edge of the cliff, “I hereby deputize you, Agent D.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the droning plastic disappeared down the hill, he watched its camera feed in the app. The megacampus, with a roof spanning at least a dozen football fields, grew larger. It was an unbreakable expanse of white tiled off into the distance, its uniformity broken at regular intervals by massive HVAC units, each sprouting countless ductwork. Heat vented from several of these, causing their own shimmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheesh, it was hot. Was it the day or was he really that nervous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill snapped a picture, then another. The drone was still outside the perimeter and if he could just zoom in a bit, he might be able to see something more conclusive. As he reached to pinch in the app, however, he bumped the thumb stick. The feed from the camera spun dizzily. Bill snapped his head up, trying to see where the drone had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He tried to regain control but with his lack of experience, he over-corrected, jerking left, right, and then diving directly straight toward the perimeter fence. A gust of wind finished the job, the distant buzz of the rotors whining slightly higher pitched for a second before cutting out completely. Only the sound of baking shale remained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, no, no!” Bill shouted as he ran to the edge of the parking lot’s rim, over-looking the scene below. “Shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was painful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill snapped back toward his truck. Next to it was a kid astride a well-loved dirt jumper, scratched helmet in her lap, shock of pink attitude swept across her head. He recognized the look from his own kids; a mix of curiosity and disdain that only a middle-schooler could manage, 12 or maybe 13 years old. With all his focus on the drone, he hadn’t heard her roll-up behind him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey,” Bill straightened, unsure of what to do with the controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you, um, saw that practice flight, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girl looked incredulous, and walked her bike toward the lip so she could get a better look. “Practice for what? Crashing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She peered down the bluff while shading her eyes. Bill was still trying to decide how to answer when she suddenly pointed. “It’s just on the inside of the fence, just on the edge of the drainage ditch, I think. There. You want me to go get it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill hesitated. “You can get down there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. There’s a service gap about a quarter mile down. Everybody rides through there to cut across the west end. Nobody cares. It’s all empty. Expansion or something. The serious cameras and fences are further inside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill squinted at her. “How do you know that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because I live here, dude.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen minutes later, the kid pedaled back up to where Bill had been pacing. She swung the drawstring off her back, producing ‘Agent D’. It was a little dusty, and maybe scratched where it had skidded across the rocks, but otherwise in one piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wow, I can’t believe it! You have no idea- Thank you!” Bill reached for his wallet. “I think I have a $20. I really appreciate-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nah”. The bike girl reshouldered her bag. “Keep your money.” She aimed her bike back down the hill. “Just.. Uh, maybe don’t mess with Mordor unless you’re serious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill laughed, partly from the unexpected reference and partly because his intent has been so obvious even to middle-schooler. He gestured a thumb toward the data center. “Mordor, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It makes noise all night. And the lights never go off. Makes sense to me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the kid rode away, Bill turned to look again at the data center. Even from atop the ridge, he could hear the faint humming; an entire valley vibrating mechanically in time with the heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 3 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/30/BiggestLittleBill-04/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - The Ballpark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And then what happened?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And then,” Bill said, knocking the dust off the base before putting it in the metal box outside the dugout, “she starts gaslighting me on the county’s methodology on the way out the door. ‘Outdated’ and ‘Not fit for purpose’ she says.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic laughed and shook his head, ruefully. He leaned against the chain link backstop. 
“Anyway,” Bill continued, “thanks for covering. I didn’t think it would take that long but between the wait and getting over here it took a lot longer than I thought. Probably for the best - meant I had a chance to cool down.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No problem, happy to get practice started” Dominic said. The other parents had already picked up their players and headed for home, but the coaches’ kids - their kids - continued throwing pop-ups to each out in center field. It didn’t seem that long ago that Bill done that exact thing, on this exact field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic broke his brief revelry. “Aye yai yai. So what’s next?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Next?” Bill closed the lid on the equipment storage and put the padlock on, “I’m not sure what you mean. I put together the report, I gave it to Osirtek. I’d think it was on them now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic drawled out a “Yeahhhhhh,” slow and questioning. “I’m sure they’ll get right on it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill chuckled, shook his head, and bent down to gather bats and catcher’s gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bill, have you looked at your power bill the last few months?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Power?” Bill looked up, “No, Stace does the utilities. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic crossed his arms. “Ours has gone up every month since the beginning of the year. And not by a little - by a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s been a hot summer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bill, we’ve known each other since middle school. I’ve lived here for at least as long as you. I know summers are hot. This is something different.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic sat down on the bench which doubled as a dugout at the city park. He leaned in, elbows on knees. “I went back and looked, at least the last few years, man. Something’s off. &lt;em&gt;Way&lt;/em&gt; off. And nobody is talking about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill could feel his jaw clenching again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our water’s been fine, same as yours,” Dominic continued, “but my cousin lives over on that side of town, near Osirtek. I don’t know if they share a main or what, but they’ve had to start buying water, at least the stuff they drink. They don’t have the money for that! And they can’t do laundry or dishes in the afternoon; there’s no pressure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you think it’s the data center’s fault? Higher power, no water, cats and dog sleeping together, the whole bit?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic blew a raspberry and rocked back, looking back out to center field. “Listen, man, that place isn’t right. It’s making things worse, not better.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dom, I’m not sure what you expect me to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You figure things out, remember? Like in high school, our senior year - homecoming? What was that guy’s name?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jeremy Devlin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“JEREMY! That’s right.” Dominic whistled to get the girls attention, and waved his daughter in, “Guy was trying to steal the homecoming king election, and you caught him red handed. You noticed something that even slipped by the teachers. You pick up on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And that place is miles long, like the size of a secret villain lair. And you’re telling me there’s nothing to see?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic shouldered his daughter’s softball bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyway, we gotta go - it’s nugget night. Tell Stacey I said hi, and take another look!”
Bill waved goodbye, picked up the softball gear, and turned back to the outfield. Beyond the fence, the automated sprinklers hissed loudly, before settling into their evening water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/29/BiggestLittleBill-03/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it. If you’d rather download a collected version of all five parts, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the link on the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - The Brushoff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital assistant on the television behind the desk looked up and attempted to make eye contact approximately every three and a half minutes. Bill knew, because after waiting an hour, he had spotted looping pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a weird, memory-filled drive to the new, valley-spanning Osirtek Systems complex - 438 acres of concrete and glass built alongside what used to be a dusty back road.  Now it was all multi-lane asphalt running down the heart of the Tahoe-Reno Industrial Center (or TRIC). However, Bill still remembered it as the county cut-across his father took when they went hiking across the tawny, sun-bleached hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Times had certainly changed. Outside, northern Nevada baked in August heat. Inside, the mile-long(?) data center was as chilly in tenor as in temperature. The clean white walls were spartan, featuring only the “Osirtek Systems” company logo, with its generic swoosh and unoffensive font writ large. The air smelled faintly like ozone and carpet glue. The overhead lights buzzed in such a way that made him begin to feel like a bug under a lamp, and it was beginning to give him a headache. Either that, or he had been clenching his jaw too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the generic, unoffensive gray couch he was sitting on, there was a desk against the opposite wall. The “assistant” seemingly sat behind it. If looked at straight on from the entrance, it might have almost passed as normal. However, with any sort of perspective the illusion evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What looked like a desk from the front was really just a facade, with the human simulacrum on an edgeless TV mounted behind it. The background on the edgeless TV carefully color-matched to the wall. From head-on, the presentation was almost perfect - it really did seem like there was a person diligently manning their station. But moving slightly left or right, the illusion evaporated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And given how long he had been waiting, with the regularity of the ticks, Bill was now almost certain that what he was seeing was not, in fact, ever an actual person. This seemed much more like an hyper-realistic software creation, albeit one passable for human; not some clever video mashup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shot a text off to Dominic. At this rate, Bill was going to be late for practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hour and thirty-seven minute mark, the assistant’s idle state changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Hoppern, thank you for your patience. Ms. Coeburn will see you now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill thought about sighing a “FINALLY” as he stood, but thought better of it; something, something discretion and something valor. It felt good to stand. He had been sitting too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please step through the door and follow the lighted path on the floor. Ms. Coeburn is waiting in her office, down the hall and third door on the right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What were the social norms here? Are you supposed to thank a screen saver? After a moment of hesitation, Bill thanked her anyway, checked that he had all his manila folders for the thousandth time, and crossed the threshold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn rose to greet Bill as he entered her office. She smiled broadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mr. Hoppern, good to see you. I apologize about the wait. It has been an absolutely &lt;em&gt;frenetic&lt;/em&gt; afternoon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please, call me Bill.” He shook her hand, trying to match the level of agreeableness, and then took the chair she gestured towards. “I was beginning to wonder if I had the wrong day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn playfully scoffed, “Yes, well, at Osirtek Systems, we always try to make time for the county planning commission. We may be the nation’s premier hyperscaler, but we’re happy to meet with our partners.” She paused, trying to remember something, and then the smile was back. “How is Peter, in economic development?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mostly good, I think.” That was an understatement. Last time Bill saw Pete was at Pete’s “retirement” party. Pete left his government job as county economic adviser when SilverRange Partners, a private equity company, came calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hear he’s really moving up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m so &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt; to hear that,” Coeburn said, with just a little too much relish. “We’re thrilled to be part of this community. Peter was one of the first to welcome us and we are so thrilled that the commission continues to play such an important role in ensuring both of our continued prosperity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill didn’t spend the last several weeks researching, pulling together charts, and waiting the last hour and a half to dwell on Petie’s &lt;em&gt;lame and obvious conflict of interest&lt;/em&gt;. “Ms. Coeburn, I know you’re busy. I don’t want to waste your time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill tapped the folders on his lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The county has been trying to reach someone here at the data center for the last several months regarding irregularities in your water metering. In fact, I thought I was meeting today with someone from your engineering audit team. Will they be joining us?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“May I take a look?” Ms. Coeburn held out her hand. “Our engineers are so very busy, but I’m happy to help where I can. Let’s see what we have here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She opened the folder and began to skim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On top is the July usage report.” Bill opened his own copy and pointed to a line item toward the bottom. “We’re seeing July volume exceeding the drought contingency cap by at least 20 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn slowly turned the page next page, making a good show of furrowing her brow and looking thoughtful before moving on to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s after some odd aberrations in the month before, and another double-digit overrun in May.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms. Coeburn continued to give a cursory glance at a few additional pages, making the occasional “hmm” sound while making a show of letting her finger linger on a line, then  drifting to a different spot on the page, feigning interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think I see the problem,” she said, eventually looking up, “I can understand how that might look alarming if you’re not familiar with our systems. But Osirtek runs on a closed-loop cycle. What we drew in May was primarily a one-time fill to balance the cooling lines. After that, the water recirculates. It’s apples and oranges to compare May with later months.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, that might be true,” Bill began, “but residents don’t care about that nuance when their taps are running brown. We’re seeing unexplained pressure drops across significant stretches of our main lines.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coeburn chuckled softly and leaned back in her chair. “That tough, I won’t deny it. But, if I remember my history, the Reno-Sparks region has had rain shortfalls the last four out of five years. We didn’t bring the drought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you know as well as I do, agriculture in this valley uses thirty times what  we ever could.” She folded her hands in her lap. “Our footprint, compared to that, is a rounding error. Meanwhile we employed seven hundred people during construction, and another two hundred jobs on an ongoing basis. That’s real prosperity for Reno families.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill gripped his folder so tightly, his knuckles were white. And the lights in this place really were annoying; his migraine was full on raging. He could barely make out the framed photo on the credenza behind Coeburn’s desk; it was definitely Coeburn in a ribbon cutting ceremony with… is that… the governor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I get the jobs thing, but I want to stay on the water numbers. I’ve spent the last month reviewing the numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And I’d hate to see you spend another month chasing whatever this, &lt;em&gt;reporting quirk&lt;/em&gt;, is.” Coeburn closed her folder and pushed it to the side while keeping her eyes, and smile, fixed. “Rest assured, I’ll pass this to our experts on the sustainability team. Until then, let’s keep our focus on the bigger picture - growth, opportunity, and diversifying opportunities for everyone in Reno.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 1 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/28/BiggestLittleBill-02/&quot;&gt;Click here for the next installment of The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Perils of Platform Plumbing (and What to Do About It)</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Similar to years prior, I was delighted to be asked to speak at the 2025 CarMax DevOps Days Internal Developer Conference. I didn’t have to cast about for a topic very long; the rash of cost optimization and benefit rationalization conversations happening across industries have platform owners on their heels. So I decided we needed to talk about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the slides had auto-looping GIFs in the background. However, in creating the web version, I dropped the animation; the transitions still made sense without them. The slides and speaking script are below - enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s climate, every software investment is under scrutiny, and Internal Developer Platforms (or IDPs) that can’t demonstrate short-term value are on the chopping block. Yet many IDPs built in the last decade are now invisible; assumed rather than celebrated. This talk offers a survival guide: why invisibility is dangerous, how macroeconomic pressures magnify the risk, and some practical steps to avoid the worst of the downsides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was mentioned, my name is Matthew, and I’ve worn many hats over the years. I’ve been a software developer, an architect, product manager, writer, speaker, conference organizer, entrepreneur, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve reached the point where I’ve decided if I’m going to wear a label, it might as well be one that I’ve made up. For now, I refer to myself as a software change anthropologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coach enterprises on software platform, governance, and change initiatives. Often that means bridging the canyon between technology ambition and actual business value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the pleasure of speaking at DevOps days multiple times in the past on topics as varied as soft skills and AI. Some of those previous presentations include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2024 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/09/30/TurboEncabulator&quot;&gt;Surviving the Turbo Encabulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2023 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2023/06/23/SeparatingAIFactFromFiction&quot;&gt;Separating AI Fact from Fiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2022 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/06/28/SevenSkillsToSaveSoftware&quot;&gt;Seven Skills to Change Complex Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2021 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/10/01/WeMadeAnAPIDescription&quot;&gt;We Made an API Description, Now What?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But during my work with enterprises, I’ve seen a disturbing trend that became the basis for this talk. Today I want to talk about the imminent peril many &lt;strong&gt;internal developer platforms&lt;/strong&gt; find themselves in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide3.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I’ll illustrate the challenge many of us face, a paradox in platform engineering: the better our platforms work, the less visible they become. I’ll explain why that’s dangerous, and I’ll highlight three patterns associated with invisibility:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reactive investment cycles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the loss of champions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finance’s tendency to classify platforms as overhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll share a case study from my own experience that illustrates how even state-of-the-art platforms can drift into neglect if they’re not actively supported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ll present three solutions I’ve found to be effective; strategies you can take back to your organization to help keep your platform relevant, funded, and visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is that you leave here not just with a new insight or two, but with practical approaches you can apply to ensure your internal developer platforms remain recognized as essential to your company’s success and &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; become invisible plumbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide4.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t interact with an &lt;strong&gt;Internal Developer Platform&lt;/strong&gt; (or IDP) daily as part of your job, I guarantee you there are others in your org that do. These critical pieces of software might be an API developer portal, cloud offerings like AWS Proton, Azure Developer Hub, or Google Cloud deploy, or even internal CMSs for knowledge management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software infrastructure has become big business, with some of the biggest software names offering managed solutions. But it wasn’t always this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide5.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The push for automating common tasks and providing shared infrastructure is a relatively new phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Brief History of Internal Developer Platforms (IDPs)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early 2010s: DevOps and the DIY Era&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The term “DevOps” was coined in 2009 and spread rapidly. Teams began stitching together their own toolchains for CI/CD, infrastructure automation, and monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hallmarks of these tentative first steps were often &lt;em&gt;ad hoc scripts, Jenkins jobs, and wiki pages&lt;/em&gt; that worked locally but didn’t scale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first “platform teams” emerged to provide reusable pipelines and guardrails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mid-2010s: Paved Roads and Golden Paths&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large tech firms (Netflix, Spotify, Google) started publishing about “paved roads” or “golden paths” — curated ways to build and deploy software safely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These weren’t yet packaged as platforms, but the &lt;em&gt;concept of self-service developer experience&lt;/em&gt; took shape: one place to go to create a service, get a pipeline, and deploy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late 2010s: Portals and the IDP Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tools like Backstage (from Spotify, 2019) and open-source frameworks gave a name and face to these efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analyst firms (Gartner, Forrester) began writing about IDPs, as a category, something distinct from raw Kubernetes, CI/CD, or cloud infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The framing shifted: IDPs weren’t just tech; they were &lt;em&gt;products&lt;/em&gt; offered internally, with dedicated development teams, roadmaps, docs, and support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020–2022: Hype and Expansion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CNCF talks, venture-backed startups, and blog posts proliferated. IDPs became “so hot right now.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The promise: accelerate developer productivity, enforce standards, reduce cognitive load.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many organizations launched portal initiatives to catch the wave, often anchored on Kubernetes and API governance considering companies discovering they were now liable for an explosion of microservices without a means of managing them responsibly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023–Present: Paradox and Peril&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, unprecedented system shocks and geo-political instability are redefining company IT spending. Today’s challenge isn’t proving that IDPs &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; but proving that they &lt;em&gt;matter&lt;/em&gt;: making their invisible value visible to finance and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words: &lt;strong&gt;IDPs grew from scripts to portals to platforms&lt;/strong&gt;. By 2026, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/experts/top-tech-trends-unpacked-series/platform-engineering-empowers-developers&quot;&gt;Gartner predicts that 80% of organizations will have platform engineering programs&lt;/a&gt; – but the firm also reported that platform engineering has fallen from its height of hype into the “trough of disillusionment”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They solved real pain, got hyped, and now face the paradox of success: invisibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide6.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could attempt to paint a picture of what I see happening across the industry right now, but recently I came across a post by GitLab’s Field CTO,  Bryan Ross. &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsletter.bryanross.me/p/beyond-launch&quot;&gt;It so beautifully captures this unique moment, defining this moment’s paradox, that it is worth spending a few moments on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one’s saying, ‘don’t transform’ or ‘internal developer platforms are bad’. What has changed is that &lt;strong&gt;everyone’s doing spreadsheet math now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide7.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that internal platforms were safe from scrutiny. However, times have changed, and – trust me – your organization’s finance and accounting departments have been put through a wringer to identify where the money is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Goodman, a strategy executive, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/bobgoodman_executivesandmanagement-leadership-activity-7347961315690262528-iSUU/&quot;&gt;has an excellent summary of how turbulent a normally stable area has been&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll leave reading the detailed breakdown as an exercise for the reader. But, broadly, the unexpected shifting of tectonic financial plates can be group in three big, massive moves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End of zero interest rate policy (ZIRP) == &lt;strong&gt;Higher Cost of Capital&lt;/strong&gt; == less “free” money available for infrastructure build outs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post-pandemic rebound miscalculations == &lt;strong&gt;Conservative Growth Spending&lt;/strong&gt; == the “coiled spring” of consumer demand that was assumed to be building during the pandemic never “sprung”, resulting in lowered revenue realities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Section 174 tax law changes == &lt;strong&gt;R&amp;amp;D amortization shocks&lt;/strong&gt;, now partially reversed but still fresh in memory == platforms which may have been amortized over years (and thus reducing expense on any single year) now were expensed all at once, again reducing perceived revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result is leadership demanding &lt;strong&gt;near-term ROI or threatening they will pivot&lt;/strong&gt; – even for platforms that were once pitched as long-term bets. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ciodive.com/spons/why-cios-cant-afford-another-modernization-failure-in-2026/759896/&quot;&gt;CIOs can’t afford another modernization failure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this happening? The answer is &lt;em&gt;money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is always money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide8.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve talked about why this is happening, but &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; does this happen? How can an internal developer platform be released with such fanfare and high hopes only to be on such shaky ground a few years later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide9.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason why platforms get into this situation is because of how they’re funded after launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of your home gutters. On sunny days, you never think about them. Even when they are working as intended, you don’t sing their praises or give them even an ounce of attention. It is only when there is a problem, when they clog and overflow in a sudden downpour, they become an urgent pain to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal platforms work the same way. Their success makes them invisible, which means funding often follows a reactive, ‘as-needed’ model. The danger is that by only investing when something breaks, you let small issues accumulate into big, costly crises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invisible systems drift into a break/fix funding model.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platforms, like gutters, need regular, proactive care to ensure they can continue to perform when stressed. Otherwise, the foundations you rely on every day become fragile, and you pay more later for problems that could have been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide10.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason why internal developer platforms are threatened is that many of their original advocates are no longer there. And without them, the organizational memory of what problem the platform solved has faded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Champions are the people who remind leadership of the platform’s value, fight for budgets, and keep the story alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, those people often move on. And within most companies, platform work doesn’t carry the same prestige as building customer-facing features or new innovations. Ambitious people want visibility, advancement, and resources, so they leave the platform team for shinier opportunities. Without champions, platforms are quickly forgotten, and their reputation erodes into ‘that thing in maintenance mode’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if a platform is seen as now being composed of ‘B’ players, that can pose a challenge during budgeting time, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide11.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third reason why this happens is that finance frames platforms as &lt;strong&gt;business as usual (or BAU) overhead, not innovation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if, as a platform owner, you’re able to secure ongoing headcount, finance often doesn’t view that work as transformational or an investment in growth. Instead, they categorize it as overhead. That’s bad for two major reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It undervalues crucial ongoing work that will &lt;em&gt;enable&lt;/em&gt; the next big thing to happen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Makes any platform an easy target during cuts (“let’s redistribute headcount to growth initiatives”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transformation is exciting; maintenance is not. Innovation is allowed to incubate. Operations are ruthlessly optimized as if it were a mature implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platforms are like mowing the lawn: you’re never truly done. If you stop, things overgrow, break down, and cost more to repair later. But regular lawn care can get overlooked by one-off, new, shiny objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide12.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know these forces exist because I’ve personally seen them play out. A few jobs ago, I had the pleasure of contributing to a fantastic, homegrown API developer exchange. When we launched it in 2015, it was genuinely state-of-the-art. Developers could submit an OpenAPI description, and have it go through an editorial workflow for design review. Once approved, the API description would be automatically published to our internal portal, initiating the corresponding environmental setup. There was nothing else like it in the industry. In fact, there was a moment when we even considered open-sourcing it, and this was several years before Spotify released Backstage. That’s how ahead of the curve we were when it came to a &lt;em&gt;structured, platform approach to our API program&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But platforms don’t stay cutting edge on their own. We soon had challenges. While we had launched with OpenAPI 2.0 (or Swagger) support, adding OpenAPI 3.0 lagged behind other priorities. While vendors raced ahead, our platform stayed stuck. Meanwhile, new needs emerged - data, compliance, other protocols - but investment in the platform remained limited. Without champions, without funding framed as innovation, our home-grown tool became more of a burden than an enabler. Eventually, it was eclipsed by other tools. What started as a crown jewel ended up as an Achilles’ heel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this isn’t just my story. It’s the same pattern I’ve seen over and over again: an internally built tool feels special at the start. It demonstrates brilliance. But without continuous investment, without telling the story of why it matters, it falls behind. And when new hires look at it, they wonder why we didn’t just use an off-the-shelf solution in the first place. By the time leadership makes the switch, you’ve already paid the cost &lt;strong&gt;twice&lt;/strong&gt; - first in building, then in abandoning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why invisible platforms are so dangerous. Left unattended, they rot quietly until failure or replacement forces a reckoning. And by then, the costs are far greater than steady, proactive investment would have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide13.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can feel unfair. We may want to lash out at the systems as being unfair or unjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are far more productive ways of going about ensuring platforms remain relevant within your organizations. These recommendations aren’t just based on theoretical, but lots and lots of reflection on just what exactly I could have done better as a platform steward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide14.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building the platform isn’t enough. You also need to tell the story of what it does. Left alone, people forget how bad things were before. They reset their expectations and stop noticing your impact. Narrative work means showing the before-and-after, in terms business leaders care about. If you don’t make the value visible, it may as well not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I pushed for OpenAPI 3.0 support, my message was all about technical currency: “This is the newest version, and we must remain current.” That might have resonated with engineers, but it didn’t land with business leaders. To them, the story sounded like unnecessary tinkering. If I had framed the narrative differently - for example, how supporting OpenAPI 3.0 would unlock faster partner onboarding, reduce manual review cycles, and align us with external vendors - the value would have been clearer. Without that story, my ask felt abstract, and the investment didn’t follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide15.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every platform produces numbers. But most don’t matter to the people holding the budget. Counting services onboarded or uptime doesn’t tell finance or executives why the platform is valuable. The right metrics connect directly to business impact: time saved, cost avoided, risk reduced. And they should be trended over time to show progress, not just raw figures. Metrics are the evidence for your narrative.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making the case for OpenAPI 3.0, I had no metrics that mattered outside the platform team. I could point to “number of services asking for OpenAPI 3.0” or “percentage of APIs wanting to use new features,” but those were outputs, not outcomes. What I couldn’t show was how our platform’s limitation translated into developer time lost, longer onboarding for consuming teams, or how being perceived as “outdated” was eroding trust. Without metrics that tied directly to business impact, my case felt like a trivial detail instead of a productivity bottleneck or risk reduction opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide16.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the platform doesn’t help the right people achieve their goals, it will get bounced around like a hot potato. Tech leads, finance, product, executives all need to see the platform as advancing their own priorities. Stakeholder mapping means aligning your story and metrics to each audience. When they can point to the platform as the reason they succeeded, that’s when funding and support are sustained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The failure to get OpenAPI 3.0 prioritized was also my failure to properly understand what my executive stakeholders needed to hear. Tech leads cared about compatibility and reuse, but product management only saw another competing priority. Leads didn’t see how this helped deliver features faster, and executives weren’t convinced it tied to strategic goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To each of them, doing the work to add 3.0 support &lt;strong&gt;looked like a platform tax, not a platform win&lt;/strong&gt;. Had I mapped the upgrade to each stakeholder’s priorities - reduced integration risk for product, clearer compliance guarantees for executives, lower support costs for finance - I might have built the coalition needed to secure investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide17.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to owning a platform, it can sometimes seem like the train has already left the station. Like the best we can do is hang on for dear life before it inevitably runs off the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as I’ve hopefully shown, by being more mindful in how we talk about internal developer platforms, we can change the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide18.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you remember anything from this presentation, let it be these three points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell the story: don’t let the problem your platform solved value fade into the past.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show the right metrics: connect your work to outcomes that matter. Vanity metrics may be easy to gather, but they mean nothing to others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And understand what your leaders need to win: ensure every stakeholder can point to the platform as a reason for their success. That’s how platforms stay visible, funded, and trusted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, in my DevOpsDays talk, I talked about the dangers of hyperbole. &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/09/30/TurboEncabulator&quot;&gt;In Surviving the Turbo Encabulator, I laid out a framework for evaluating the outlandish claims that swirl around our industry&lt;/a&gt; (Crypto! The Metaverse! AI!). These claims are the bold promises that, if left unchecked, steer teams into wasted effort and false confidence. The message last year was that exaggerated visibility – &lt;em&gt;the hype&lt;/em&gt; - is dangerous to your long term, professional success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I’ve tried to show the opposite extreme: invisibility. These are the platforms that work so well they fade from memory, becoming plumbing in the walls or gutters on the roof. When that happens, the story disappears, the champions drift away, and finance sees only overhead. Invisibility doesn’t provoke bold, bad bets like hype. Instead, it invites neglect. And neglect is just as perilous, &lt;em&gt;because if no one sees the value you’re providing, it might as well not exist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on one end of the spectrum, we have hype: noisy, over-promised technologies that overinflate their importance. On the other end, we have invisibility: quiet, underappreciated systems that erode because they aren’t connected to narrative, metrics, or stakeholder wins. Both extremes are perilous in different ways. The real work, &lt;em&gt;our work as people who care about what we do and want to be better&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;is to steer a middle path&lt;/strong&gt;. To build &lt;strong&gt;platforms with substance&lt;/strong&gt;, but also to &lt;strong&gt;tell the story&lt;/strong&gt;. To keep them relevant, visible, and sustainable without falling into either exaggeration or a memory hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the challenge I want to leave you with: how do you make your platforms &lt;strong&gt;visible enough to be valued&lt;/strong&gt;, but &lt;strong&gt;grounded enough to be trusted&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/09/Slide20.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like my other presentations, I will have the extended script and slides posted to my personal website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com&quot;&gt;matthewreinbold.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that site, you can also find my writing at my email newsletter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com&quot;&gt;Net API Notes&lt;/a&gt;.
Finally, if you’re on the Fediverse – like on the Mastodon platform – and would like to continue this conversation, you can find me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://opinuendo.com/@matthew&quot;&gt;opinuendo.com/@matthew&lt;/a&gt;; I’d love to hear from you directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, thank you for this opportunity and your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/09/30/platformsAsPlumbing</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/09/30/platformsAsPlumbing</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>management</category>
                
                <category>Presentations</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Grace with a Spine</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The thing I can’t emphasize enough about living through the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/16/20991816/impeachment-trial-trump-bannon-misinformation&quot;&gt;flooding the zone&lt;/a&gt;” era is the &lt;em&gt;exhaustion&lt;/em&gt;. It is a cumulative weight creeping in through social media and offhanded, unguarded moments during work. If you are any kind of empathetic person, it threatens to crush your resolve. Things only seem to be getting worse, the weight heavier, and the callousness more justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t stop caring, not entirely. But becoming guarded becomes a survival tactic for getting out of bed. Communities ripped apart and kids orphaned by unaccountable agencies? &lt;em&gt;That sounds bad, but I’ve got a 9 a.m. I need to prep for it.&lt;/em&gt; Genocide in Palestine? &lt;em&gt;Yes, but I need to get the kids’ sporty clothes washed before games tonight.&lt;/em&gt; Has our democratic experiment run its course? &lt;em&gt;I don’t drink, but I’m reconsidering.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/14/minnesota-lawmakers-targeted-shooting-00406125&quot;&gt;Then comes the news that multiple Minnesota state lawmakers were shot and killed in their homes, apparently targeted for their political affiliation&lt;/a&gt;. After the suspect was caught, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/minnesota/comments/1ldterg/governor_tim_walz_the_way_our_nation_moves/&quot;&gt;Governor Tim Walz urged for cooler heads to prevail&lt;/a&gt;, saying, “The way our nation moves forward is not through hate. It is not through violence. It is through humility, grace, and compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, if you scan the replies beneath the Reddit thread, what do you see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This is a nice sentiment, but you aren’t going to get anywhere by being nice to fascists.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The other side doesn’t play by those rules.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This is loser talk.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that people disagree that these events are a tragedy. They want Walz’s words to be true. But wanting doesn’t mean believing anymore. They don’t see the utility of such statements or how “taking the high road” leads to anywhere better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can blame them? In the face of people who treat cruelty as a strategy, compassion can feel like vulnerability. Grace feels like plugging one’s ears and just accepting all the worst that happens while hoping it doesn’t happen to you. Neighborliness sounds naive when the flag your neighbor started flying promotes further chaos  (&lt;em&gt;When did they get a flagpole? Why won’t they lower it to half-mast for the slain lawmakers? And they make DOGE flags now?&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the choice is either to be kind or to be strong. One or the other. But what if that’s not the choice at all? What if that thinking is a trap?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-false-choice-kind-and-victimized-or-strong-and-violent&quot;&gt;The False Choice: Kind (and victimized) or Strong (and violent)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/15/us/trump-immigrant-deportations-rome-georgia.html&quot;&gt;a New York Times article that circulated several months ago&lt;/a&gt;. It chronicled the life of a Mexican immigrant named Jamie, his family, and his father-in-law, Sky. What stands out isn’t just the family tension; it is how Sky’s love expresses itself in a world he increasingly perceives as unsafe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“He brought along candy for the children and his “go bag” of survival gear, which had traveled with him everywhere for the last several years. It contained all the supplies he thought he might need to be self-sufficient in a power outage or a societal collapse: tourniquets, binoculars, knives, whistles, flashlights, water filters, fire starters, a snakebite kit, a firearm, a slingshot, a Bible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone described as having “big dad energy”, I have a “go bag” too. Mine’s just… different. My bag is the one with the extra snacks. The monthly book club pick. Band-aids. Wet wipes. A backup battery in case someone’s phone is running low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch enough “everyday carry” (EDC) videos, and you’d think I’m irresponsible for not having a paracord and a fishing hook on hand at all times. But let’s be clear: &lt;strong&gt;if I’ve resorted to fishing, things are far beyond what any single “go bag” will fix&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s where things start to twist. For all too many, the instinct to protect - how they express care - gets rerouted to something harder and darker. It becomes a posture of war, not warmth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sky’s grandkids don’t need a sniper. They need a babysitter. A calming presence. But he’s showing up like an action hero prepping for a climactic shootout against a world full of threats, including those leftist, pinko… snakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thewhitepages.net/p/rigged-to-explode&quot;&gt;As Garrett Bucks said commenting on the situation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What breaks my heart about his story is that it’s clear that this is a man who wants to care, who would like to love his family. And his family is giving him direct clues as to how he could show that love and care, but he’s bought so far into a contrary story that he can’t hear them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That contrary story? &lt;em&gt;That strength is decisive. Strength doesn’t flinch. Strength wins.&lt;/em&gt; It is survival of the fittest. And in contrast, kindness? Kindness hesitates. Kindness pauses to consider. Kindness wants to talk it out. Kindness is taken advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a tempting narrative, especially when you’re watching cruelty pay off in real-time. When the guy with the loudest voice, the most shameless lie, or the most cartoonishly unhinged podcast keeps winning attention, money, and elections. When one side gleefully TikToks the announcement of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwyrnrnxy7yo&quot;&gt;Alligator Alcatraz&lt;/a&gt;” and the other side’s tactic is a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/news/pathetic-critics-cringe-leading-dem-191116497.html&quot;&gt;very strong letter&lt;/a&gt;” it’s hard not to feel like we’re getting lapped by nihilism. (&lt;em&gt;Seriously though, Chuck. “A very strong letter”!?&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no wonder people ask: &lt;em&gt;Why should I be considerate and get steamrolled again and again and again when the stakes are so high? Don’t the ends justify the means? What about an eye for an eye?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if choosing between kindness and strength isn’t actually the choice at all? What if the entire framing is the trap, a binary custom-built to exhaust decent people until they either give up or give in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself, what’s the best way to neutralize someone who believes in good faith, pluralism, and shared responsibility? Convince them they’re suckers. Turn grace into a punchline. Turn the community into a liability. Make them feel alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because once you believe that kindness is a trap and strength means domination, you’ve already forfeited the idea of working together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is: &lt;strong&gt;real strength isn’t incompatible with grace. It requires it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boundaries aren’t betrayals. Clarity isn’t cruelty. And there is a long, rich tradition of people who carried both compassion and conviction with the same spine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred Rogers wore cardigans, sure. But he also went to Washington and stared down a skeptical Senate committee to &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/05/02/ThisStupidity&quot;&gt;save public broadcasting&lt;/a&gt;, armed with nothing but his words and the steadiness of a man who believed the emotional lives of children mattered more than political posturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grace isn’t the opposite of strength. Grace &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; strength, practiced daily. It’s the strength to hold the line &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; becoming the thing you’re holding it against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-one-side-brings-cookies-and-the-other-brings-a-club&quot;&gt;When One Side Brings Cookies and the Other Brings a Club&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotional math that so many people are quietly doing these days looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why should I keep reaching across the aisle when the other side brings a flamethrower?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why am I expected to be tolerant of people who openly say they want to strip away rights, dignity, and even humanity from others?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why does grace always feel like it only flows one way?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are valid - and exhausting - questions. And they fuel the more profound fear that haunts so many people: &lt;em&gt;that we’re suckers for still caring&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the truth is that &lt;strong&gt;when only one side agrees to the rules, there are no rules&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what makes this moment so destabilizing. Pluralism only works when everyone agrees that other people are allowed to exist, that facts are still real, and that winning an argument doesn’t mean resorting to threatening someone’s family or livelihood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When that compact breaks down, grace becomes a harder sell. It starts to feel like disarmament while everyone else is shopping at the gun show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why this moment demands something more substantial than “cooler heads” or saccharine calls for “unity”. It requires &lt;em&gt;a moral imperative with clear, precise execution&lt;/em&gt;. This isn’t a license to be cruel, but a stark line drawn between those who want to live together in mutual dignity, committed to resolving disagreements peacefully when they occur… and those who don’t. And those that don’t, aren’t allowed a seat at the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not drawing lines to exclude people who disagree. I’m drawing them to protect the very possibility of peaceful disagreement. Acting with grace doesn’t mean welcoming everyone to the party. Sometimes, it means saying, clearly and calmly: “If your purpose for being here is to give others a bad time, you need to leave.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This piece is long enough, and I don’t need another tangent. However, in Ryan Coogler’s &lt;em&gt;Sinners&lt;/em&gt; (2025), there is a moment where the main characters inside the jukejoint are petitioned by a trio of vampires to be permitted entry. The metatext - predators seeking entry to a created safe space, only to be denied - makes its own argument. That scene &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goodness-isnt-a-transaction&quot;&gt;Goodness Isn’t a Transaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been trained, be it subtly, culturally, or algorithmically, to see goodness as a currency (and I mean that quite literally, if you read and remember &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Whuffie-Factor-Social-Networks-Business/dp/0307409503&quot;&gt;The Whuffie Factor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; from ye olden Web 2.0 days). It is the belief that if you do the right thing, you get the result you want. Karma. Validation. A like, retweet, or an opportunity that presents itself - some sign that a moral universe is still functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not goodness; that’s just quid pro quo dressed up in ethical drag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real goodness isn’t a transaction. It’s a commitment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t do it &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; it’ll pay off. You do it because that’s the only way the world you want has any chance of existing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t compost because you want an award one day for averting climate collapse (at least, I hope not). You compost because &lt;em&gt;you believe in stewardship&lt;/em&gt;. You encourage your kids not to lie, not because it guarantees their employment but because &lt;em&gt;you believe in being trustworthy&lt;/em&gt;. You show compassion not because it wins friends and influences people but because &lt;em&gt;the alternative is rot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this framing, grace becomes an &lt;em&gt;act of imagination&lt;/em&gt;. It is choosing to believe that a better world is possible and that &lt;strong&gt;your behavior can help shape it - inch by inch, day by day&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean being soft. That doesn’t mean tolerating harm. It means refusing to let someone else’s bad faith turn you into someone you’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or to put it another way: &lt;strong&gt;you don’t do the right thing because it works - you do the right thing because it’s &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; And identifying and preventing those who would exploit unchecked expression (as defined in the &lt;a href=&quot;paradox of tolerance&quot;&gt;Paradox of Tolerance&lt;/a&gt;) is one of those right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-were-building-together&quot;&gt;What We’re Building Together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this might sound like semantic handwaving, an exhortation to take on a punishing daily exercise in restraint while the loudest and worst among us run victory laps in bad faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But grace with a spine isn’t just about preventing a personal moral collapse. It’s about creating the conditions for a future that’s worth living in &lt;em&gt;and fighting for&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not showing up kind because you’re naive. You’re showing up kind because you refuse to let cynicism evict you from your community. You’re practicing dignity not because it’s guaranteed to work but because &lt;em&gt;it’s the only thing that stands a chance of outlasting the cruelty&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thewhitepages.net/p/nothing-is-inevitable-and-no-men&quot;&gt;Garrett Bucks (two mentions in the same piece!) wrote recently about this tension&lt;/a&gt;. He stated that we can build something beautiful together &lt;em&gt;if we remember what makes us strongest&lt;/em&gt;. He quoted Serbian organizers who helped bring down Milošević:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We simply loved life more than them… Those guys were the preachers of death. Their hatred, their propaganda, their language smelled like death. And we won because we loved life more. We decided to love life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. That’s the whole blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point isn’t to beat the other side at their own game of cynicism, ‘gotcha’ hot takes, and noisy spectacle. The point is to play a different game altogether: one where we insist on life, on community, on shared joy, on a future that isn’t designed around crushing each other for scraps. Your proverbial &lt;em&gt;life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we choose grace, we’re not choosing to lose. We’re choosing to keep the field of possibility open. We’re choosing to make room for people who want to live together in mutual dignity, even when we disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how we win: by refusing to let our souls be shaped by their fear. By loving life more than they love exploiting it for their own gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-isnt-a-race-its-a-marathon&quot;&gt;This Isn’t A Race, It’s a Marathon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be tired. I know I certainly have my days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might feel like the moral high road is just a scenic route to getting steamrolled. You might feel like you’ve been holding the line alone, waving your tiny flag of decency while the rest of the world ammos up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the truth: &lt;em&gt;You’re allowed to rest&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest isn’t weakness; it’s maintenance. You’re not a machine for moral production. You’re human, and humans need breathers. The work of holding space for grace, of setting boundaries, of refusing to be turned by cynicism is &lt;em&gt;heavy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we carry it in shifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you rest, you’re not quitting the field. You’re handing the banner to someone else for a moment so you can return stronger. You’re trusting that this work isn’t yours alone; &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/06/10/GrowingCommunity&quot;&gt;it is a community’s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grace isn’t a solo act. It’s a collective practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So rest. Breathe. Touch grass. Netflix and chill if that restores your energy. Go thrifting with friends, play some disc golf, or have a good meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we rest and reconnect, we can look to those who have shown us how to hold grief and grace at the same time. After the tragedy, the children of Minnesota state Rep. Melissa Hortman and Mark Hortman shared a statement that felt like a blueprint for this alternative we seek. Among other things, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Fauxmoi/comments/1ldd796/children_of_minnesota_rep_melissa_hortman_and_her/&quot;&gt;they encouraged those who wished to honor the memory of Mark and Melessa to&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Plant a tree. Visit a local park and make use of their amenities, especially a bike trail. Pet a dog. A golden retriever is ideal, but any will do. Tell your loved ones a cheesy dad joke and laugh about it. Bake something - bread for Mark or a cake for Melissa, and share it with someone. Try a new hobby and enjoy learning something. Stand up for what you believe in, especially if that thing is justice and peace.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grace with a spine isn’t the easy way. However, it’s the only way forward that doesn’t turn us into what we’re against.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com2025/06/30/grace</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com2025/06/30/grace</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>