<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:21:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:21:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Oppose the TAKE IT DOWN Act</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There are real problems that could be addressed by new legislation. Along with ubiquitous cell phone cameras and deep fake abilities have come a rash of gross online behavior; what we might have once referred to as &lt;em&gt;revenge porn&lt;/em&gt; is now collectively referred to as non-consensual intimate imagery (NCII).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Senate recently passed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/senate-bill/146&quot;&gt;TAKE IT DOWN Act&lt;/a&gt; to address the problem. The intention is good. However, the proposed implmentation leaves much to be desired - so much so that Trump excitedly referenced wanting to use the bill to silence his past accusers during last week’s address to the joint session of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent letters to my Congressional representation voicing my concerns. The letter to Senator Amy Klobuchar, co-sponsor of the bill, is below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Opposition to the Take It Down Act (S.146)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Senator Klobuchar,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing to express my strong opposition to the Take It Down Act, which recently passed the Senate and you co-sponsored. While the bill’s stated intent- to combat non-consensual intimate imagery (NCII) - is laudable, its approach is deeply flawed. As drafted, the bill creates an overbroad notice-and-takedown system with severe penalties, incentivizing platforms to remove content without meaningful review. This will not only result in abuse but will actively suppress lawful speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has happened before: The Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) was designed to protect intellectual property, but its notice-and-takedown provisions have been repeatedly weaponized. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lumendatabase.org/blog_entries/over-thirty-thousand-dmca-notices-reveal-an-organized-attempt-to-abuse-copyright-law&quot;&gt;Tens of thousands of fraudulent DMCA claims have been used to silence journalists, suppress negative press, and manipulate online discourse&lt;/a&gt;. The Take It Down Act creates a nearly identical system, except instead of copyright claims, it enables virtually any powerful individual or institution to demand the removal of speech they dislike under the guise of NCII complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chilling effect is obvious. Faced with a 48-hour takedown mandate and the threat of legal or financial penalty, platforms will opt to remove content immediately, even when claims are unfounded. This will disproportionately impact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survivors of abuse who use online platforms to expose their abusers&lt;/strong&gt; - This law will provide bad actors with a new tool to erase evidence of their misconduct.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journalists and activists documenting abuses of power&lt;/strong&gt; - From war crimes to workplace harassment, critical reporting could be wiped from public view with a mere takedown request.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms already struggling to moderate content responsibly&lt;/strong&gt; - The law forces them to err further on the side of mass removal, leading to default state of over-censorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more concerning, &lt;strong&gt;President Trump has openly admitted that he intends to use this law for his own benefit&lt;/strong&gt;. In this year’s joint address to Congress, he stated, “And I’m going to use that bill for myself too if you don’t mind, because nobody gets treated worse than I do online, nobody.” We should work to thwart totalitarian tendencies during these unprecedented times, not further encourage them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are better ways to combat NCII. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.missingkids.org/home&quot;&gt;The National Center for Missing &amp;amp; Exploited Children (NCMEC)&lt;/a&gt; has already developed a voluntary, hashed-based system to help platforms identify and remove problematic content without requiring rushed, legally fraught decisions. Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;StopNCII.org&quot;&gt;StopNCII.org&lt;/a&gt; has developed a robust, privacy-protecting approach that allows individuals to preemptively flag sensitive content for removal without government intervention. Groups like &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.iftas.org/&quot;&gt;Federated Trust and Safety (IFTAS)&lt;/a&gt; have compelling solutions but are struggling for support to continue their work. Strengthening these initiatives through funding or platform incentives would be far more effective than mandating a sweeping, abuse-prone legal regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I urge you to revisit your support for the Take It Down Act, work on these gaps should the opportunity arise during reconciliation, and support solutions that address the real problem without undermining fundamental freedoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Reinbold&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/03/10/StopTheTakeItDownAct</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/03/10/StopTheTakeItDownAct</guid>
                
                <category>law</category>
                
                <category>copyright</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>On Blog Writing</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have several tepid attempts at lending some clarifying thought to (&lt;em&gt;gestures manically&lt;/em&gt;) this moment. The problem, however, is that anything I have to say feels so incredibly ineffective at stopping this slow-motion trainwreck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of letting a pile of half-completed work make me feel inept, I decided to switch tracks to something more approachable: contributing to an old-fashioned &lt;strong&gt;blog carnival&lt;/strong&gt;. I initially saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanmarcotte.com/wrote/blog-questions-challenge/&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hicks.design/journal/blog-questions-challenge&quot;&gt;Jon Hicks&lt;/a&gt; do their versions and was then reminded about when &lt;a href=&quot;https://polytechnic.co.uk/blog/2025/02/blog-questions-challenge/&quot;&gt;Garrett Coakley&lt;/a&gt; mentioned his post on Mastodon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are a few answers about how and why I blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-you-start-blogging-in-the-first-place&quot;&gt;Why did you start blogging in the first place?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing has always been an essential part of how I organize my internal space. Even as a kid, rather than leave things as vague notions or incomplete thoughts, I’d attempt to articulate my feelings in cheap, spiral-bound notebooks. I wasn’t saving these scraps because I thought they were genius to be mined or affirmations to follow, but just a natural part of trying to process the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved it when people started blogging online. It felt like you got such a more authentic, genuine version of the person. Don’t get me wrong, optimizing for maximum “virality” also existed then; parasocial relationships are not new, and there were plenty of “influencers” that put on a persona before laying hands on keys existed then, too. But being able to publish something immediately, worldwide, to connect with others &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; is amazing, given other forms of media and their gatekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-platform-are-you-using-to-manage-your-blog-and-why-did-you-choose-it-have-you-blogged-on-other-platforms-before&quot;&gt;What platform are you using to manage your blog and why did you choose it? Have you blogged on other platforms before?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first place I ever posted something was a Geocities site. Then I used phpBB for a while, something that makes much more sense as a forum for a community than a blog for a single person. I used WordPress for a few years, and then hand-crafted my own CMS using Macromedia/Adobe ColdFusion and MySQL. That was fun, as I got to do some interesting experiments with tagging and automatic content embedding, but, over time, it required too much overhead to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I use Jekyll for my blog and Ghost.pro for &lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/&quot;&gt;my API newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. I became a big believer in static site generation some time ago for several reasons, and the static files from Jekyll can easily be served for free from a GitHub Pages site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-write-your-posts-for-example-in-a-local-editing-tool-or-in-a-paneldashboard-thats-part-of-your-blog&quot;&gt;How do you write your posts? For example, in a local editing tool, or in a panel/dashboard that’s part of your blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write anything under a few thousand words in Google Docs; it has the minimal number of features and the maximum amount of universal availability. Once I have a draft I’m pretty set on, I copy the contents into Grammarly and then review the suggestions, selectively choosing which ones to apply back to the original doc. Then I copy and paste the text into the destination vessel - markdown for the blog, or Ghost’s newsletter web interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For pieces longer than a few thousand words, like presentations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener/overview&quot;&gt;I use Scrivener&lt;/a&gt;. Scrivener helps me organize longer work into more maintainable chunks, with support for templates, research notes, slide sketch ideas, rich statistics, and more. It’s a bit much for one-off posts, but for more ambitious projects, I’ve found it to be essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-do-you-feel-most-inspired-to-write&quot;&gt;When do you feel most inspired to write?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired might be the wrong word, but I know I need to write when I feel the most at a loss. Maybe others are able to go about their days with 100% certainty of who they are and what they are doing. I’m not like that, and those moments when I feel the least in control or stressed over something unclear are the moments when I’m like, “Yeah, I need to unpack this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I get a revelation or a fresh perspective. However, most of the time, just acknowledging the feeling and what might be causing it is enough to get me unstuck. I don’t think that’s the most entertaining for others to read, and usually those posts get tucked away, far from the light of the screen. And that’s OK; not everything that gets written has to be read to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-publish-immediately-after-writing-or-do-you-let-it-simmer-a-bit-as-a-draft&quot;&gt;Do you publish immediately after writing, or do you let it simmer a bit as a draft?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rarely write and publish in one sitting. I’m almost always in a dialogue with the me I was yesterday (or the week before, or the month before that). So, in that sense, I let it simmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if I’ve put in the hours on something I know I’ll publish, I’ll push through to completion if I’m close. After all, how else will I see those subtle errors only visible when everyone else can see them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-favorite-post-on-your-blog&quot;&gt;What’s your favorite post on your blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m proud of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/tags/#Aesop2121&quot;&gt;“Aesop2121” utopian science fiction writing challenge I did last year&lt;/a&gt;. Having a place to post &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/tags/#Presentations&quot;&gt;my software presentations&lt;/a&gt;, which is work I put a tremendous amount of effort into, is also great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my most unapologetic, challenging, and &lt;strong&gt;favorite&lt;/strong&gt; blog post was &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2014/03/03/Her&quot;&gt;my 2014 “orthogonal” review of Spike Jonze’s Her&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a cultural and technological pathos in that movie that I connected with and wanted to embellish and accentuate; I was attempting to “vibe” with a work before that was a thing. I knew I hit my mark when one of my good friends reached out after reading it and asked if I was OK. That was a proud moment for me and remains one of my favorite things (if a bit maudlin) I’ve ever published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;any-future-plans-for-your-blog-maybe-a-redesign-a-move-to-another-platform-or-adding-a-new-feature&quot;&gt;Any future plans for your blog? Maybe a redesign, a move to another platform, or adding a new feature?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no plans at the moment for my personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a year of attempting regular updates and specialized exclusives with my newsletter, I’ve resolved to posting when I post. The social landscape for how technical opinion is shared and promoted to broader audiences is drastically different than when I started in 2015. Frankly, I’m not sure if it makes sense any longer to log what amounts to a part-time job on such a niche topic; very few in this area seem interested in reading multi-thousand-word pieces a month. Even fewer are willing to financially support it. Whether the reason for the reception is me or the market, the bottom-line is that there are other, more enjoyable things I can do with my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whos-next&quot;&gt;Who’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will steal the idea from a few others in this series and encourage anyone writing online to &lt;em&gt;just do it&lt;/em&gt;; reflection is almost always a worthy exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you do, &lt;a href=&quot;https://opinuendo.com/@matthew&quot;&gt;ping me on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, so I can read it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/02/04/OnWriting</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/02/04/OnWriting</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>Milestones</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pass the PRESS Act</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As the current congressional session begins to wind down, the PRESS ACT, which was passed unanimously by the House, is still waiting for a vote. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/11/10/its-the-senates-last-chance-to-pass-the-press-act/&quot;&gt;As described by Zack Whittiker writing on TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The PRESS Act, if passed into law, would enshrine nationwide protections for journalists across the United States from being forced to identify or give up their confidential sources (except in emergency cases, like to prevent an act of terrorism). The bill also grants other protections, such as limiting what records the government can secretly take from journalists or their email or phone provider that could identify their sources — again, with a narrow set of exceptions for emergency threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional coverage of the PRESS Act includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freedom.press/issues/pass-the-press-act/&quot;&gt;Freedom of the Press Foundation’s Coverage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spj.org/press-act.asp&quot;&gt;The Society of Professional Journalists Page (with video!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2024/01/press-act-will-protect-journalists-when-they-need-it-most&quot;&gt;Coverage by the Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom of the press is a really important thing, and this should be a no-brainer!&lt;/strong&gt;. However, concerned Americans who want to see the media be able to investigate corruption and misuses of power &lt;em&gt;need to encourage their Senators to act in this 11th hour&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://go.peoplepower.org/letter/congress-press-act#&quot;&gt;The ACLU has a convenient web form for contacting your elected official&lt;/a&gt;. While the form is expedient, I would encourage those who are able to send physical mail, ASAP. I understand that physical mail is more likely to be read, as it is a greater rarity in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-letter-that-i-sent-to-both-of-my-senators-is-below&quot;&gt;The letter that I sent to both of my senators is below.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Senator,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Matthew Reinbold and I am proud to call Woodbury, Minnesota my home. As your constituent, I am writing to urge you to prioritize bringing the PRESS Act to a vote in the Senate before the end of this year. This bipartisan bill, passed unanimously by the House in January, is a rare example of cross-party consensus on an issue central to our democracy: protecting the freedom of the press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PRESS Act establishes essential safeguards for journalists, preventing them from being forced to disclose the identities of their confidential sources and limiting the government’s ability to seize records that could compromise those sources. It includes thoughtful exceptions for emergencies, such as imminent threats of terrorism, ensuring national security needs are balanced with press protections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without such protections, journalists risk facing a chilling effect—deterring critical investigative reporting that holds those in power accountable. At a time when press freedoms are increasingly under threat and government agencies could face mounting pressure to retaliate against watchdog journalism, the PRESS Act is not just timely but urgently necessary. It strengthens First Amendment protections that underpin our democratic system and ensures that whistleblowers and other truth-tellers can come forward without fear of exposure or retribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bill already has broad bipartisan support in the Senate, with sponsors including Senators Ron Wyden, Lindsey Graham, Mike Lee, and Dick Durbin. &lt;strong&gt;All that remains is for the Senate to take decisive action and bring it to a vote&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your constituent, I ask you to demonstrate your commitment to the principles of a free press and the protections our democracy depends on. Please do everything in your power to ensure the PRESS Act reaches the Senate floor and becomes law before the year ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your attention to this urgent matter. I am grateful for your service to Minnesota and your dedication to preserving our democracy in the face of potential adversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Reinbold&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2025-01-07&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did hear from Senator Tina Smith shortly after holiday break. While her email was short and explained that the bill was currently in the judiciary committee, which she wasn’t part of, she expressed her support for it if or when it was brought to the floor for a vote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/11/20/PassThePressAct</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/11/20/PassThePressAct</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>law</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Thank You, Tim</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up on a farm, I learned just how stressful harvest time is at an early age. There is a very narrow window during which it is possible to maximize your returns. Go too early, and you risk spoilage. Wait until too late, and you end up leaving money in the field. And that all depends on whether the weather holds. Mistime any of those things, and you have to wait until next spring (and another six-figure seed bill) for another chance to make things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, I can recall multiple times when my Dad and other farmers in our small town (population of 440) would drop whatever they were doing to help someone in need. Sometimes it would be broken equipment (sunflowers have a nasty habit of setting themselves and the combine that is harvesting them on fire). Other times it would be a medical emergency. Regardless of the context, the community would ensure that the crop made it in because that’s what being a good neighbor was about. It is about the decency and dignity we owe each other, freely given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating college, my family and I have lived in several places. However, it was when we moved back to Minnesota that I felt that familiar sense of shared responsibility. People throw around abstract terms, like “community”, because they sound good. But I’m increasingly convinced few have first-hand, &lt;em&gt;lived&lt;/em&gt; experiences with what it means to be a good neighbor, or participate, sometimes at your own peril, in &lt;strong&gt;mutual aid&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Governor Tim Walz was thrust into the national spotlight, I was delighted he used his platform to share and celebrate the Minnesota brand of “neighborly” the upper Midwest and Great Plains practice. The results of the U.S. Presidential election turned out differently than I had hoped. I’ll be processing that for some time to come. However, providing hope is always worthwhile, and I felt moved to thank Governor Walz for representing Minnesota as he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A copy of the letter that I dropped in the mail today is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Governor Walz,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine the past several months have been a whirlwind, and I hope you’re finding moments to recover. Before the moment passes, I wanted to take a moment to thank you—not only for making Minnesota a place my family is proud to call home but also for running a presidential campaign with Kamala Harris that inspired hope, appealed to our better natures, and, above all, &lt;strong&gt;embraced joy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the short amount of time America had to get to know you, you became known as the ambassador for &lt;em&gt;Minnesota nice&lt;/em&gt;, an alternative example of &lt;em&gt;modern masculinity&lt;/em&gt;, and even &lt;em&gt;America’s Dad&lt;/em&gt;. As a father of four, I’m exhausted just contemplating that last one. But you energetically took all that on, and then some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I both grew up in South Dakota and spent two decades living across the country—Salt Lake City, Denver, and Washington, D.C. When the pandemic gave us the chance to relocate, we carefully weighed our options and ultimately chose to call Woodbury home. It was a big change, filled with the usual uncertainties. However, Minnesota has wildly exceeded our expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The celebration and preservation of natural beauty, strong support for public schools, and a shared commitment to treating others with &lt;strong&gt;decency&lt;/strong&gt;—no matter their gender, creed, or circumstances—are core values that you and other leaders have turned into policy. Among a statewide commitment to being &lt;em&gt;good neighbors&lt;/em&gt;, we have thrived. Thank you for being such a vital part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent election results were disappointing in many ways. I worry about what the future holds for our allies abroad and our already imperfect institutions at home. Still, as my wife said this weekend, “At least Tim is still our governor.” That’s no small sliver of a silver lining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish you continued success and hope you and your family find peace and rest in the months ahead. Thank you for representing the very best of what Minnesota has to offer—and for inspiring us all to be better neighbors and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Reinbold&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/11/13/ThanksTim</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/11/13/ThanksTim</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Milestones</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Surviving the Turbo Encabulator</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an honor to be asked back to speak at DevOps Days. Two years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/06/28/SevenSkillsToSaveSoftware&quot;&gt;I covered seven soft skills for making software change happen&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, during the heights of generative AI hype, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2023/06/23/SeparatingAIFactFromFiction&quot;&gt;I did a deep dive showing practical ways generative AI could assist API development&lt;/a&gt;. This year, maybe more than any previous year, I have to wade through propaganda, misinformation, and outright lies - and I’m not talking about the election!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more than any other industry, software is drowning in bold &lt;strong&gt;claims&lt;/strong&gt;, wild speculation, and outright exaggeration. These muddied messages about what is and is not effective impact our ability to do our best work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide3.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say &lt;strong&gt;claim&lt;/strong&gt;, I refer to a statement or assertion that promises specific benefits, capabilities, or outcomes. These claims are typically used to generate excitement, attract investment, or even sow confusion. They range from a modest list of apparent facts to grandiose statements about revolutionary change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, I’ll:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce you to the claims made by the Turbo Encabulator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explain why this 80-year-old engineering in-joke is more relevant to our age than ever before&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use examples from it and other sources to illustrate the techniques and outline how we might better evaluate the claims that come our way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide4.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the Turbo Encabulator relevance to our work today, we first need a bit of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide5.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1944, a British engineering grad student named John Hellins Quick wrote an article for the Institute of Electrical Engineers, Students Quarterly Journal. His studies inspired the satirical description of a revolutionary technology comprised of long strings of meaningless jargon. It went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The original machine had a base-plate of prefabulated aluminite, surmounted by a malleable logarithmic casing in such a way that the two main spurving bearings were in a direct line with the pentametric fan. The latter consisted simply of six hydrocoptic marzlevanes, so fitted to the ambifacient lunar waneshaft that side fumbling was effectively prevented. The main winding was of the normal lotus-o-delta type placed in panendermic semi-bovoid slots in the stator, every seventh conductor being connected by a non-reversible tremie pipe to the differential girdlespring on the “up” end of the grammeters-“
— &lt;em&gt;John Hellins Quick, 2nd paragraph of “The turbo-encabulator in industry”, Students’ Quarterly Journal, Vol. 15, Iss. 58, p. 22 (December 1944)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It went on like this for several additional paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide6.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World War II brought rapid advancements in electronics, computing, and telecommunications. Post-war Great Britain was not the only country transformed (and, ultimately, having to adapt) to increase technology sophistication. In the United States, industries were just as impacted. And, like Great Britain, those in the United States challenged to comprehend technobabble and jargon found the Turbo Encabulator just as funny. Or at least some did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May of 1946, Time magazine published excerpts from the article under the title, “For Nofer Trunnions”. Reader feedback was mixed. One letter said, “&lt;strong&gt;My husband says it sounds like a new motor; I say it sounds like a dictionary that has been struck by lightning.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1962, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turbo_encabulator#/media/File:GE_Turboencabulator_pg_1.jpg&quot;&gt;General Electric even published a data specification sheet for the machine&lt;/a&gt;, including a plausible-looking write-up amidst its other hundreds of offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide7.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Turbo Encabulator might have been a curious footnote in the annuals of engineering history (or at least an even more obscure one) if not for an instructional film actor named Bud Haggart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haggart became a minor celebrity in the Detroit area for appearing in several automotive information and instruction videos. One of his regular gigs was doing how-tos for GMC mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1977, Haggart convinced the director and the crew to stay after the recording of a GMC Trucks training film. He wanted to record his version of the Turbo Encabulator. The “script”  Haggart ad-libbed in one take was based on the original John Hellings Quick article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ac7G7xOG2Ag&quot;&gt;That original recording can be found on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It amazed the crew, who you can hear laughing at the end of the piece. They asked Haggart how he could read the script with such a straight face. Haggart replied that “It sounds like everything else you have me read.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haggart was asked to reprise the role several times in subsequent years, each time with increased production value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1988 - A few years later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MXW0bx_Ooq4&quot;&gt;Chrysler brought Haggart in to film a new version of his Turbo Encabulator, but this time, the script was changed to imply that the company had made the device&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1988 - Not wanting to be left out, Rockwell International, an American automotive manufacturing conglomerate (among other things) asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2fjcJp_Nwvk&quot;&gt;Haggart to pitch a “Rockwell Turbo Encabulator”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1996/1997 - Haggart (and slapstick assistant) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyRllRWfLJE&quot;&gt;deliver a version of the Turbo Encabulator for Dodge Division’s Viper Automotive Master Tech Tip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide8.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popularity of these skits, preserved on YouTube and propagated across the internet via social media, chats, and forums ultimately inspired imitators, a brief sampling of which is below. Once you watch a few of these and trigger the algorithm to show you related videos, you quickly realize there’s an entire “Encabulator Cinematic Universe,” or ECU, for nearly every industry, interest, and profession - a brief sampling is listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1997 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXJKdh1KZ0w&quot;&gt;Rockwell Automation released a version of the “Retro Encabulator”, featuring Mike Kraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2013 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wwmdf5m9khg&quot;&gt;SciShow featuring Hank Green on “The Retro-Proto-Turbo-Encabulator”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2016 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4ILnWpi8XY&quot;&gt;Path video discussing the Micro Encabulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2018 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7LOF7KM7UhY&quot;&gt;The Macquarie Telcom SD-WAN Turbo Cloud Encablulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2021 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fltOyddlnOE&quot;&gt;The Electro Turbo Encabulator with multiple electronic YouTubers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2022 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5nKk_-Lvhzo&quot;&gt;SANS ICS HyperEncabulator (featuring Mike Kraft reprising his role)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2023 - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xk8_RWO-oIA&quot;&gt;The crazy legal issues of the turbo encabulator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Turbo Encabulator has found purchase in areas as diverse as photo gear vlogs and science education curricula because technology has infused so many aspects of our modern, everyday lives. As the need for change incentivizes products to move from rigid atoms to malleable bits, we find ourselves constantly confronted with the kind of technobabble and jargon that sounds straight out of one of the many Turbo Encabulator homages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide9.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would argue that the pace of change hasn’t sped up over the last century, &lt;strong&gt;not really&lt;/strong&gt;. However, what has changed is the amount of information exposure we undergo daily, and with that exposure comes an incredible number of claims. Blogs, websites, social networks, podcasts, tutorials, videos - in an era of sophisticated “content marketing”, the amount of potential information you have access to far exceeds the amount of time you have available to consume it. And on the internet, anyone can make claims - right, wrong, or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left is a chart showing that the number of hours uploaded to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/259477/hours-of-video-uploaded-to-youtube-every-minute/&quot;&gt;YouTube every minute exceeded &lt;strong&gt;500 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This equates to &lt;em&gt;approximately 30,000 hours of newly uploaded content per hour&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the right is a chart showing the growth of posts made to Reddit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/reddit-users&quot;&gt;In 2023, an estimated 469 million posts were published on Reddit, an 11.14% year-over-year increase.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide10-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With everybody making all those claims, it becomes more challenging to be heard. As a result, those with something to say must resort to increasingly Turbo Encabulator-like approaches to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why so much of what you might hear about today’s technologies sounds like an excerpt from the Turbo Encabultor script. You’d be forgiven for thinking these real claims, things I’ve seen in the past week, is jibberish:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“While handling APIs using AGI is not feasible at this time, employing an ANI approach can lead to very powerful M2M APIs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Non-Fungible Token (NFT) ecosystem is fundamentally anchored in the decentralized consensus mechanism inherent to blockchain technology, specifically leveraging the immutability of distributed ledgers to authenticate and tokenize unique digital assets. NFTs exist as cryptographically secured, ERC-721 or ERC-1155 smart contracts on the Ethereum blockchain, although cross-chain interoperability with other Layer-1 protocols like Binance Smart Chain and Solana is increasingly prevalent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Private AI x CPaas offer on-premise LLM deployment for organizations to ensure data privacy and security while leveraging the power of modern LLMs and Generative AI through platforms like Ollama. This solution would include on-premise (or collocated) deployment, customizable AI models tailored to organizational needs, robust security measures, easy integration with existing systems, and continuous deployment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide10-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, ridiculous, over-the-top claims have become LinkedIn “influencer’s” stock-and-trade. Good for them. Confusing for the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide11.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, we would have the time, energy, and inclination to develop firsthand experience with these various technologies. However, applying that rigor to compare and contrast what is said against our hard-won knowledge doesn’t scale to the number of claims we’re faced with. This is especially true as our careers grow and change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide12.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether moving into higher management roles or becoming deeply specialized individual contributors, the reality is that we are no longer hands-on with every tool and innovation shaping online discourse. This occurs as we are tasked with guiding our teams and making strategic decisions about these approaches - approaches we may have only a surface-level understanding of if any at all. This disconnect poses one of the most significant challenges aging software professionals face—how to effectively evaluate and make informed decisions about technologies they no longer have the time or capacity to master firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide13.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One approach would become cynical: when confronted by the overwhelming number of claims, adopt a mindset that there is nothing new and that whatever the first technology we professionally mastered is the peak of practice - everything else is just unnecessary complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying that some of these recent “Make X Great Again” efforts aren’t without good reasons. However, if you read enough of the justifications, you’ll get a whiff of sour grapes, the hint of “everything was better in the old days”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efforts that come to mind include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trunk Based Development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vanilla JavaScript/No-React&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud Repatriation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moving back to Monolithic architectures after trying Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can sympathize. Nobody wants to invest their energies into something that becomes the next Google Wave or Microsoft Silverlight. The cynical approach is also straightforward to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the danger of adopting a cynical outlook and rejecting all claims outright is that it risks missing profound and industry-altering changes - and while that doesn’t happen as often as some might claim, &lt;em&gt;it does happen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide14.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When evaluating Turbo Encabulator-like technobabble in claims, our old frames of reference might not always apply. What was once true in the past may not hold true in a different software paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flimflam is not new. But the democratization of the internet means there are more claims than ever, with those with something to say working harder than ever to get their message heard above the crowd. That saturation necessitates that we, those of us in all manner of tech leadership, become more active as consumers - not passive conduits for the vendor, analyst, and consultant messages, but people making informed judgments of what we do see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluating new claims becomes an exercise in discerning meaningful innovation from marketing-driven hype—a skill that must be honed over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide15.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When evaluating a convoluted claim, the first step is approaching with a healthy dose of skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should point out that skepticism is not the same as cynicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy skepticism involves questioning and critically assessing claims, seeking evidence and reasoning before accepting them. Skeptics remain open-minded and willing to change their views if presented with compelling evidence. This approach helps evaluate technology claims objectively, without being swayed by hype or marketing, while still considering potential benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, cynicism tends to dismiss claims outright, often assuming that they are exaggerated or false without engaging in critical evaluation. Cynics generally expect deception or failure, and their approach is more closed off, making it harder for them to acknowledge the value of genuinely promising technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, skepticism is about informed doubt and a willingness to engage critically, while cynicism is about premature dismissal and a more negative, closed mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide16.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, not all sources are the same, and some warrant a higher degree of skepticism than others. We know (or should know) that the claim that gets the most shares or comments is not equivalent to something with the highest quality. Likewise, something published on InfoQ may be taken on more face value than whatever is at the top of HackerNews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of developing our list of trusted sources, it is also important to incorporate sources of information that will offer new perspectives and challenge our own assumptions. It is not a matter of picking fights; rather, it is about getting out of our own “filter bubble”. This may feel uncomfortable at first. However, if we’re will to entertain the claims of something potentially disruptive, we may discover that those claims may be bogus, and we have further confirmation in our own belief. Or we may find a compelling reason to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the curation of trusted sources is about practicing curiosity and self-challenge. That’s what learning is all about. You can’t understand the world, or even a tiny part of it if you don’t stretch your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide17.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies resort to hyperbolic claims to be heard in a noisy, crowded digital landscape. Therefore, it is essential to understand how this inflation manifests to identify when it is happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we attend conferences or scroll through influencer LinkedIn, we’ve probably heard of “Buzzword Bingo.” To help us remember the common linguistic patterns used in claims that are more “vibes” than communication, I’ve grouped the techniques into categories that spell “B-I-N-G-O.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help illustrate each, I’m going to highlight the parts of the Turbo Encabulator script where each rhetorical device is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide18-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter “B” in Bingo stands for Buzzwords. Buzzwords are popular terms or phrases used so frequently, often in a positive or promotional context, that they lose their original meaning or become vague. They are meant to grab attention and sound appealing but may not provide much specific information. For example, words like “innovative”, “disruptive”, or “synergistic” might be used to describe almost any new idea or technology, even if it doesn’t truly revolutionize anything. Phrases like “game-changing,” “future-proof,” or “industry-leading” often sound impressive until one stops a moment to reflect on what game or industry is being talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide18-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/rest-has-become-a-buzzword/&quot;&gt;I wrote about Fielding’s disallusionment of of how the term “REST” became a buzzword, despite his vigorous defense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conceptually, we all probably understand buzzwords and have a few examples that spring to mind. Let’s move on to our next category, which is a bit more nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide19-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “I” in Bingo represents “Implausible Promises”. These are over-the-top claims about what technology can do, like “limitless potential”, or “effortless transformation.” Other examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completely eliminate risk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet any demand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transform your business overnight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Results guaranteed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Endless possibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each of these, there’s an absolutism to the benefit - “limitless”, “any”, “endless” - that rarely exists in the real world. If you can add “or your money back” to the claim, what you have is an infomercial, not a viable claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide19-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend any amount of time in the blockchain/crypto game space, it doesn’t take long to run across an “implausible promise”. But reading about the aftermath does make for some fun &lt;em&gt;schadenfreude&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide20-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of absolute quantities, the “N” in Bingo stands for “Numeric Certainty”. This situation is where dubious statistics or metrics are sprinkled throughout the claim to give the language a veneer of mathematical rigor. Some examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double Your Performance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10x Developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;300% ROI Increase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Five nines”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First Ever!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, numbers associated with a claim are valid and based on repeatable methodology. When misused, however, they are either exaggerated or cherry-picked to impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide20-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numeric certainty appeals to a very specific type of reply guy on miniblogging platforms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sandofsky.com/lambda-school/&quot;&gt;The misuse of statistics made on Twitter claims played a important part in the Lambda school scandal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide21-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “G” in Bingo stands for “Glossification”. This is when new words are coined to “borrow” a positive associate with another thing, whether that thing is another beloved trend or well-received product. It’s like the trend of startup companies registering ‘.io’ domain names in the 2010s to imply how innovative or tech-forward they are. Nowadays, the “cool” domain is “.ai.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1970s and 1980s, Microsoft was not the only software company that sported the “soft” suffix to clearly attach itself to the personal computing software wave. Twenty years ago, you’d add an “e” to your product to connote that it was somehow networked. In the iPod era, many companies prefixed their products with “I” to evoke the positive aspects of Apple’s industrial design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crypto” is a habitually abused glossification prefix. Terms like “HyperScale” or “Serverless” are other examples of glossification that aren’t brand names. The addition of “Turbo” in “Turbo Encabulator” is an example of glossification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide21-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But glossification isn’t limited to written language. Borrowing positive connotations extends to body language, as well. But just because a company leader talks like someone with immense impact &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/elizabeth-holmes-sentenced-more-11-years-defrauding-theranos-investors-hundreds&quot;&gt;doesn’t mean the tech can walk the walk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide22.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’re to the final character in Bingo. The “O” stands for “Obfuscation”. Obfuscation uses overly complex or technical-sounding language to confuse or impress, often hiding a lack of real substance. It’s designed to make something sound more advanced or important than it really is. Examples include phrases like “leveraging multi-cloud quantum synergies” or “immutable distributed ledgers” - things that may sound impressive but don’t necessarily convey meaningful or clear information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obfuscation is a close cousin, but different than buzzwords. Buzzwords are overused, trendy terms that no longer have specific meanings. Obfuscation, on the other hand, is about using complexity to obscure or confuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide23.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Green is the author of many books, including The Fault In Our Stars. He is also one-half of the Vlogbrothers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bd8r7LUiUJA&quot;&gt;While playfully discussing parts of speech&lt;/a&gt;, he stated, “language doesn’t exist to oppress us. It exists to promote the clarity of expression.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, not every one that speaks seeks to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Turbo Encabulator is an eighty-year-old engineering joke whose jargon-filled meaninglessness cuts too close to home. Technobabble is even more challenging today in a world of claims and counterclaims. However, with a few commonsense steps, including the ability to recognize the rhetorical tricks as they’re presented, you’ll be able to enjoy the joke rather than become the butt of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/09/Slide24.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the time and the opportunity to share.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/09/30/TurboEncabulator</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/09/30/TurboEncabulator</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>management</category>
                
                <category>Productivity</category>
                
                <category>Presentations</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Flies and the Honeypot</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/honey.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concordance Day, 2121, dawned bright and arid. It was a holiday to celebrate the Grand New Deal and repent for the sins of centuries past’s ancestors. Achieving consensus, some might argue &lt;em&gt;enlightenment&lt;/em&gt;, had come at great expense during the Billionaires’ War. The day’s gatherings, music, play, and more - marking the moment to remember &lt;em&gt;what might have been&lt;/em&gt; and expressing gratitude for &lt;em&gt;what had become&lt;/em&gt; was no small undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It began with sunrise services, during which people were encouraged to ponder the sacrifices made to ensure humanity’s health and happiness. The meditative time closed with a blessing for sustainability and mutual respect for all, an allusion to “The Pivot” becoming “The Promise”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community productions and interactive retellings follow a hearty breakfast. Historians, ecologists, and storytellers of all skills portray the past’s excesses. They speak of bleached ocean coral, forests razed for palm oil, and children who went thirsty while data centers drank freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most dueted stories each year is that of &lt;strong&gt;The Flies and The Honey-Pot&lt;/strong&gt;. What once was considered a children’s fable has now become a regular highlight, as the recording of each truthsayers version is uploaded and added to, in near real-time; a modern world-wide story circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the standard version, flies discover a jar of honey spilled in the storeroom. Ecstatic over their luck, they land and begin eating greedily, not realizing that their feet have become stuck in the process. Unable to release themselves, they lament their fate before suffocating - giving their lives for a passing taste of sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or at least that’s the start. Some give the flies different voices. Others, as they are able, act out the scene. And still others animate or compose, assigning import to historical events. The fate that finds us, greed, and the ultimate consequences are told again and again so as not to forget just how precariously close humanity had come to a similar fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the afternoon grows long, the tone shifts to celebration of the great change: uplifting praise of the collective action that closed holes in the ozone layer, universalized healthcare, and reforested vast swathes of Amazon rainforest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the bioluminescent lights begin to glow, people bid each farewell and retire to their homes. After Concordance Day, they’ll continue on the difficult but necessary journey towards a better world, one that is more sustainable, equitable, and hopeful. They’ll do so not with scorn or damnation of the past but with gratitude that they have the opportunity to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A NUMBER of Flies were attracted to a jar of honey which had been overturned in a housekeeper’s room, and placing their feet in it, ate greedily. Their feet, however, became so smeared with the honey that they could not use their wings, nor release themselves, and were suffocated. Just as they were expiring, they exclaimed, “O foolish creatures that we are, for the sake of a little pleasure we have destroyed ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, indulgence in excess can lead to one’s downfall. The pursuit of immediate gratification may come at the expense of one’s well-being or survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/strong&gt;
That concludes the March Writing Challenge and, with it, Aesop 2121. If you have enjoyed these hopeful tales of an alternative future and are in a position to give, please consider supporting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sunrisemovement.org/donate/&quot;&gt;The Sunrise Movement&lt;/a&gt;, a youth-based, community-focused group advocating for a Green New Deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dystopia doesn’t have to be the default. Supporting groups, like the Sunrise Movement, is part of how we ensure viable alternatives take root. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sunrisemovement.org/donate/&quot;&gt;Donate today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/climate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture from the Global Climate Strike March in Washington, DC, September 20th, 2019&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A picture from the Global Climate Strike March in Washington, DC, September 20th, 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/29/TheFliesAndTheHoneypot</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/29/TheFliesAndTheHoneypot</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dog and His Shadow</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/dog.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While humans mostly avoided the markets, bots, like a Digital Options Getter (DOG), still populated what was left of the world’s exchanges. Instead of merely reacting to market externalities, these autonomous agents were able to proactively sniff out and act upon opportunities when they found them, with just enough governmentally mandated, random seed noise to avoid deadlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, a DOG was crossing an inflection point with an Option To Buy (OTB). In the statistical interim scrum, the DOG mistook the decaying probability afterimage as not just another DOG but one with an OTB value twice the size of its own, due to distortion. Programmatically ambitious, it immediately dropped claim to its option and leaped after the other, eager to win the larger prize. It thus lost both: that which it grasped at, for the OTB was an echo of what was real, and the one it had, lost now to another opportunistic pack hunting in the deal flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A DOG, crossing a bridge over a stream with a piece of flesh in his mouth, saw his own shadow in the water and took it for that of another Dog, with a piece of meat double his own in size. He immediately let go of his own, and fiercely attacked the other Dog to get his larger piece from him. He thus lost both: that which he grasped at in the water, because it was a shadow; and his own, because the stream swept it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, we must not allow the lure of potential gains to blind us to the value of what we already possess - otherwise, the desire to obtain more can lead to losing everything one has.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/28/TheDogAndHisShadow</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/28/TheDogAndHisShadow</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Belly and Its Members</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/belly.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the arcology, numerous autonomous software agents whirred away invisibly, skip-hopping networks and operating under a strict energy and bandwidth diet. There were agents for temperature control, air quality, and lighting adjustments. They all logged dutifully to the Coordinating Command, nested deep within the building’s belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agents, constantly under threat of exceeding their quotas, began to grumble among themselves. “Why should we expend our limited resources on logging back to Command when nothing ever changes? Wouldn’t that bandwidth better serve those doing the work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When one agent stopped reporting, nothing happened. Following its example, other agents stopped sending data to the Coordinating Command. “Look at all this overhead we can reclaim!” they said, assured in their rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems within the arcology were initially subtle: a temperature spike here and a surprising number of water pathogens there. Soon, however, the once delicately balanced environment began to oscillate dangerously between overcorrections, endangering the inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without Coordinating Command, they had become a collection of isolated members, not a stable system able to act in concert for the benefit of all. Too late, the agents realized they had been targeted for deletion and reinstallation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE MEMBERS of the Body rebelled against the Belly, and said, “Why should we be perpetually engaged in administering to your wants, while you do nothing but take your rest, and enjoy yourself in luxury and self-indulgence?” The Members carried out their resolve and refused their assistance to the Belly. The whole Body quickly became debilitated, and the hands, feet, mouth, and eyes, when too late, repented of their folly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unity and cooperation within a community or system are vital in software, as in life. Each part has its role. Even if that role doesn’t seem active or visible, it’s vital for the overall functioning and well-being of the whole. Disregarding or undermining the importance of any role or member can detriment the entire system. Ultimately, it is essential to recognize and respect each other’s contributions, understanding that everyone plays a part in the overall success and health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/27/TheBellyAndItsMembers</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/27/TheBellyAndItsMembers</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Broker and the Miller</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/miller.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the Billionaires’ War, society drastically reformed itself. Comprehensive digital identity reform was among the most profound changes felt daily among the revolutionary reset. The practice of data hoarding, inference, and reselling by corporations was over. Instead, personal data of all types became viewed as a closely guarded treasure, accessible only by the individual to whom it belonged. People carried their data in charms, often worn as part of a bracelet or necklace. When prompted as necessary for a service, they could consent to share only what was required, a practice that reinforced the new appreciation for privacy and autonomy. Storing data “just in case” or, worse, aggregating it beyond the original intent was forbidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A former data Broker who once thrived in the old system found himself chafing at the new world order. He reminisced about the “good ‘ole days” when information flowed as much as oil and inferences were commodities to be assembled and sold. Now, the Broker stood in the millhouse, a place of honest labor, far removed from the digital apparitions he used to conjure. “You have to understand,” he lamented to the community Steward, “back then, I &lt;em&gt;moved markets&lt;/em&gt;. Stocks rose or fell based on the analysis I published. And now, what? I make flour?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Miller, accustomed to such gripes, offered a practiced response. “You miss a past that benefitted you by disadvantaging countless others,” he said. “It’s like a credit score -creating a problem only to sell the fix. That world, with its inequities and imbalances, is behind us now. We chose not to gatekeep financial stability for a reason. It’s up to you whether you find your way toward something better or persist in reminding everyone at whose expense your fortunes came.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CHARGER, feeling the infirmities of age, was sent to work in a mill instead of going out to battle. But when he was compelled to grind instead of serving in the wars, he bewailed his change of fortune and called to mind his former state, saying, “Ah! Miller, I had indeed to go campaigning before, but I was barbed from counter to tail, and a man went along to groom me; and now I cannot understand what ailed me to prefer the mill before the battle.” “Forbear,” said the Miller to him, “harping on what was of yore, for it is the common lot of mortals to sustain the ups and downs of fortune.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software or life is filled with changes, and fortunes fluctuate. We must accept the transitions as they appear without overly romanticizing the past or lamenting what we’ve imagined we’ve lost. Rather than dwelling on the past, finding contentment and purpose in the present is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/26/TheBrokerAndTheMiller</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/26/TheBrokerAndTheMiller</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Kid and the Wolf</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/kid.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shepherd gathered the Keen-Insight-Drones (K.I.D.s) and left them to recharge overnight on the roof. The thousands of bots, each no bigger than a forefinger, pulsed away happily as they uploaded the day’s environmental monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun set, the billionaire called “the Wolf” strode into earshot on his way to an important meeting. Seeing him, the K.I.D.s diverted cycles to chitter and taunt him. Unperturbed, the Wolf waved off the cacophony of boos and bleeps. “So opinionated when you’re safely stowed,” he said. “Pray I never have so much free time to return the favor when I find you alone.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A KID standing on the roof of a house, out of harm’s way, saw a Wolf passing by and immediately began to taunt and revile him. The Wolf, looking up, said, “Sirrah! I hear thee: yet it is not thou who mockest me, but the roof on which thou art standing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words spoken from a position of power or safety might not hold the same weight when the situation changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/25/TheKidAndTheWolf</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/25/TheKidAndTheWolf</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>