<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:17:28 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:17:28 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Moneyballer Americana - 04</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Moneyballer Americana&lt;/strong&gt; is a seven-part novelette about a struggling bluegrass musician who accidentally ignites a sports-betting media frenzy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Come back each day for the next installment. When all seven parts are published, they’ll be compiled into a single downloadable version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 4 - Breaking the Huddle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli parked his Outback - it should be noted - without any alarming clunks or shuddering protests. The check engine light also no longer shown. His cut of the sponsorship windfall had set all to rights. At least materially with the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He fed the meter and bent upwards to admire the downtown buildings before a cold blast snapped his revelry. Eli pulled his coat in tight and ducked into the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steakhouse had apparently been chosen for “vibes” rather than its acoustics, because the place was a cavernous drum of concrete, brushed steel, and wood paneling. Every echoed fork clank and chair scrape caused him to wince like a missed note during a solo. That is, when the discord could be heard over the televised games lining the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty and Lance had insisted this was “where athletes go”, although a quick scan of the patrons on this particular busy Saturday night suggested clientele closer to golf, maybe pickelball than crossfit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli checked his messages - still no update from the band. He shelved that concern as the host led him to a tall-backed booth in the back. Ty and Lance were already there, excitedly conspiring about something on their phones. Ty had on a relaxed fit sports coat. His power chic contrasted with Lance, who wore a jersey and yet another clunky, oversized watch. Eli felt suddenly self-conscious in his white button-up and stage jeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ELIIIII!” Lance shouted a bit too aggressively as he approached, as if the announcement was more a call for attention from those around them than an actual greeting for him, “Our rainmaker!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you pumped for tonight!” Ty pounded the table. “I am so pumped.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a &lt;em&gt;rocket&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;da moon&lt;/em&gt;!” Lance said, high-fiving Ty, “And you got on board at just the right moment. &lt;em&gt;How awesome is that&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli forced a chuckle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. It’s been a learning experience, for sure.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some effort, but the trio was finally able to wave down the server for water. The place for athletes or not, it was certainly busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re clear on the plan, right?” Eli ventured, delicately navigating what he assumed could be challenging, “This guy reached out because he’s &lt;em&gt;interested in the business side of the show&lt;/em&gt;. Not the betting. Not lines. Just talking shop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty rolled his eyes. “Yeah, you already said that in the email. Relax, would you?” Ty waggled his thumb between Lance and himself, “We know how to talk to players.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if on cue, they saw their guest cutting through the crowd toward them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fellas! How we doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock Schlesinger was much more massive than Eli expected. Of course, Eli reminded himself, even a mountain of a blocking tight end probably appears on TV downright svelte next to the average offensive linemen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock seemed to move with a slight stiffness, betraying a lifetime of hard knocks - something at odds with his young, twenty-something face. He wore nondescript, gray sweats and a battered ball cap - much less “celebrity sighting”, and more “guy grabbing ice melt before the hardware store closes”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These are the guys I recognize. Hello Ty! Hello Lance. So glad we could connect while I was in town.” Brock shook their hands before turning to Eli. “And you must be Eli, the one I’ve been emailing with.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli felt his hand engulfed, and marveled at how easily his hand could be crushed, if Brock wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some additional difficulty getting the staff’s attention, menus were exchanged. Brock declined the drink cart. Opening pleasantries were exchanged, which - with Ty and Lance’s eagerness leading the conversation like a dog chasing a rabbit - could have gone very badly. However, Eli was impressed by Brock’s dexterity at turning awkward interludes into passable, even charming, moments. Countless meet ‘n greets and press interviews must have been good practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orders were taken, and then Ty and Lance recounted their latest feats: the Dettmer scoop, the line movement, and the other big moves they saw “just over the horizon”. It was like they were conducting a rumorville Rorschach test - tossing out a vague notion or half-formed impression, gauging Brock’s response, and then breathlessly cycling to the next with little segue or subtlety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To his credit, Brock played along politely as he munched on the complimentary bread, at one point calling the server over for a refresh. But Eli sensed a growing exhaustion - shoulders slightly more rounded, smile a bit less authentic and more mechanical reflex as he, once again, deflected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah guys, I can’t say what the front office might be thinking there. Most weeks, I don’t even know the full gameplan until the last minute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Totally hear that,” Ty said, “Back when I was starting linebacker for State - &lt;em&gt;GO FIGHTING CARDS!&lt;/em&gt; - we always tried to stay super fluid right up to the last second, then we’d &lt;strong&gt;LOCK IT IN&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lance was about to launch into another of his, increasingly, conspiratorial scenarios but Brock cut him off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, talking about my work is fun and all,” he said, leaning forward, “but I’m really interested in what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m coming up on the end of my rookie contract. Don’t get me wrong, it has been a great four years. Getting drafted at all was a surprise-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-and haven’t missed a start since!” Lance said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, yeah. I wouldn’t trade the experience for anything. I’ve worked hard and been incredibly lucky. But I’ve been thinking a lot about the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty was confused. “Your next contract?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well…” Brock’s voice trailed off as he studied the ceiling, avoiding eye contact. “No. I need to be realistic. Since turning pro, I’ve never been on a winning team, and we’re trending that way again this year. They’re probably going to clean house at the end of the season, if not before. My rookie deal is up, so I’m no longer the cheapest option for a rebuild. And there’s just not that much demand for a blocking tight end that can’t catch in a passing league.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean,” Brock said, reconnecting with the group, “the average career for an NFL player is 3.3 years. I’ve managed four as a fifth round pick - and I’ve done that without a major injury or concussion. What are the odds?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But it just seems like it’s time to move on to what’s next, before I press my luck.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lance fidgeted with his massive watch, seeming to turn over this confession with each twist of the elastic band. “Couldn’t you, I dunno, be a broadcaster?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, my degree is communications. But they only really want big names for something like that.” Brock sipped his water. “Besides, my agent keeps saying that I need a ‘platform’. Like what you guys do, with the show. That’s why I wanted to get together - learn more about it, how you got started, the time investment - that sort of thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was about what Eli had expected after their email exchange. What was unexpected was watching the extra point sail wide past Ty’s head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Totally. Totally. We’d love to talk about your platform. Your timing is perfect. I’ve been thinking I really need to put together an online course. One of those self-paced ones? There’s so much I could coach people on about developing winner’s mindset, or starting controversies to get views.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s not-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I may,” Eli cut Brock off, apologetically, “I think what Brock is trying to say is that he’s looking for something stable. Something that he controls. You want something on your own terms. Did I get that right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock snapped his fingers and pointed at Eli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bingo. My man.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty and Lance regarded Eli, confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Eli could further elaborate, Brock’s phone chirped. He flipped it over, quickly skimming whatever snippet was shown on the lock screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hang on team. I need to answer this. I’ll be back in a minute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He ventured back toward the hostess, seeking somewhere sheltered from the din.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minute Brock was out of earshot, Lance hissed. “What was that? We have &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; for the next show. No overs. No inside dirt. &lt;em&gt;No nothing&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We will,” Ty said, his body language betraying his words, “We didn’t come this close to stop now. We just need to ask the right way. Like… guy-to-guy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli put his napkin on the table. “Guys, Brock really just wants some basics. I’m sure you guys have some stories about starting out? Like how you found your first audience? What things you learned to avoid?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well sure, I love reminiscing over beers as much as the next guy.” Lance said. “But we &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a scoop. If we don’t have the next big thing, our fans will move on. It’s sink or swim, whether we like it or not.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have to be an alpha shark if you’re going to survive being a new media entrepreneur,” Ty added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You keep moving,” Lance tapped the table for emphasis, “or you die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli, who had refrained from the bread feeding frenzy, felt a pit in the bottom of his stomach. He was pretty sure it wasn’t because he was hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, there was a commotion; dishes for multiple tables arrived simultaneously. Brock’s absence caused a momentary confusion, then four plates hit the table at once. The server was off again in a hurry, without so much as a water check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Speaking of fish, you see that?” Lance gestured to Brock’s setting. “He ordered seafood at a steak house. &lt;em&gt;Baller&lt;/em&gt; alpha move.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli blinked. “&lt;em&gt;What!?&lt;/em&gt; That is not a thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s totally a thing,” Lance insisted. “Showing out with shrimp pasta instead of ribeye? It means he’s alpha, like us. We’ll talk guy-to-guy. We’ll get that content.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shrimp just means… shellfish,” Eli said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He felt like he was on stage, and suddenly had to play around a broken string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock returned, serpentining between the tables and quickly sitting down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry about that. Team curfew check.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the others digging in, Brock grabbed his fork and scooped his entree with gusto. He bit down and his face froze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli watched, puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock dropped his fork, grabbed his napkin, and spat out the bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Was there shellfish in that?” He began turning pale and his eyes started to water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, yeah,” Ty said, stunned, “You ordered the shrimp pasta.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brock braced himself again the table. “I ordered,” Brock said, grimacing, “the chicken Alfredo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh no,” Eli said, scooting across the bench. “Oh no. Do you have an EpiPen?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the… rental,” Brock managed. “Outside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli helped Brock stand up and was fully, unfortunately, aware of just how big Brock was. They moved, weaving ungracefully back out through the tables in their haste, like trying to lug an upright bass through a tight stairwell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they made it through the doors. The cold now barely noticeable over the concern.  Brock’s wheeze could now be seen, the shuttering breath instantly turning to vapor. He weakly gestured to a sedan up the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they reached it, Brock fumbled with the handle and the car unlocked. He dropped into the seat and pulled a bag from the passenger seat. Clawing at a side pocket, he pulling out an EpiPen. Brock tore it from the packaging, regarded it for a moment, and then jabbed it in his thigh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a few minutes, the color started returning to his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli shivered slightly, arms crossed, standing beside the open door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You good?” Eli asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” Brock managed, “Thanks. Haven’t had a close call like that in awhile. I’m not sure what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There must have been a mix up with the other table. Do you want me to go back inside, see if I can straighten it out? Get the Alfredo to go?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I appreciate that but,” Brock shook his head, “I already owe you one. You’ve done enough. I think I’m going to bail, find the team doc at the hotel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli stayed with him for a few more minutes, making sure he was good to drive, and then watched him pull away. A sudden shiver reminded him this was no weather to be caught outside without a coat. With a sigh, he returned to the restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the booth, Eli found Ty and Lance on their phones. They both looked up at him, expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So,” Ty started, “Is he gonna be OK?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” Eli said, sitting down. “I think he’s out of the woods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But,” Lance asked, phone held up at the ready, “Is he good to start tomorrow?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli stumbled. “I… I don’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bro. If he misses the start… that’s actually crazy. Do you know what that will do to the props?” Ty punched Lance’s shoulder. “The subs are going to eat this up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is it! This is our next exclusive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We gotta get on our Discord. This is huge.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty reached out and shook Eli’s shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DUDE. Do you realize what this means?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pit inside Eli’s stomach was suddenly unavoidable. He looked down at his untouched plate of food. In the ensuing chaos, it had grown cold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/07/MoneyballerAmericana-04</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/07/MoneyballerAmericana-04</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Moneyballer Americana - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Moneyballer Americana&lt;/strong&gt; is a seven-part novelette about a struggling bluegrass musician who accidentally ignites a sports-betting media frenzy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Come back each day for the next installment. When all seven parts are published, they’ll be compiled into a single downloadable version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Booth Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marci came home with groceries as Eli was scrolling through the show’s email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, can you help me with these?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli popped up off the counter barstool and took both of the paper bags. Marci hung her winter coat on a peg near the door, next to her school para badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No band practice tonight?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rupert had sick kids, so we postponed.” Eli took the frozen items out of the bag and began making room for them in the fridge’s freezer. “For the best, probably. Gives me a chance to figure out what to say to them about the TEDx gig.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marci rolled up her sweater sleeves to help. “You heard back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yep.” Eli pushed aside a bag of peas. “The usual, ‘Thank you for your submission. We received several outstanding applications. Unfortunately, we could only select a handful, blah, blah blah.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry.” Marci tenderly put her arms around Eli’s neck and hugged. “I know you guys worked hard on your pitch.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you.” They kissed briefly and then Eli turned back to the remaining items in the bag. “Oh well. The conference’s loss, really. I had a really killer mandolin solo prepared.”
Marci smiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sure you did. Any news on the bluegrass cruise?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It might still happen,” Eli said, half-heartedly, “We still have a slot to perform. The deadline to let them know is coming up.” Eli sighed, looking at the handful of bills waiting for attention on the counter. “But I just don’t know if that’s the right call with everything else going on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, we’re not solving anything on empty stomach. Let’s get some food on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over supper, Eli recounted the most recent show. It had been quite the affair. Last Tuesday’s conjecture over Ali Dettmer had become &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; Tuesday’s reality - the Raiders had made the trade.  Ty and Lance had spent the stream crowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was after that production that Lance had given Eli access to the show’s email, “on a trial period”. Something about “a chance to hammer on his winner grindset”. The thousand unread messages, many new since the previous taping, suggested a different reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, I know you just started working with these guys, but,” Marci hesitated, forked hotdish suspended in the air, “is this like an act? Like, are these characters they do for the show? Or are they like this all the time?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli had his suspicions, but his Mom always said if you don’t have anything nice to say, &lt;em&gt;write a song, instead&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe he’d do that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Eli concluded. “They’re certainly… enthusiastic.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After helping finish the dishes, Eli poured a glass of wine for himself and Marci. He then turned on the TV. After some fumbling, he found the right combination of apps and logins for the Thursday Night football game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marci raised an eyebrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is this our life now?” she teased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Call it research.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marci smirked, sat her glass down, and picked up her book off the end-table. She stretched her legs so that her woolen-socked feet could rest in Eli’s lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a majority of Americans, Eli been to the occasional Super Bowl party or stumbled across a football game while flipping channels. But sitting there, &lt;em&gt;studying&lt;/em&gt; what the game had become, was a different experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He thought he’d strum his guitar along with the commercial jingles, but quickly abandoned that plan. There wasn’t much to play along with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ENTER THE PROMO CODE, AND GET $200 IN BONUS BETS AFTER YOUR FIRST DEPOSIT.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“BOOSTED ODDS ON THE OPENING KICKOFF DISTANCE! SCAN THE QR CODE BEFORE THE KICKER LINES UP!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most had celebrities that Eli recognized. But there was the one that was little more than a mascot holding a “FREE MONEY” banner for a majority of the ad, before violently exploding into multi-colored confetti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard to harmonize off of explosions and shouting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli had always thought of Ty and Lance as their own distinct thing. But he was surprised by how much the pregame patter could be mistaken for an episode of Bet Ballers. The chyron repeated the spread live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And more ads. So discordant with the broadcast’s triumphant, orchestral fanfare  bumpers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So &lt;em&gt;that’s&lt;/em&gt; what a parlay is?” Marci’s book sat in her lap as she watched, confused. “My kids at school are always going on about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not just your kids. I had to convert a lesson to gambling-eese at the middle school this week just to get it to click.” Eli turned the laptop around so that Marci could see the inbox’s unread count. “And then there’s all these, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, they certainly run enough ads. That’s got to cost a lot.”
It was a good point. Eli decided not to mention one of the companies in the ads also owned the stadium naming rights, which would cost even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; money. A headache was forming behind his eyes; the kind he usually got during tax season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game, itself, wasn’t much of a distraction from his growing unease. While not being a “sports guy”, Eli could appreciate a good performance. This, however, was not one of those, with both teams seeming out of sorts on a short week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tonight’s injury report brought to you by BETTER BEATDOWN, the social betting game where YOU CAN BEAT YOUR FRIENDS FOR FREE.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli kept the game on in the background while he triaged the inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a new item atop the queue, “Request for Sponsorship Details”. After a bit of Googling, it seemed legit - a national sports bar chain was looking to find non-traditional media partners. They were interested in basic stats for the show, along with some sponsorship suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lance had shared a doc with him for “advertising opportunities”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli studied the rate card. It seemed low, especially for this company. This was a household name - unlike the ball-shavers and “low T” supplements that comprised a majority of the first month of his production.  And the “clunk” his Outback’s drivetrain made when shifting at speed wasn’t going to fix itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pasted the template into the response, first doubling the price. Then he remembered Huey, Dee, and Louis from school.  Eli hesitated for a moment, backspaced, and then tripled what he had started with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would that be enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“WINNERS NEVER WAIT! GO BIG OR GO HOME.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The universe had decided then. Eli hit send.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining triage was tough sledding. For every legitimate potential sponsor or cross-promotion opportunity, there were dozens of messages from the show’s “fans”. They asked for customized line-up advice. Complaints about bets gone bust. Even one full-on prayer request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there was the one from someone claiming they lost their car payment because they took the wrong side when Lance shouted, “LOCK IT IN.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli had to set the laptop aside after that last one. Marci had long ago left to ready herself for bed. Eli returned to the game, hoping for a distraction. But, in the slog, it was clear that even the broadcast team was struggling for angles to keep the audience engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a night both teams would rather forget. Then again, nobody cares about who wins - only who covers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli was about to turn the TV off when the color commentator mentioned the Ali Dettmer trade, and threw to the sideline reporter for an “update”. Eli scrambled for the remote and, then, turned the volume up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-when asked what inspired the Dettmer trade, Raiders’ General Manager, Spencer Rourke remained vague, almost coy, alluding to the idea being ‘in the air’. Well, after some digging, we tracked the idea back to the source; a little online show streaming twice a week out of the midwest. And you won’t believe the name, guys.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli’s stomach dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right, as best we can tell, Wednesday’s blockbuster trade was inspired by a podcast named &lt;em&gt;Bet Ballers&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys in the booth both chuckled, ruefully, as if they both knew the punchline to a dirty joke that couldn’t be said out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; it would be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What a world, partner. Boys will be boys - am I right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made no sense. The “story” had been made up, and now they were covering it on national television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that important?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli blinked and looked up. Marci stood in the bedroom’s door frame, holding her toothbrush. She pointed to his phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli hadn’t noticed it vibrating. He flipped it over. It was a group text with Ty and Lance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DDUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUUDDDDDDDDDEESSSSSSSSSSSSS”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact nuance was difficult to follow, but it was clear that Ty and Lance had seen the sideline report, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laptop dinged. Eli pulled it back toward him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a new email - from the potential sponsor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How soon can we sign?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli was shocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But not as shocked as he was by the email that arrived the next day&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/06/MoneyballerAmericana-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/06/MoneyballerAmericana-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Moneyballer Americana - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Moneyballer Americana&lt;/strong&gt; is a seven-part novelette about a struggling bluegrass musician who accidentally ignites a sports-betting media frenzy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Come back each day for the next installment. When all seven parts are published, they’ll be compiled into a single downloadable version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - Encroachment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Monday, Eli was subbing for Mr. Hendrickson, the middle school’s history teacher. Huey, Dee, and Louis sat toward the back of the room during their home base hour. Supposedly, they were to catch up on their overdue assignments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that was easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I see you’re currently covering World War 2 - the German invasion of the Soviet Union? Operation Barbarossa?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trio looked at each other, doing some kind of telepathic risk assessment between themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess so?” Louis ventured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK! So where do we start?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” Louis said, “Germany decided to attack the Soviets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure.” Eli looked expectantly at the others. “What else?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huey had given up any pretense of participating in the conversation and had retreated to his phone almost immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What happened next?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Dee shrugged, Eli went to where the draw strings for a variety of maps mounted to the ceiling. Finding one for WW2’s European theater, he tugged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Until 1941, if I remember, Germany had looked unstoppable.” Eli picked up the pointer and circled areas as he spoke, “They had easily steamrolled Poland, France, and much of the Scandinavian Peninsula.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A phone chirped&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli recognized the chime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three boys perked up instantly, like squirrels at the first screech of a red tail hawk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli sighed. “Guys, come on-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huey groaned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My four-leg just busted!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He showed his screen to the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dude, you still falling for those?” Dee said, slumping back in his chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The free bonuses are free for a reason!” Louis said. “For real, when have those ever paid?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli felt a chill. He sat in on Ty and Lance’s show enough to recognize this song. To date, whenever he monitored the live stream chat, Eli had always pictured college-aged or twenty-something men with more time and disposable income than sense. It hadn’t occurred to him that &lt;em&gt;Chuckles27&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PHATRICHARD&lt;/em&gt; might actually be the same kids he sees in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Ty talked strategy, he’d always joke about “broadening the demo[graphics], “ but this was ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli put down the pointer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your history lesson; let’s try this again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three boys looked at him, skeptically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, Operation Barbarossa. Imagine World War II Germany is about to place one massive bet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bet?” Louis looked skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, a bet. Nazi Germany’s success, to this point in the war, was largely about overwhelming their slower, less mobile opponents.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Blitzkrieg.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli pointed at Dee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dee looked embarrassed as the other two regarded him with surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What? I play video games.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, so Germany knows that’s there’s tons of useful resources in we now call eastern Europe. They also had gotten a taste of winning; they wanted to chase it while they had a hot hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You said there was a bet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A big one. To conquer Europe and have a chance at the world,” Eli paused, making sure he was getting the terminology right, “Germany was, essentially, betting they would win a multi-leg parlay.”
Huey looked up from ruminating on his phone, suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;What kind of parlay?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli hesitated. “A… big one?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uncapped a marker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t matter.” He started making bullet points on the white-board. “What does matter are the different events, or &lt;em&gt;legs&lt;/em&gt;, of their bet that all needed to break in their favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Leg one, Germany needed to advance &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;, to outrun any sizable counter-attack.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started a second point. “They needed undisrupted supply lines, despite stretching further and further into enemy territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They needed a late, or mild, winter - weather that wouldn’t ding either of the first two points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Finally, Germany needed demoralize the Soviets so much that reinforcements would never arrive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli underlined the points. “Germany needed ALL those legs to hit to win their parlay.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huey tilted his head. “So if one misses-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You lose the eastern front,” Dee answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cool.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not cool,” Eli corrected. “Cold. Lots of Operation Barbarossa soldiers &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; froze to death. The early, harsh winter rallied the Soviets. They stopped Germany before they could take Moscow. It was a huge move of the line, and the Soviets would later join the Allied Powers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boys sat silently for a moment, processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OK, but… if the Soviets were the underdogs, what were the odds?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli smiled, relieved. “At the time? Massive. Nobody thought they’d cover. But they did.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dee was scribbling in his notebook. “Can we use that? Like, the odds and stuff?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli was surprised by the question and it took him a second to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I- I don’t know if Mr. Hendrickson knows what a parlay is,” Eli laughed, “Just remember the bigger point: &lt;em&gt;don’t bet against the Russian winter&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They laughed - laughed! - and wrote it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli had gotten through. But why, &lt;em&gt;in God’s green earth&lt;/em&gt;, were middle-schoolers betting? Let alone during school hours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guys, let me ask you a question. You’ve got that app - but don’t you have to be 18 or something? Like to have an account?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just use my Dad’s account,” Dee said, “I see him on it all the time, and he uses the same password for everything. I don’t think he even notices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huey shrugged. “My older brother doesn’t have time while he’s at work, so I play during the day. If we hit, I get a cut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, and when was the last time &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; happened?” Louis teased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, I was THIS CLOSE to doubling my mowing money. Stupid steam move.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli had heard Ty rant about that - jumping on a popular bet right as it was turning sour. 
Dee and Louis exploded into laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No hedge,” Louis shook his head, “and you chased it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli sensed a line had been crossed. Huey grew angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, at least my &lt;em&gt;Mom&lt;/em&gt; didn’t &lt;em&gt;take my phone away because she had to cover my losses&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;again&lt;/strong&gt;!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoa,” Eli stepped forward, “Guys, guys, guys - easy. Relax.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took a breath and released it theatrically, palms up, making eye contact with each and encouraging them to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It sounds like you all have a lot of experience, and not a lot of good. So why do you keep doing it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They exchanged glances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because,” Louis said, “it’s - fun?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli looked at him in disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t win if you don’t play?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even if that were true, it sounds like there isn’t much winning happening, anyway.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An idea occurred to Eli. He went back to the white board and began erasing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Have you done probability in math yet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Math?” Huey was confused. “This is history home base.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were talking parlays, right? That’s probability. We still have ten minutes. Go with me on this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli drew four boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Say we have a four leg parlay. We want to see if we can get four heads on a coin flip in a row.” Eli pointed at the first box. “What are the odds of getting a heads on the first flip?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“50%?” Dee said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Assuming its a fair flip, yes, you have a 50% chance. What are the odds of getting a heads on the 2nd flip?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louis squinted, thinking. “It would still be 50%, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes!” Eli said, getting excited, “and it would be 50% for the third and the fourth flip, too. So what are the odds of us winning the parlay?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If everything else is 50%, then this would be 50%, right?” Huey guessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You might think that,” Eli said, returning to the board, “but we actually need to &lt;em&gt;multiply&lt;/em&gt; the percentage of each event happening &lt;em&gt;with every other event’s percentage&lt;/em&gt;. Taking the first two values, 50% times 50% is 0.25, or 25%. &lt;em&gt;It goes down&lt;/em&gt;. If we continue to multiply all legs, we get-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dee read from his phone’s calculator, “Zero-point-zero-six-two-five, or 6.25%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli capped the marker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So we could expect that four-leg parlay in this example to pay out a little more than 6% of the time, or only 1 out of 16 times. And just because you might have lost the previous fifteen times does not mean you’re due on the 16th play. You still have-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-a 6.25% chance of winning the next parlay,” Louis finished. “Huh.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to bring this home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And that is only a four-leg parlay with each leg having a 50% chance of happening. I bet - I mean, I &lt;em&gt;suspect&lt;/em&gt; - that if we looked, the odds for the events happening in these offers is far, far below 50%. I mean, we pretty quickly get into ‘struck by lightning’ probability without trying too hard. &lt;em&gt;Think about that&lt;/em&gt; - how many people do you know that have been struck by lightning?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trio again looked at each other. There seemed to be a dawning realization. Maybe he taught them something valuable today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’re saying boosted odds are always bad?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like the Nazi’s chances of taking Moscow in November.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/05/MoneyballerAmericana-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/05/MoneyballerAmericana-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Moneyballer Americana - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Moneyballer Americana&lt;/strong&gt; is a seven-part novelette about a struggling bluegrass musician who accidentally ignites a sports-betting media frenzy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Come back each day for the next installment. When all seven parts are published, they’ll be compiled into a single downloadable version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - False Start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the opening segments were anything to go by, this episode would be as many air raid sirens as fart sound effects. Eli wrote down the time stamp. He’d need to check if the audio clipped, maybe compress and normalize, before posting clips to the socials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sensed an ad read and tapped a few keys, triggering the queued promotional overlay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Real quick, bros, I gotta give a shoutout to our newest sponsor, Gameset AI. Gameset is the revolutionary sports-prediction engine you need to take your winnings to the next level. Trained on every game since 2000, Gameset lets you bet like the pros!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been using it and, let me tell you, it’s scary good. Plug-in your match-up and Gameset will provide you Degenerates with their patent pending insights.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Use our exclusive, VIP code, #BetBallers, and &lt;em&gt;get your first month free&lt;/em&gt;!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s like having us giving you personalized advice - for only the price of a couple pizzas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do it right and you’ll cover those pizzas in no time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No doubt! No doubt. Use our code - #BetBallers - on registration and start winning today!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli sat off stage in the converted garage studio and a battered folding chair that had seen better days. On his lap was his old laptop, called into service to run the livestream’s admin account. It was balanced as precariously as his finances, if he was being honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a few episodes since Eli got the Bet Ballers “producer” job. Sports, let alone sports betting, wasn’t his scene and these weren’t his people. He could list least a half-dozen area middle schools with bad reputations he’d rather sub at. However, the money had surprisingly good for what was a pretty straight forward job; running the board at some local churches had been more challenging, by comparison. And it had been steady - something that his bluegrass band, at the moment - was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His Outback, and its growing list of worrisome noises, wasn’t going to fix itself. Subbing wasn’t steady enough to repairing his credit deficiency disorder. So every Tuesday and Thursday afternoon he was here, in the “Bet Baller Media Worldwide Headquarters, LLC”, policing diatribes between such chat room luminaries such as &lt;em&gt;JockstrapJestor&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BallerBoy06&lt;/em&gt;. And pretend he understood what hosts Ty and Lance were talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look, they aren’t paying me to say this,” Ty said, looking directly into the camera, “but last week their model was dead on. When the public was heavy on Seattle, as the favorite, the sharp money saw Gameset +7. Sharp players faded the square action, and basically were printing value.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s simple math,” Lance riffed, confidently. “You can either normalize momentum, adjust for weather, and regress touchdown variance, or let Gameset do it for you. You don’t even need to watch the game!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For real, for real. But what we do want to watch? J-E-T-S! Jets! Jets! Jets!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dude, you are so right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli guessed Ty was in his 30’s. He had that aging college jock look. At least once an episode, Ty would name-check the nearby division II school where he played linebacker (“Go fightin’ Cards!”) Sometimes it was to justify his take, other times it was to establish pecking order. Eli just assumed Ty’s current real estate gig must be pretty boring by comparison if he kept going to the 15-year-old well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OH YEAH. Can you say &lt;em&gt;quarterback drama&lt;/em&gt;!?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His co-host, Lance Nowak, punctuated his question with a practiced swig of the sponsor’s energy drink, label out. While Tyler could still pull off a quarter zip, Lance’s fit was more athletic cosplay. And watches so bulky their primary purpose was to be seen more by others than looked at by the wearer. Lance was adamant he was the “numbers guy”. As Eli observed in the ensuing weeks, this meant defending your own stats to the death, while deriding anyone else’s as “nerd shit”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you see Sunday night’s game!?” Ty was now addressing Lance, “My man, Ali Dettmer &lt;em&gt;once again&lt;/em&gt; had a &lt;em&gt;killer&lt;/em&gt; game in his third week in relief of franchise hero, Joe Jonson.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Two-hundred twenty four yards with two touchdowns through the air,” Lance read off his phone, “and another 86 yards and a walk-in touchdown with his feet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chat was starting to come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s embarrassing. I’m embarrassed for them. The Jets have an embarrassment of riches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nobody had backup journeyman Dettmer odds on favorite for their comeback player-of-the-year, that’s for sure. But with Jonson set to come back from turf toe, and the trade deadline nearing, you think the Jets should continue to ride the hot hand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you kidding? The Jets are sitting on a gold mine.” Ty spammed several party air horn honks in a row to emphasize his point. “You think the Jets front office isn’t already fielding offers?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Better question,” Lance countered, “Is what happens to the line?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lines. Spreads. Overs. It felt like running the sound board in church where everyone was speaking in tongues. Eli was trying to keep up with the chat, which was a challenge. It was always a froth of unfamiliar terms and locker room innuendo. But when they sensed a incoming prediction, it was like chum in the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Spill it! Gonna play or gonna lay!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“what’s the move???”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“got a hundo for a line grap. Gimmie gimmie.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more polished presentation would have a picture of the player overlayed on screen. Eli opened up a new browser tab window and searched for “Ali Dettmer” to find something to insert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With Ali’s mobility,” Ty continued, “he could come in and be productive for a new team on &lt;em&gt;day one&lt;/em&gt;. Forget learning the playbook. He’s a scrambler. Run some simple option plays that’ll set up the play action and you’re in business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Instant offense wherever he goes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few offseason stories speculating about Dettmer joining the Raiders. Eli liked the hero image on one story. The site had clearly mocked-up a different picture so that it looked like Dettmer was wearing a Raider’s jersey. The player, eyes wide, was hurdling over the head of a defender who missed low. It was all dynamic motion and would look great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like he had done several times previously, Eli flipped the laptop around and pointed to the screen. Eli would catch Ty’s eye, he’d subtly indicate to whether to include the image or find something else, and then Eli would act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, today Ty wasn’t so subtle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“BRO. BRO! RAIDERS ARE MAKING A PLAY.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli shook his head. “No, that’s not-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s huge! Degenerates, that’s HUGE. That’s going to move.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty triggered the air raid siren. “EXCLUSIVE BREAKING NEWS ON THE BET BALLERS PODCAST - Ali Dettmer is going to the Raiders!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“LOCK! IT! IN!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli looked studied the screen in shock. Checking twice, he confirmed that this was, indeed, an article from pre-season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“HAMMER RAIDERS +7”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“OMG OMG OMG”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“LINE MOVING!!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“PUT 1000 ON IT LFG”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been saying this for WEEKS. Weeks, people.” Ty pumped his fists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time since starting a month ago Eli had heard about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A chance to take the house like this is once in a blue moon opportunity. Smash those lines and then tell your friends you heard it here first!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty pointed at the camera, “We are plugged in and here for you! When you get your jackpot, make sure you like, subscribe, and draw an unsportsman-like conduct penalty on that alert button!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And don’t forget to join our exclusive Discord! For subscribers only, we go even harder with the kinds of advice and insight &lt;em&gt;those Vegas insiders&lt;/em&gt; won’t let us say on stream.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know we’re going deep on this Dettmer news. Subscribe now so you don’t miss out!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hosts were on wind-down auto-pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And be back Thursday, when we break it wide open.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was Eli’s cue. He cut the mikes and cut over to play the final sponsor clip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty and Lance hopped up and chest-bumped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dude,” Ty said, turning to Eli, “That was amazing! That was the shot in the arm this show needed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli was thoroughly confused. “But it’s not actually happening. That was an old article.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But it’s too good not to be right, right?” Ty navigated the narrow space around the desk. “I mean, if it makes sense to enough people, it becomes real. It’s like wisdom of the crowds, like that book, &lt;em&gt;The Secret&lt;/em&gt;-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-that’s not-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DUDE!” Lance furiously flipped between apps on his phone. “We seriously just moved a line. Totally. We’re gonna see it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty high-fived Lance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But-“ Eli was still missing something, “-but it’s not real.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ya know,” Lance said, still scrolling, “when the universe makes a connection like that, you just go for it, you know? Trust your gut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Engagement makes it real. And if doesn’t happen,” Ty squinted, trying to read over Lance’s shoulder, “We just say we got some bad information or whatever.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nobody remembers when you’re wrong. But call your shot and have it work out? That’s what legends are made of.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was an &lt;em&gt;insane&lt;/em&gt; connection, but so obvious. What are the degenerates saying?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli refreshed the chat window. The messages were flying by so quickly, they were hard to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“just put $200 on the Raiders”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Free money boyz”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“rent inda bag”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty watched the comments scroll. “This. Is. Awesome.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We got a runner.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message about the rent caught Eli’s eye and he chuckled nervously. “Are they… talking real money?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ty and Lance looked at each other, and then exploded into a fit of laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli put the extra mic cables and his laptop bag in the passenger seat of his Outback. He was parked on the curb outside the cookie-cutter split level where they recorded the show. The lackluster effort at clearing the recent snow left the sidewalk icy and treacherous. Eli gingerly circled around the front of the wagon, the crunch of his steps reverberating across the cul-de-sac. He exhaled, as though he had been holding his breath this entire time, and took in the suburb. Yesterday’s pristine, white blanket had become today’s rutted, frozen mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eli climbed in and turned the ignition. The check-engine light was still on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/04/MoneyballerAmericana-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2026/01/04/MoneyballerAmericana-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 05</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy this one, or at least use it to justify a different path. This is the fifth and final scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;download a collected version of all five parts and get a bit of background from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 5 - Superstorm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The superstorm began long before social media, before radio, before the first stories flickered against cave walls. There was no narrative, no protagonist seeking revenge, no monster with intent. Only heat rising from water, vapor becoming cloud, air feeding on air until motion became inevitable - natural interactions as old as the planet itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For centuries the Gulf had warmed, each year storing energy, releasing it in fits, then resetting to a new normal a degree closer to ruin. The atmosphere - an ocean we live at the bottom of - moved according to laws more ancient than our knowing. Where it brushed the sea, a spiral began. From orbit, it thickened: a white convulsion swelling to blot the curve of the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satellites recorded the pressure drop, numbers slipping past precedent, but the data could no longer describe what existed below. The language of measurement broke first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hurricane isn’t angry. It has no morality. No justice. It cannot be reasoned with. It doesn’t care about followers or forecasts. It simply is - vast, unalive, consuming without hunger - simple systems combining into incomprehensible design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the wind arrived, and the sky was erased. Color fled. Horizon dissolved. Roofs peeled like fruit skin, walls bowed, towers folded. Everything moved; nowhere remained. Roads liquefied into canals. Water and sky became one continuous violence, their boundary only the white teeth of the gusts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For twenty hours - though time had lost meaning - the storm held one unbroken note. Reality, as we comprehend it, wavered. Rain didn’t fall; it traveled sideways, carving trenches without reason, driving rivers from their beds into madness. Seawalls fell. Houses lifted and vanished. The ocean climbed stairs, found ceilings, pried walls apart. Yachts, shrimp boats, even freight containers skipped inland like stones and lay still, marooned of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From above, an eye that was not an eye opened: twenty-five miles wide, a perfect geometry, a stillness that could not last. Then the opposite wall made landfall, and the impossible resumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By morning, the Archipelago was a smear of mud and debris. The precise geometry of grids and cul-de-sacs erased. Canals redrawn by surge and silt. Mangroves, cordgrass, and pink houses - gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sea did not notice. It was beyond such negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, the Louisiana Branch of the Bureau of Truth issued a priority statement: 
	&lt;em&gt;“The Florida Archipelago Demonstrates Resilience After Historic Weather Anomaly - A Clean Slate for Growth.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alethia tagged it, “&lt;strong&gt;Highly shareable&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/21/HurricaneDavid-05</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/21/HurricaneDavid-05</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 04</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy this one, or at least use it to justify a different path. This is the fourth scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;download a collected version of all five parts and get a bit of background from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 4 - Calm is Contagious&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t so much a blue sky as a blue &lt;em&gt;dome&lt;/em&gt;, trapping the sun and moisture alike to unbearable degree. It was a brilliant sapphire color that couldn’t be looked directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dome didn’t allow for a single gust of relief. The air couldn’t get a breath in under all the intensity. The mangroves sagged under their own weight, their leaves glued together. Further up, a heron stood in the shallows, motionless as a lawn ornament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only ripple on the canal’s surface was from the autonomous drone, now making its way toward David with machine precision. David bent over the bodega boat and waved his ID in the air, vaguely over what looked like where its electronics might be housed. The drone, bobbing gently in the canal, beeped an affirmation and the lid slid back, exposing David’s order, doubled-bagged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package was warm to the touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat’s lid closed and the craft gracefully pivoted in the water, re-orienting itself toward the open end of the inlet before picking up speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the water higher? He couldn’t be sure; David was still getting used to the waterfront here. It was probably just the tides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked around him. As best as David could tell, he and the drone were the only moving things in the entire development. He exhaled in frustration. The entire damn region was in hysterics. He had watched, forlornly, as several of his neighbors boarded up their windows and fled before he could properly introduce himself. He’d have to have a conversation about the dangers of disinformation and the resulting panic cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d role-played a half dozen Bureau storm drills &lt;em&gt;this week alone&lt;/em&gt;. This “event” was trending strongly to just another coastal evacuation hype cycles; a bunch of data spikes that would be smoothed out in the following days as cooler heads prevailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David was surprised to vividly remember the last time he saw his mother. He was suddenly a teen again, watching her leave with other volunteers to shore up a sandbag levee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s watch chirped, pulling him from the memory. He’d configured Alethia to provide regular confidence level updates. Checking his wrist, he saw the probability for a positive outcome it was still holding above 50%; not great, but still no reason for panic, either. 
He turned and retraced his path to his new house. It was a small, but tidy, single-story coastal contemporary. Best of all, it was right along the water, like he had always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door unlocked satisfyingly as he approached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside, he kicked off his sandals by the door and crossed the terrazzo floor to the kitchen. After the Satan’s snow globe outside, the cool tile of the kitchen on his feet was heavenly. There were a couple items already on the island; the owner papers for achieving 100% vestment, with “Congratulations on achieving coastal residency!” headlining the stack. There was a new company credit card with its documentation. The welcome pack even had a ‘CALM IS CONTAGIOUS’ mug like the ones they had at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pushed those aside to make room for the takeout on his countertop. The bag’s crinkle echoed unsatisfactorily across unfurnished space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David leaned over the island. Taking in the empty expanse, he found it wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“House,” he said, addressing the room, “Call Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house acknowledged. The call rang once, twice, and then the sound of wind answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Go for Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Declan, dude! Would you believe it? I’m calling from my own house! You should come over. What does your night look like?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a pause on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No bueneo” Declan finally answered, “I’m headed upstate.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Upstate!? What’d you have going on with those panhandlers?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; know about the storm, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You bailed? Seriously? Over what, a little rain? I thought you were smarter than that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David, they’re saying this one is a Cat 5. Maybe bigger. Surge estimates are off the charts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cat 5? We don’t use those terms anymore. That’s sensationalist language. I see all the streams, I was cross-correlating expert sentiment just yesterday. It’s an over-reaction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The charts-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whose charts?! We make the charts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Listen, we’re seeing a high probability of the inner eyewall weakening and collapsing before it gets anywhere near shore. There’s no way. &lt;em&gt;There’s just no way&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was silence on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And don’t even get me started about how inaccurate we’ve seen the tracking models.” 
Another pause. The house did its best to filter out the sound of wind on the other end, but pops and hisses still peppered the other side of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“David, you should consider getting out, man, while you still can. I’ll see you when I see you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The house confirmed the dropped connection in its neutral tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bah!” David exclaimed, rubbing the back of his head in frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David grabbed a beer from the fridge, snatched the bag of food off the counter, and stormed out the rear sliding doors. On the back patio he scanned the horizon. It was empty. Not even a container ship in sight. Just a few wispy, delicate streaks of white where the edge of the world met the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He checked his watch. No change. Still above 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David toasted the sky, and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 4 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/21/HurricaneDavid-05&quot;&gt;Check here for the final installment of Hurricane David&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/20/HurricaneDavid-04</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/20/HurricaneDavid-04</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 03</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy this one, or at least use it to justify a different path. This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;download a collected version of all five parts and get a bit of background from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 3 - Vindication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analyst break-room coffee wasn’t better, but it came with a perk: instead of cardboard cups, they had real mugs, stamped with the Bureau’s slogan, &lt;em&gt;CALM IS CONTAGIOUS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam curled from David’s mug as he climbed the stadium seating of the command room - a college lecture hall as if it were built by defense contractors. The lighting was dim. The space was almost entirely lit by the floor-to-ceiling monitors comprising the front wall. It pulsed with blues and reds, trending terms, sentiment analysis broken out by geography, ideology, education, and any of two dozen more demographics summarized in pixel form; the sum total of the world’s anxiety abbreviated as light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the command center was quiet - the hum of the HVAC indistinguishable from whatever fan noise came from the dozens of computers in the room, the whir occasionally punctuated by flurries of keyboard assaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no assigned seats,technically, but people are creatures of habit. Maya was already at her usual spot, along the left edge and about half way to the top. She was staring intently at her space’s screen, tapping aggressively - summoning forth modals and then, summarily, dismissing them with a flick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David slid into the empty seat next to hers, its screen waking when it detected activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Miss me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya only grunted an acknowledgment, still pursuing something he couldn’t see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tilted his head toward the front wall. “How’s our girl today?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked up in irritation. “She’s being a drama queen. It’s been yellow alerts non-stop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as he logged in, an alert covered David’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The f-.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-see? It’s been like this since I started my shift at 5am. It’s got all the signs of an economic rumor cascade.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gulf side?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh. Home-grown and running hot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hmmm.” David skimmed the included detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was a seawall-crack shock clip. I cross-checked the footage. It is legit; it’s not doctored. The actual impact, though, is pretty slight. There is flooding in the lower 37th zone, but it’s contained; a localized, not systemic, failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But it looks bad, and the clip is breaking containment. It’s that time of year - old axes out again. Alethia keeps readjusting feed weights and dropping chaff. She’s managed to keep it off trending lists so far, but it’s starting to go viral on its own merits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sentiment acceleration?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look who’s been reading their manual! But yeah, could be big. People love any reason to short archipelago real estate for a quick buck. Hashtags are &lt;em&gt;#floridaFail, #sunkenAssets&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;#waterSoWet&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of what Maya was saying was huge. If the Archipelago looked unstable, insurers would re-price everything by the next morning. Markets would collapse. Panic had bankrupted just as many banks as storms did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, is there someone on the seawall video?” Alethia’s algorithm must have tripped over some threshold and started recruiting additional analysts for help. José, down in front, was scanning around the room for confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Over here-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got it,” David cut in, “Maya and I are tag-teaming it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked at David, skeptically. “You sure about that, rookie? Confidence index is at 62.5% and falling. We’ll have a sell-off on anything under 50%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked. “What, you scared?” He turned back to his screen and began launching his script agents; some boilerplate, others requiring brief field entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya weighed her options, then mockingly crossed herself and addressed José, who was still waiting for confirmation. “Override. I guess we got it. We’ll rope you in if we need it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turned back to David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d started ID’ing mouthpieces for a credibility challenge. Not a whole lot of influencers active at this hour, but we’ve got a handful of puppets that might apply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s fingers were now flying. “Is the source dirty?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like I said, bona fides look clean. But something always turns up, if we dig long enough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do we have time for that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Probably not. There is the usual terms and conditions take down. Something, something public safety. Quick and clean-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-T&amp;amp;Cs are too blunt. Looks like a cover-up. The Streisand effect is the opposite of what we want.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chyron scrolling across the bottom of David’s screen turned red. A neutral voice addressed the room. “Confidence index is below 60%.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoa, easy, girl.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the play here, rookie?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gathered his thoughts for a moment before speaking. He suddenly brightened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can use this, flip it.” David launched a volley of keystrokes, triggering an equal number of new dialogs. “It’s all about perception.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya made a prune face and leaned over to follow along on his screen. “Come again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So right now it is an infrastructure-fail that is playing.” David dismissed a few of the topmost related posts referencing the video, then pointed to the next in the queue, tapping through as Alethia sorted in real-time. “We’ve got climate aura farmers, government trolls, Florida haters… “ he rapidly swiped several more items in the carousel, “… a few members of Cirque du Soleil, for some reason-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rookie!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How often do they inspect the seawalls?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can find out. Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We reframe this footage captured of a maintenance test, or a drill. Something deliberate to test disaster response. Proof that the green plan of mangroves and cordgrass work as expected.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll need to dummy and backdate some work tickets.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shouldn’t be. Alethia has access those county systems.” Maya started typing. “And the flooding?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Localized, right? We spin it as an unexpected byproduct. Cracking eggs to make an omelet. Invaluable real-world insights that will be used to refine and upgrade the entire system performance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya returned to her terminal and ran a probability forecast; the trend line stabilized, but not high enough. David, watching over her shoulder, leaned in and tweaked demographic and geopolitical targeting sliders by hand. The projections wavered a moment, then orange coded labels bled to yellow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya leaned back and crossed her arms. David looked at her expectantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From behind them, Jeter said, “That’s not bad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nearly jumped out of his seat. During his color-coding, he hadn’t heard Jeter approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The seawall leak, I presume?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forming an approach,” Maya answered, “We’re about to execute.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Run it back for me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya looked expectantly at David and David cleared his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We supercharge the spread.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter’s eyebrow twitched. “Unconventional.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We frame it as proof of diligence - routine testing, proactive governance. Push hashtags like ‘StressTestSuccess’, or ‘MakingSafeHappen’ and run with whatever pops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter grunted affirmatively. “Shift the sentiment from panic to civic pride?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Exactly! Like ‘Look at our proactive resilience’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya joined in. “It’s too cute, by a lot. Those tags need a pass or ten through sentiment refactoring. But it might work. The types that might otherwise spread it will back off; they won’t want to seem pro-gov. And it will be like catnip for those looking to clown on the climate types.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We bait a positive spin. It’ll be chum in the water.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeter stroked his beard for a moment before speaking. “Alethia: projection?”
The manifested voice localized between the three of them. “Projected confidence recovery is 67 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Do it. Nobody leaves until we’re back over 65%. The markets don’t dip when they open tomorrow.” Jeter took in the rest of the room for a moment. Finding nothing else amiss, he told David good job before ambling back to the crows nest at the rear of the room.
David beamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey! We’re not out of the woods yet, &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt;.” Maya chided, pushing his coffee toward him. “We’ve got a long day of cleanup ahead of us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 3 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/20/HurricaneDavid-04&quot;&gt;Check here for the next installment of Hurricane David&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 02</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enjoy this one, or at least use it to justify a different path. This is the second scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;download a collected version of all five parts and get a bit of background from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 2 - Party On&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, David zipped down the marina ramp on an electric ride-share scooter. He was late for Declan’s party. Work had run over, and he was now having trouble finding the right mooring among the other stationary vessels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was uncomfortably muggy, per usual for Florida’s late summer. The afternoon didn’t have the courtesy of cooling things off, so David was stuck trying to keep sweat out of his squinting eyes as he scanned for landmarks. This close to the ocean, he could taste the salt at the back of his throat, and smell a faint trace of mildew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after more than few embarrassing dead ends, David caught signal and found his way to the sleek two-story white box on pontoons. It glowed at the end of the dock, LED light strings casting colorful reflections in the canal water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As David approached, music, punctuated by laughter and whoops, could be heard. And there was Declan, lounging at the end of the gangway. He was with a couple of hangers-on David recognized from previous parties. They sat on either side of the walkway, drinking beers from a cooler between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan waved and swung a sockless loafer over the barrier from where he had been straddling the rail. His tanned skin gleamed from days spent pretending to sail. He met David with mock disapproval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s Mr. 9-to-5! Bout time! I was starting to think the Bureau had revoked your public privileges.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never!” David tugged at where his shirt stuck to his back, and readjusted his fit.  “Would’ve been here sooner, but work’s been crazy. You know how it is when the Midwest thinks they have a bit of heat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan handed David a beer, “Ah, the joy of keeping the Karens calm. So chivalrous!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David gratefully accepted the drink. The condensation had been almost instantaneous, making it slick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well,” Declan grandly gestured, “What do you think of &lt;em&gt;me casa&lt;/em&gt;? Isn’t she a ‘beaut?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David ran his eyes over the entirety of the illuminated craft, all 65-feet of pulsating brightness; a stark contrast to the fading twilight all around them. “I dunno, man. You couldn’t have bought something &lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bought?” One of the others laughed. “Hell no. Declan doesn’t buy shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a lease,” Declan clarified. “Ownership’s a liability, man. Shows up on the balance sheets-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“-and lawsuits-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan swatted the air, as if he was waving away something unpleasant. “I suppose that’s true, too. But like I was trying to say, real wealth is leverage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other two in Declan’s orbit chuckled. David nodded, taking a mental note to try and work out what they meant later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, bureau boy, come aboard. I’ll show you around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan and David crossed the gangway. On board, the crowd was Declan’s usual mix of high and low-brow, a clashing of class and culture. He seemed to do that on purpose; the greater degree of friction, the greater likelihood of free entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They slowly circulated, Declan making introductions or issuing orders to the handful of wait staff. As the night began to envelop them, the hot air seemed to grow heavier, more oppressive. Somewhere, on the horizon, there was a distant flicker of lightning; a late attempt at relief. But nobody seemed to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They climbed the ladder to the second floor, past the DJ and the makeshift bar. That’s when David noticed a woman by herself toward the stern, set apart in white against the railing. She didn’t look like Declan’s usuals. There were no designer logos, no gaudy influencer techwear; just a simple light cotton summer dress gently animated in what little breeze came off the water. Poised, but not performative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who is &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan turned and looked, his eyes taking a minute to adjust. He then laughed with recognition. “The granola? That’s Lucía, my second cousin. Mom thought I should invite her since she’s home between tours. ‘We’re family’, and all that.”
“Tours?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“‘Food Without Borders’ or something. Some kind of disaster recovery non-profit. Feed the poor, film the pity reels, make everyone else feel guilty for still drinking imported rum. All moral compass, pointing nowhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declan looked back at David, who was still staring. “Ahhhh, nah-uh. Not your league, dude. Not even the same game.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh-huh.” The challenge was made. David reached over and grabbed a pair of bottles from the bar. “I think I’ll go over and introduce myself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your funeral.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David winked and sauntered his way as casually as possible to the back of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía leaned on the railing, thick curls pulled into a loose bunch atop her head. She seemed to be intently looking at something while scrolling on her mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked up at his approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nodded and gestured to her device. “Something important?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing that can’t be handled by people on-site,” Lucía said, powering off the screen. “I’m doing a poor job of taking &lt;em&gt;a break&lt;/em&gt;, I suppose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Same. Except my boss calls it ‘field listening’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía seemed to smile, despite herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cold one?” David offered one of the beers. “I’m David, a friend of Declan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thanks, David. I think I will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David handed her a bottle and took a spot next to her. He studied her as she twisted off the top and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Declan mentioned you do relief work? Is that, like, internationally?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I run field ops, sometimes overseas. But, lately, that has been a lot more stateside than most people realize.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cool. Where were you at last?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía turned to look out across the water, somewhere in the darkness. She took another drink, giving her response a moment to collect. “Tennessee to Ohio and back. The new tornado alley. Lots of towns there that don’t exist anymore, except on maps.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh wow,” David said. “But fresh starts for the people there, though, right? Silver linings?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From somewhere across the water, there was a clap of thunder loud enough to be heard  over the DJ’s bass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía gave David a quizzical look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not really. Mostly grief.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I just mean,” David picked at the edge of the bottle’s label, “that kind of thing can be a reset. People are freed up to move somewhere else, somewhere safer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line was smothered in damp silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David pivoted. “I think I remember some of what you’re talking about, though. Lots of pull-yourself-up-by-your-bootstraps stories the past couple months came outta that area.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was flash of lightening, illuminating the clouds building over the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That is certainly one take. What is it that you do, David?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He leaned in conspiratorially, “I’m with the Bureau.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bureau?” Lucía’s brow furrowed. “As in Bureau of Truth?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whoop rose near the DJ; someone popped a cork. The bass started again, with renewed vigor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Is that a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened. “Not for me. I’ll sleep fine tonight. I can’t speak for you, though.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey - come on. It’s not so bad. In fact, you could say we do the same work-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía cut in, “Feeding people and filtering them aren’t the same.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She took a sip while staring right &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David tried to laugh it off. “We &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; help people. You-“ he said, gestured vaguely, “do what you do. We keep people from stampeding every time it rains.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s one way to describe propaganda.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David laughed. “Look, if we hit the siren every time the radar twitches, then shelves empty, freeways jam… I’ve seen it. Sometimes the calmest thing is… not shouting.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She scoffed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t argue that there’s lots of people, here and overseas, looking to capitalize on driving people apart. Disasters-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía tried to interject, but David kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”-&lt;em&gt;Disasters&lt;/em&gt; are primed to be piled on and exploited. &lt;strong&gt;Somebody&lt;/strong&gt; has to have their hand on the brake.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hand on the brake? Or across the lens?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another flash. The LED strings hiccuped. David reached for a response and found nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was in Lower Broadway, outside of Nashville, after the F4. The fuel we brought for the hospital generator ran out after 36 hours. We made call after call for help, only to be told that the ‘reported weather anomaly’ didn’t ‘qualify for disbursement’. We were accused of &lt;em&gt;running counter-Bureau narratives&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She exhaled, turning back to eye the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it was clear help wasn’t coming, we moved those who could be moved… but-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was thunder. She seemed to soften, slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David waited for the sound to fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s… a lot. You really carry it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s reality. Most don’t really get much of a choice.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía remembered her drink, considered it for a moment, and then set it on a nearby table. A sudden gust blew off the water, pushed to shore by the advancing storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You seem like a bright guy, David. Really. You could do anything. But you choose to tell fairy tales. And people are dying because of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucía straightened her dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m tired. I’m going to find my friends.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She brushed past him, her bare shoulder icy against his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around David, the music seemed to resume. The storm continued to build over the open water, closer now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David’s face felt flush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you, man,” Declan yelled over the crowd, his arm around some new acquaintance, “She’s not gonna go for no Bureau boy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David forced a smile back, then turned from the railing and back to reassess the party drinking deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Analyst&lt;/em&gt;, he thought. &lt;em&gt;A Bureau analyst. Let’s see her try to dismiss that&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 2 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/19/HurricaneDavid-03&quot;&gt;Check here for the next installment of Hurricane David&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hurricane David - 01</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When social media is increasingly used to create events, rather than report on them, I find that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;Hurricane David&lt;/strong&gt; is a corporate-gothic tech tragedy set in a near future Florida Archipelago. This post-truth fable traces the edges of where reality can be manufactured - and what happens when the natural order reasserts itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more on the story’s background, the companion soundtrack, and more &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the appropriate section on my Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/11/waterfront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A watercolor picture of a beach-facing waterfront property on on side of a palm-tree lined path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A thrush was feeding on a myrtle-tree and did not move from it because its berries were so delicious. A Fowler observed her staying so long in one spot, and having well bird-limed his reeds, caught her. The Thrush, being at the point of death, exclaimed, ‘O foolish creature that I am! For the sake of a little pleasant food I have deprived myself of my life.’”&lt;/em&gt; - “The Thrush and the Fowler”, Aesop’s Fables, trans. George Fyler Townsend (1887)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 1 - All Hands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Truth is a managed resource, and I am its steward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pledge to start the monthly all-hands droned through the atrium. It reminded David of the omnipresent air conditioning: steady, automatic, and operating at low-energy. The audience was already sneaking glances at whatever might be more of a dopamine draw before they were seated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agenda was the usual polite clapping for tenure milestones, process updates, and tepid pep-rally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…sentiment volatility down 12% year-over-year…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Truth’s Director of Narrative Alignment, over-slick and as passable as HR clip-art come to life, was speaking. Jeter performatively moved about the stage, hitting his marks like he was giving a TED talk. He was saying something about the de-amplification campaign done for the Midwestern heat dome. But you’d be hard pressed to tell this campaign from the half-dozen others running at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…localized anomalies successfully recontextualized as resilience narratives…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Maya, Chris, and David, seated toward the back, it couldn’t be more rote. Maya, who was already vested, must have endured dozens of these meetings. David tried to match her detached aloofness, her effortless indifference, and was failing horribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He flicked his smart watch. A chicklet blinked to life, replaced the idle screen. “94% vested” shone in bright letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six more points and the waterfront would be his. No more commute from inland, no more landlord, no more roommates. He would have his very own house in the Florida Archipelago. The daydream was so vivid he nearly missed the next part of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…and as we say goodbye to our team headed to the new, New Orleans office, we have some new roles available for the right kind of energetic, enthusiastic game changers…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David nudged Chris. “Wait, what’s happening?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris shrugged. “Sounds like some analyst positions are opening up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really? How quickly do they vest?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maya chewed her gum for a beat and regarded them with mock disdain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like it matters. They’d never let you sock puppet types anywhere near Alethia.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s not,” David said while leaning in and dramatically pausing, “what your mom said last night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris covered his mouth, squelching his sudden laugh into a coughing fit as best as he could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group drew Jeter’s glare. He paused for a second to make it clear he was looking their way, and then resumed his slide with slightly more volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before we break, I wanted to remind everyone that we’re entering our seasonal period of elevated rain triage. I know some of the old timers might have heard these referred to as ‘hurricanes’ or used the 1-5 scale of the Saffir-Simpson categories. Just remember, these are now considered terms of terror. Avoid using in your comms. If you have any questions, please consult the new intranet resource that we’ll link to in today’s recap email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remember, ‘Panic is not a public good -‘”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David, in unison with the rest of the assembled employees, replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Calm is contagious.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you, and let’s keep calm out there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Scene 1 - &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/11/18/HurricaneDavid-02&quot;&gt;Check here for the next installment of Hurricane David&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/11/17/HurricaneDavid-01</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Biggest Little Bill - 05</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve spent years writing about the intersection of technology, culture, and policy. When concepts like megawatt and megabyte are reshaping the very places we live, I’m finding that work increasingly relevant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is one thing to write an essay here or a newsletter there. Given the potential harms, utilizing adding additional forms, like narrative, seems warranted. &lt;strong&gt;The Biggest Little Bill&lt;/strong&gt; is part tech satire, part civic noir. It’s a reminder that accountability doesn’t just live in boardrooms or algorithms; like all things, it starts with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this one, and maybe see a bit of your own fight in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the third scene. If you missed the first, &lt;a href=&quot;/2025/10/27/BiggestLittleBill-01&quot;&gt;you can begin at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;. Or download a collected version of &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;all five parts from the Stories page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/10/biggestlittleheader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rocky, scrubby, sun-blasted hilltop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene 5 - Burn In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill unzipped his hoodie, which had served him well before dawn, and now would serve as a cushion. He spent PTO to take the morning off. When he got up, before the sun, there had been a chill in the air. But the temperature had been steadily rising since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap in the fence had been right where the bike girl had mentioned it. The walk down the bluff in the dark had been a bit treacherous; Bill didn’t want to use his phone to light his path for fear that it might give him away. There had been a few close calls, but he managed to make it without twisting an ankle (or worse).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill was surprised to find the drainage ditch, meant for storm water runoff, was wet. This, despite the fact that it had been at least a month since the area had any rain that amounted to anything. And, as Coeburn had mentioned, the area was still in a multi-year drought. In the growing light, he could see the slick discoloration, like this had been a regular occurrence for some time. It turned the concrete scar running parallel to the fence into a treacherous crossing - literally and figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had found a patch of scrub. It wasn’t the greatest cover, but it was better than any other alternative that he could see. And he waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first surprise happened well before 10am. There was a regular parade of light trucks starting their shift from 7 or 8, which was expected. What was a surprise was the large water tankers. Using his binoculars, Bill saw them being staged in a temporary area partially obscured by stacked shipping containers. Workers dragged hoses to and fro, coupling them to a row of valves along the data center’s flank. And it was &lt;em&gt;potable water&lt;/em&gt;, but from where were they siphoning drinking water from? When one truck finished, another would take its place - was this how they were attempting to bypass monitoring? It certainly didn’t meet any definition of “closed loop” Bill understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took pictures, noting the motor carriers and any USDOT numbers he could make out. That would be worth a follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second surprise was how the air seemed to intensify well in advance of the event. The data center always thrummed, 24-7, with a certain amount of unnatural, low-end wobble, a noise pollution that was felt, if not heard, for miles. But, in the last hour, there had been a noticeable increase in pitched whine, a grating screech that gave an unsettling, shrill accompaniment that only grew with the temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rumble intensified. Bill, through the binoculars, could see steam venting across the roof. The ground seemed to vibrate like a plucked wire. It was like the entire valley was trembling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This continued well after ten, the relentless cacophony setting his teeth on edge. But, as the humming, whirring, and crackling began to recede, there was a new sound. Bill heard it before he could see it - an rolling static, jets of white noise somewhere further up the drainage ditch. The water got louder and louder until he saw it splash around the bend, flying down the channel toward whatever watershed lied beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least he thought it was water. The speed made it hard to tell for sure, but it looked &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;. There was a pearlescent sheen on the top, as if there was oil in the mix. The chaotic release and sloshing was also causing a foamy scum on the edges. Leaning forward, on his hands and knees Bill could smell something faintly metallic or chemical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no way this was storm water - or that it should be dumped without treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was it! This was his proof!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’d analyzed numbers, filed reports, and attended hearings but he had never had a case so brazenly lie to his face before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grabbed his water bottle and hurriedly dumped the last of the contents on the thirsty ground beside his sweatshirt. Then, leaning out over the ditch, he reached down, taking care not to lose the bottle in the sudden rapids. A few seconds later, it was topped off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He carefully screwed the cap back on, and recorded some additional video with his phone. The water was beginning to slow but he had more than enough, in multiple ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then he heard the crunch of tires on gravel, above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He crabbed walked the few feet to his scrub-shielded camp. He made out a light truck parked beside his own. A second later, both doors opened. The driver, walked around the front. He looked like security, with gray monochrome from head to toe broken up only with a high-vis vest. He looked out, across the valley, at some point at the far end of the data center, while reaching for the handset clipped at his shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill couldn’t hear what was said. He still didn’t see the passenger. The driver circled the front of his vehicle and then stood looking at Bill’s license plate, for a moment, head arched to speak into his radio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’d know whose truck it was soon enough. And what if they did? Bill could feel his initial fear and embarrassment turning to anger. He had every right to be there! What were they even doing patrolling there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill slung his bag over his shoulder and started up the faint switchback. By the time he reached the top, a second security vehicle had arrived, pinning his Tacoma. The two original uniformed employees stood near the open window of this new vehicle, discussing something as Bill crested the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey there!” Bill said, a bit winded but determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three private security employees looked up, surprised. One - the driver of the first vehicle, Bill thought - was first to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, is this your vehicle?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure is. Is there a problem?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one to speak put his hands on his hips. “That’s private property. You can’t be down there. I’m gonna have to-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill interrupted the guard with his upheld hand. He put his bag on the hood of his truck, rifling for a second, and then produced his county government lanyard. He approached the trio, offering his badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m with the Washoe Planning Commission. As such, the entire community watershed, including the floodplain easement just over there,” Bill nodded below and to the west, “is my jurisdiction”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guards exchanged glances with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill recognized the hesitation - he’d seen it in a hundred zoning hearings - and pressed his advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You folks had quite the morning here, huh? Documented case of metering avoidance? Unauthorized discharge?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other standing guard, the one yet to speak, answered. “We’re an independent contractor. We just provide security. They don’t tell us what they’re doing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Uh, huh.” Bill put the lanyard around his neck. “Given what I just saw, you are looking at a half dozen regional and state environmental violations, not to mention your site covenants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two guards standing shifted, uncomfortably. The third, still in the second security vehicle, visibly stiffened in his seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you say you had nothing to do with this? Otherwise, I should probably get your names and any IDs for my report. Or - you’d probably make great collaborating witnesses if the state decides to launch an investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driver in the truck called the lead guard over and said something inaudible. Bill couldn’t make it out, but the pickup started and then slowly backed up and left the parking lot, leaving the original two guards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lead motioned for his junior to return to their own vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’d best move on, sir,” he said, the authority he spoke with before now gone. “It’s for your own safety. We don’t want to find you back here again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each guard carefully avoided eye contact as Bill watched them back out and drive further up the hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It crested the next rise and disappeared before Bill unlocked and got in his truck. He shut the door and exhaled - a massive, shuddering sigh. Outside, the valley continued to hum; inside, however, he could hear himself over it. His hands, draped on the wheel at ten and two were shaking, but he started to laugh. He whooped, punching the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After he got his breathing under control, he reached into his bag and retrieved the aluminum water bottle. Inside, he could feel the contents gently slosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill smiled. This was everything - not the proof itself, but the knowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And that’s a wrap! Thanks for reading The Biggest Little Bill. If you’d like a downloadable version with collects all five parts into a single PDF, &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/&quot;&gt;check out the ‘Stories’ page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2025/10/31/BiggestLittleBill-05</guid>
                
                <category>Culture</category>
                
                <category>Writing</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>