<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
    <description>This is the website for Matthew Reinbold (that's me!). I am the Director for API Platform Ecosystems and Digital Transformation for Postman. I also write the 'Net API Notes' email  newsletter and curate NetAPI.events. 
</description>
    <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:42:40 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:42:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Prompts Should Be In an OpenAPI Tempate?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last piece, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/30/TemplatesAsPrompts/&quot;&gt;I talked about the importance of not overlooking the behavioral influence of software templates&lt;/a&gt;. The conclusion was that our output is influenced by our tools whether we consciously are aware of it or not. Therefore, we &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; continue to trudge on in ignorance and wonder why things aren’t working out as intended. &lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt; we can design our environments to more easily achieve our governance outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An OpenAPI description has become the most common way to express RESTful and RESTish API designs. As a result, a wide variety of API tooling presents an OpenAPI default to a developer beginning a new design. Unfortunately, this default is usually a lowest-common-denominator, stripped-down suggestion that does little to encourage company-common practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/prompt03.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the default OpenAPI template provided by Postman.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A picture of the default OpenAPI template provided by Postman.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kinds of prompts could an API Center of Excellence/Enablement, API Governance, or enterprise architecture group consider putting in their default template?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;versioning&quot;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/4002570-how-to-deliver-sustainable-apis&quot;&gt;In its research (paywalled, unfortunately)&lt;/a&gt;, Gartner identifies not one, not two, but &lt;em&gt;five&lt;/em&gt; different ways an API could be versioned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API Evolution, or only allowing for additions to an API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Root namespace URI versioning (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://api.example.com/v1/resource&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resource-level URL versioning (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://api.example.com/resource/v1&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTTP content header versioning (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;curl -H &quot;Accepts-version:1.0&quot; https://api.example.com/resource&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTTP query parameter versioning (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://api.example.com/resource?version=1&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, there are even more ways to version an API than that!  And one way isn’t superior to another method. Yet, to manage the cognitive overhead of working with many APIs, it is important to create designs with consistent versioning behavior within a common domain, like an organization. A new member to that domain, when presented with a template, shouldn’t have to guess which approach is desired in their new context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenAPI template should demonstrate the versioning method preferred by the organization. It should not be up to the designer to recall best practices from a separate correspondence in order to do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-descriptions&quot;&gt;Better Descriptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, how many times have you been reading documentation, like that generated from an OpenAPI description, and you’ve come across something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;name: userId
description: the Id of the user
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that might be &lt;em&gt;technically&lt;/em&gt; correct, it is also the bare minimum way to describe an important piece of information. The writer might have not bothered with a description since it doesn’t convey much more than what could be gleaned from the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous role, we defined a series of characteristics that makes a compelling, worthwhile description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Characteristic&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Details&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Examples&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Context&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Context Detailed business context explaining what the data stands for and its expected usage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“A userId represents individuals and business entities that either (1) have active accounts or (2) are in the pre-sales pipeline.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Disambiguation&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Explains terms not commonly used&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“Field refers to the number of seconds after launch when MECO occurred. MECO stands for “Main Engine Cut-Off”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Interrelationship&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Defines if there is an important interrelationship with other available data in the same structure&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“User account status code and user reactivation indicator are referenced together for obtaining the correct status of the account.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Values, Range, or Examples&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Proves insight into the range or bounded set of values possible.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“Valid FICO scores are between 300 and 850. A FICO score less than 300 or greater than 850 is invalid. Negative numbers should never be used.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Data Sourcing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Where the data comes from or how it is generated.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“This FICO score is provided by Equifax.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reference/Notes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Provides links to training documents&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“For more information on satellite launch thresholds and valid values, please see https://example.org/reference/DOC-12345.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Proper Grammar &amp;amp; Complete Sentences&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Definitions should start with the term being defined.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“Currency Code is the ISO three-character code indicating the currency for the transaction.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Update Frequency/Retention&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Information on source application, frequency of upload, and/or retention policy, if applicable.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;“Data is updated monthly for the entire customer population.”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every field will require every characteristic. However, when it comes to the template presented to an API designer, we should provide examples that illustrate better, more complete information. If we give a designer a bare-bones, minimally worded OpenAPI description, they’re likely to continue that same approach in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your API landscape grows, perhaps versioning or better field descriptions aren’t a primary concern. However, hopefully, these examples have sparked some ideas on how you might lean in on the issues that concern you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it doesn’t have to end with just the templates. At the recently completed APIDays conference, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/D1vPdX2TdRI?t=901&quot;&gt;ADP’s Boris Vernoff demonstrated how their customized environments promote consistency within their design environments (screens begin around the 15-minute mark)&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than starting the design process with a blank page, a designer can select from a series of prompts. This ‘wizard’ approach does constrain the possibility space. However, in doing so, it directs energy to solve the unique business problem and away from introducing variance on non-value-adding API mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot that goes into creating APIs with &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2016/06/02/ConsistencyAndCohesion/&quot;&gt;greater consistency and cohesion&lt;/a&gt;. What is your environment doing to make that easier?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/07/14/WhatShouldBeInATemplate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/07/14/WhatShouldBeInATemplate/</guid>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        <category>API governance</category>
        
        <category>environment</category>
        
        <category>behavior</category>
        
        <category>Boris Vernoff</category>
        
        <category>dashboards</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rethinking the Humble Template</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/25/ArchitectureIsLaw/&quot;&gt;I discussed how changing the environment could change people’s behavior&lt;/a&gt;. Further, I proposed that software tools are as much the environment as a developer’s office. Careful prompt design within those environments can create &lt;strong&gt;better behavioral outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;less effort&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;more buy-in&lt;/strong&gt;. But what does that look like in practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stack-overflow-example&quot;&gt;The Stack Overflow Example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; is a website where people ask questions for other people to answer. To remain viable, Stack Overflow desires certain behaviors from its audience. First of all, they aren’t interested in &lt;em&gt;quantity&lt;/em&gt; but quality; poorly worded, vague, or duplicate questions aren’t welcome. You don’t go to Stack Overflow to idly chat. Further, they aren’t interested in lots of answers, only the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website’s environment goes to great lengths to prompt these sorts of behaviors. Before one is allowed to ask a question, a modal pop-up reminds the asker to search to see if their question has already been asked and how to ask if they can’t find a prior version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/prompt01.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the Stack Overflow modal prompt before posting a question.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I, subsequently begin a question, the interface immediately provides feedback as to whether it is worth posting, and any already existing questions. The process continues through the post body, with a host of prompts for specificity, uniqueness, and completeness. By exhibiting these behaviors, I’m more likely to get my question answered, and the site gets a valuable reference for the next person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/prompt02.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the Stack Overflow question interface.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack Overflow still has moderators&lt;/strong&gt;. They do step in when necessary. But the amount of manual intervention they undertake is significantly less than if there were no environmental nudges toward behaviors beneficial for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-openapi-example&quot;&gt;The OpenAPI Example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, we should think of templates also as a prompt. When capturing business intent in an API specification, like OpenAPI, many tools present a bare-bones template. This template exists to help a new designer get started but often it is the most minimal valid version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/prompt03.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the default OpenAPI template provided by Postman..&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much potential here! Most companies I’m familiar with have some form of an &lt;a href=&quot;http://apistylebook.com/design/guidelines/&quot;&gt;API style guide&lt;/a&gt;. Imagine if I, as a new developer, had those desired API behaviors around naming, descriptions, and responses &lt;em&gt;embedded in my tooling&lt;/em&gt;? How much easier would it be to design “the right way” if I just had to customize a relevant example rather than invent YAML whole cloth? How much more likely am I to adopt a particular error object structure if it is prompted at the beginning of every new design, as opposed to having to track it down in documentation somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not there yet with organization-level templates. And, even then, more meaningful templates for their toolchains are only the beginning. As Stack Overflow shows, there are numerous types and times for prompts in a software environment. As people trying to create better outcomes, we need to add environmental design to our available approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/30/TemplatesAsPrompts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/30/TemplatesAsPrompts/</guid>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        <category>API governance</category>
        
        <category>environment</category>
        
        <category>behavior</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Change Behavior, Change The Environment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A school’s corridor can be a problem. Children run from their rooms on one end to the exit on the other. In the stampede, someone could trip. Kids could get hurt. In even the best-case scenario, the hallway chaos riles kids up, cutting into productive classroom time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One approach would be to insert an authority figure. Policing the hallway, they could shush and wag their finger. Alternatively, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Rainmaker1973/status/1384439194727104513&quot;&gt;a school could install a floor like this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/hallway.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of a hallway with a floor tiled in such a way that it looks like it is melting out from underneath.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The floor is still perfectly level. However, the illusion produced by the tile design demonstrates the power of architecture. People don’t run across this. We have a change to the environment that creates a change to behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyhabits.com/book/&quot;&gt;Tiny Habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, BJ Fogg, PhD  describes how a behavior occurs when the following three things converge in the exact moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt; - The desire to do a behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability&lt;/strong&gt; - The ability to do the behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt&lt;/strong&gt; - The prompt to do the behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the bell rings at the end of class, it is a &lt;strong&gt;prompt&lt;/strong&gt; for the students to exhibit a behavior: moving from one place to another. They could walk. However, they have a low &lt;strong&gt;motivation&lt;/strong&gt; to do so; if they run they can get the best pick of seats, have more time to talk, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inserting a hallway monitor is an attempt to change the motivation and, thus, the behavior. By putting an authority figure in the space, students’ willingness to “get in trouble by running” must be taken into account. It works, but the introduction of policing and enforcement creates an antagonistic relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much of the software governance literature starts with an apology. Then the author jumps to their particular riff of “sticks and carrots”. As you might guess, sticks represent punishment for not performing certain behaviors. Carrots are rewards for playing along. Most people can intuitively grok extrinsic “sticks and carrots”. However, despite being one of the easiest to understand methods of changing behavior, &lt;em&gt;both address only one part of the behavior equation,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;motivation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the floor illustrates, there are other ways to change behaviors. In software, our environments are composed of numerous tools. Conscientious systems thinkers &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; consider how tooling &lt;em&gt;prompts&lt;/em&gt; and empowers (or disempowers) &lt;em&gt;ability&lt;/em&gt;. Without purposeful design, the behaviors created by these everyday touchpoints are left up to chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modify an environment to make the right thing easy to do, and the need for someone to police behavior goes down significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/25/ArchitectureIsLaw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/25/ArchitectureIsLaw/</guid>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        <category>API governance</category>
        
        <category>BJ Fogg</category>
        
        <category>environment</category>
        
        <category>behavior</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Versus Why Questions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/06/questions.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of a card with the caption 'Absurd Questions' above a stylized question mark.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my API governance experience, I interviewed &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of teams. The purpose of those chats was always to reach a better understanding of the problem. A better understanding leads to better design. &lt;strong&gt;Most&lt;/strong&gt; of the time, these conversations were amicable, easy-going affairs. One contributing factor that kept these affairs from becoming confrontations was when I switched from asking “Why” to asking “How” questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you ask someone “Why” they do or don’t do something, you’ll inevitably provoke a defensive response. For example, when trying to learn more about somebody’s API practice, I could ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why don’t you have 100% contract test coverage?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why aren’t your API descriptions captured in a single, discoverable place?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why did you produce so many microservices?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Why is your domain terminology inconsistent?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the classic catch-all, &lt;em&gt;“Why did you do it this way?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of those may be a legitimate question. However, the nature of the question comes across as a request for justification. Worse, answers to a why question immediately entrenches the person in a list, of their own making, of confirmation bias. What was supposed to be a positive discourse has turned exhausting, as each side attempts to prove that their approach is superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking “how” is much more productive. Reframing our points from earlier changes the questions to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How do you detect breaking changes in production?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How do developers discover and learn how to use APIs in your area?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How do you manage the greater complexity with your number of microservices?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How do you describe this concept within your domain?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How did you work through the difficult decisions in this design?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the ‘how’ and ‘why’ examples address, roughly, the same areas of concern. However, the ‘how’ questions are more likely to result in people talking in greater length, detail, and thoughtfulness. They assist us in going further in exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking quality, open-ended questions creates a better rapport and a clearer idea of how to help. And the faster we get to help, the sooner our customers will find success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you feel the urge to ask “why”, try reaching for “how” instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/23/HowVersusWhyWhyQuestions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/23/HowVersusWhyWhyQuestions/</guid>
        
        <category>API Design</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>API Governance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blasting Off For New Adventures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/03/postman-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Postman Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to share that, this April, I’ll be joining Postman as the &lt;strong&gt;Director for API Platforms and Digital Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;.  I’ll be reporting to Kin Lane, Chief API Evangelist. I’m the latest addition to Postman’s Open Technologies group, an incredible, assembled group of industry-leading professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postman.com/&quot;&gt;Postman, as many developers already know, sets the bar for API collaboration excellence&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll get to help companies build their API lifecycle management and governance programs on that incredible bedrock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m excited to get started and look forward to meeting all my future fellow &lt;em&gt;Postmanauts&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m eager to look forward, I would be remiss to not say a few words about the past. Thank you to those at Capital One for an incredibly educational five and a half years. I’m proud of so much of that early, ecosystem-enabling work. That effort has scaled to thousands of schema-defined, affordance-consistent microservices that perform &lt;em&gt;half a billion requests a day&lt;/em&gt;. From training to the collaborations, from tool development to analysis, every day was an opportunity to grow as a professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A half-decade is also long enough to see initial assumptions grow, change, and take on a life of their own. Relationships form and strongly held ideals evolve beyond the first contact with production. I have a different level of professional maturity now that I didn’t have at the start, even if the past year has mostly been unkempt hair and sweatshirts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There remain a vast number of folks there continuing to create positive change. I see you, salute you, and want you to know I will continue to root for you. I also wish my former team the best of luck; you have taught me a tremendous amount. Now the wheel is yours. You’re driving where things go next. You’ve got this. I believe in you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be a busy next few months. In 2015, my family moved to the East Coast for the Capital One job. The pandemic and limited travel options impressed just how removed the northern Virginia region is from our extended families. So we’ll be taking advantage of Postman’s 100% remote allowance and moving our circus to the Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a lot of &lt;strong&gt;uff-da&lt;/strong&gt; for now, but we’ll break &lt;strong&gt;lefse&lt;/strong&gt; soon enough. &lt;strong&gt;Skol&lt;/strong&gt; and boldness to you, friends!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/03/29/Postman/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/03/29/Postman/</guid>
        
        <category>Postman</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>Minneapolis</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WandaVision and This American Moment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/02/wandavision.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;WandaVision, now streaming on Disney+&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to talk about WandaVision, the Disney+ series, and the first entry into the Marvel Cinematic Universe’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel_Cinematic_Universe:_Phase_Four&quot;&gt;Phase Four&lt;/a&gt;. After more than a year and a half, the team behind the series could have easily coasted on pent-up fan demand and character nostalgia. Yet, through some meticulous design decisions and serendipitous timing, WandaVision is uniquely commenting on this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social and class unrest, political skullduggery, disrupted workplaces, chaotic education situations, and economic uncertainty are all playing out amid a global pandemic. We’re at home; a move that began as a preventative measure but, increasingly, feels like a prison. Since there’s little else to do or little else we have the cognitive and emotional energy for, I’ve been watching more television than usual. Like many, I’ve binged past comfort shows while doomscrolling through insomnia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time moves strangely in the pandemic’s unreality. One day drags along in repetitive tedium like any other. Yet the months rapidly disappear with little memory to account that they were there. Without personal touchstones - the trips, reviews, concerts, and even new media releases- I’ve become a character stuck in my own show’s reruns, repeating the routine but unable to progress the character arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;light spoilers to follow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In WandaVision, the residents of Westview, NJ, also find themselves trapped in an unnatural reality. They are compelled, sometimes at great pain, to maintain a facade of the American dream: the suburb, the marriage, the homeownership, the stupefying white-collar job, etc. Even the town name, ‘Westview’ is a nod to western, or American, perception of success. The aspirational normalcy is an attempt to cope. And, at the end of the episode, the characters avoid the strangeness unpinning it all by watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I watch WandaVision, I see a reflection of ourselves; protagonists struggling with grief. We are unsure of how this started or when it will end. We’re in control but, not? We are grieving for those we lost. We grieve for the time we won’t get back and the plans deferred. We grieve for the myths we told ourselves about a just nation and a logical, ordered world. Wanda’s story is one of grief. Despite the superpowers, her story is eminently relatable to our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;is a lot&lt;/em&gt;. Some of us have yet to acknowledge what has happened. Some of us continue to cling, even violently, to the narratives we once had. Processing the world as it is and what has changed will continue for us for some time to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would WandaVision resonate so strongly if we weren’t in a pandemic? Perhaps. I could write another post on how the show uses TV tropes and audience expectations to accentuate the storytelling. That “meta-ness” would be entertaining in any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, WandaVision becomes transcendent at this moment in which we’re all trapped in our own Westview.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/02/08/WandaVision/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/02/08/WandaVision/</guid>
        
        <category>WandaVision</category>
        
        <category>storytelling</category>
        
        <category>Marvel</category>
        
        <category>MCU</category>
        
        <category>reviews</category>
        
        <category>superheroes</category>
        
        <category>Disney</category>
        
        <category>Disney+</category>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why AI Success is API Built</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, I gave two public presentations. I posted ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/07/09/APIsAreArrangementsOfPower/&quot;&gt;APIs are Arrangements of Power&lt;/a&gt;’ previously. The clean-up on the second, delievered when in-person gatherings still happened, languished due to (&lt;em&gt;gestures wildly at the surrounding air&lt;/em&gt;) things. During the holidays, however, I made an effort to finalize and pull everything together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recording of an abridged version of the talk is embedded at the bottom. A portion of the talk even made it into the book, &lt;em&gt;Accelerating Software Quality&lt;/em&gt;, by Eran Kinsbruner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here is ‘Why AI Success is API Built’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Welcome!&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/strong&gt; My name is Matthew Reinbold, and tonight, I will be talking about &lt;em&gt;Why AI Success is Built on APIs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Agenda&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re briefly going to go over:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why AI is such a big deal &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt; just to level set&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about the challenges of creating AI models&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why some of those challenges lead to APIs to deliver AI functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide3.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Why is Matthew giving this talk?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m passionate about these issues because they impact my work. I am the Director of the Capital One API and Event Streaming Center of Excellence. It is a unique position that requires me to be part enterprise architect, part business analyst, and part internal developer evangelist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I work with our 9000+ developer community to ensure that the message-passing systems built exhibit consistency and cohesion. We provide training, collaborate on API descriptions, evolve oversight processes, and facilitate co-creation on our design standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also do a fair amount in the broader API community. I write a newsletter called &lt;a href=&quot;http://netapinotes.com/&quot;&gt;Net API Notes&lt;/a&gt;. I curate &lt;a href=&quot;https://webapi.events/&quot;&gt;Net API Events&lt;/a&gt;, a list of in-person events for API professionals worldwide. I also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/libel_vox&quot;&gt;tweet a fair amount, mostly about APIs but sometimes, occasionally, Lego&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also make some legally dubious laptop sticker parodies &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/matthewreinbold&quot;&gt;for my Patreons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide4.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Getting on the Same AI Page&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that I first establish what I’m talking about when I talk about when I say ‘AI’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide5.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Clarifying AI&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI has generated almost as much excitement as clickbait headlines. You would be forgiven to think that we’re all one errant compile away from Skynet. I mean, even the Pope is talking with Microsoft. When something crosses over into popular awareness, it is significant; even if that awareness is imperfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going further, we should be on the same page. AI is a broad brush that paints many things. Usually, when you see these alarmist articles about Skynet and Terminator death robots, the authors are postulating about “&lt;strong&gt;Artificial General Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;”. This is software that can “think” in a manner we associate with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still quite far from that future. What I will be talking about tonight is much more narrowly focused. So narrow, in fact, that practitioners refer to it as “&lt;strong&gt;narrow AI&lt;/strong&gt;”. Even more specifically, I will discuss a popular technique, often conflated as AI, called “&lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has real, tangible benefits for companies. It also solves interesting challenges. As an additional plus, it &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; won’t end human life as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide6.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Machine Learning is Growing at a Tremendous Rate&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were trying to follow every single new paper released in the machine learning space, you’d now be trying to absorb 100 machine learning papers &lt;em&gt;every single day&lt;/em&gt;. While the concepts behind machine learning have been around for some time, the current Cambrian explosion of published work has many factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/strong&gt; - The &lt;em&gt;speed&lt;/em&gt; of compute is faster than it has ever been, particularly in GPUs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Compute&lt;/strong&gt; - Everyone can get access to these fast processors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Data&lt;/strong&gt; - For better or for worse, we are better about to scale both data collection, storage, and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greater Ease in Model Creation&lt;/strong&gt; - More people are trying more stuff more of the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Chart from the blog post ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://data-mining.philippe-fournier-viger.com/too-many-machine-learning-papers/&quot;&gt;Too Many Machine Learning Papers&lt;/a&gt;’)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide7.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;What is Machine Learning?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full explanation of how machine learning, and how its various permutations work is beyond this presentation’s scope. However, as we begin to discuss why these things take so much compute or why they’re so energy expensive, we need some theoretical model in how they’re composed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose, for example, we had to create a service that could determine whether a provided picture was of a chihuahua or not. The output is either “yes” if a chihuahua is present or “no” if not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using machine learning, we would create several &lt;em&gt;nodes&lt;/em&gt; for our &lt;em&gt;input layer&lt;/em&gt;. Each of these nodes corresponds with an individual pixel of the image provided. A &lt;em&gt;weight&lt;/em&gt; is assigned to each of the nodes. The value of this weight is based on how important that node, or individual pixel, is to determining whether a chihuahua is present. Pixels framing the outside might have a low weighted value, while those around the inverted triangle comprising the two eyes and snout would be worth more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going further, I think it is important to note we’re already dealing with some large numbers with only our input layer. My first digital camera was a Sony Mavica in 1999. The &lt;em&gt;max&lt;/em&gt; resolution of a picture saved to the floppy drive was 640x480. If we were processing images in that resolution, we’d have &lt;strong&gt;an input layer of 307,200 nodes&lt;/strong&gt;. Those are 307,200 weights that need to be tuned to develop a model. And as you might imagine, pictures taken with modern mobile devices have millions of pixels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we’re only getting started. We take the RGB values in a given node, compute a result with the weight for that node, and then pass that value &lt;em&gt;to every other node in the subsequent layer to be processed&lt;/em&gt;. There may be many of these “hidden layers” between the input and the output. Each node in each layer mathematically computes its result. This continues until all the results are recombined into a value in the &lt;em&gt;output layer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This output layer contains the probability of whether the input meets our criteria. If it is above a particular percentage, we might say, “yes” the image did contain a dog. We continue to iterate on our weights until we are satisfied with how often our machine learning model successfully matches our labeled sample data used for training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve used machine learning to create a model to detect if our picture features a chihuahua…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For more explanation, see the YouTube video course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oV3ZY6tJiA0&quot;&gt;Crash Course: AI&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/LHeDYF6az38&quot;&gt;Chihuahua Photo by Alvan Nee on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/WQ8CHKHHzK8&quot;&gt;Photo by Reproductive Health Supplies Coalition on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide8.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Finding Patterns in Data is Not the Same as Understanding Data&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…or a muffin. It is essential to point out that through all those mathematical calculations, machine learning doesn’t understand what it is looking at; at least not the way we do. It has only identified &lt;em&gt;patterns&lt;/em&gt; where two darker dots consistently appear above one other dot (eyes above the snout).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/You-Look-Like-Thing-Love/dp/0316525243&quot;&gt;You Look Like a Thing and I Love You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Janelle Shane described a similar problem. Microsoft has an image recognition product that works similar to our example: it takes an image and suggests what might be in it. One day, while using this product, Janelle noticed that it was finding sheep in photos that definitely did not have sheep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After experimentation, Janelle hypothesized that the machine learning model was trained with lots and lots of pictures of sheep in green, grassy countrysides. The model did not “learn” the sheep’s visual properties, but mistakenly correlated the landscape with the sheep label. Subsequently, when Janelle gave the model pictures of sheep in cars or livings rooms, the model labeled the animals as dogs and cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Image from the ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/chihuahua-or-muffin-my-search-for-the-best-computer-vision-api-cbda4d6b425d/&quot;&gt;Chihuahua or Muffin?&lt;/a&gt;’ tutorial.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide9.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Machine Learning is Strategically Important to Companies&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, machine learning is still &lt;strong&gt;a very big deal™&lt;/strong&gt; for companies. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/artificial-intelligence/ai-governance-support-innovation&quot;&gt;According to an Accenture global research survey&lt;/a&gt;, 85% of business leaders expect AI to open up new products, services, business models, and markets. Another 78% expect AI to disrupt their industry in the next ten years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, a report from market research firm Tractica &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.top500.org/news/market-for-artificial-intelligence-projected-to-hit-36-billion-by-2025/&quot;&gt;forecasts that the annual global revenue for artificial intelligence products and services will grow from $643.7 million, in 2016, to $36.8 &lt;em&gt;billion&lt;/em&gt; by 2025&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a 57-fold increase and makes AI the fastest-growing segment in the IT sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no, AI &lt;em&gt;is not coming to take our jobs&lt;/em&gt;. As the quote from Mary Gray says, automation doesn’t eliminate jobs; it changes the form those jobs take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide10.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Machine Learning is Good at Specific Things&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning promises to lower costs and produce better outcomes. It’s because AI can recognize subtle patterns in vast volumes of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Princeton professor Arvind Narayan created an excellent presentation late last year, entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf&quot;&gt;How to Recognize AI Snake Oil&lt;/a&gt;”. He identifies where machine learning techniques are practical, where they have problems, and where they may be ethically dubious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enhancing or scaling perception is a great application of machine learning. These have clear success criteria; either the model successfully does a thing or needs additional training. Automating judgment, or asking a machine to call balls and strikes when there is some gray area, is more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s predicting the future. You may use a machine learning algorithm to review someone’s social media feed and identify how often a beer bottle is pictured. That is perception. Assuming that a high percentage of beer bottle appearances makes an individual unfit for employment is predicting an outcome. That is problematic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2020/03/30/ai-is-bad-at-predicting-gpa-grit-eviction-job-training-layoffs-and-material-hardship/&quot;&gt;as research has shown&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Machine learning, despite its promise, cannot tell the future.&lt;/strong&gt; It can only find correlations in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide11.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;However, Machine Learning is Not a Silver Bullet&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also essential to use common sense when considering machine learning. Martin Zinkevich is a research scientist at Google and author of “&lt;a href=&quot;http://martin.zinkevich.org/rules_of_ml/rules_of_ml.pdf&quot;&gt;Rules of Machine Learning: Best Practices for ML Engineering&lt;/a&gt;”. He urges several useful heuristics when evaluating whether machine learning is appropriate for a task, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If your system has more than 100 nested if-else [statements], it’s time to switch to machine learning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine you’re a smartphone developer, and you’re tasked with recommending the next application someone should use. You could consider the time of day, the weather, user movement, sentiment of their social media accounts, their text and call volume, the proximity of that communication in a social graph, etc. Those could all be inputs to a complex model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you could recommend the most frequently used apps. If a simple heuristic, like “recommend the most recently used items”, is successful 70% of the time, any model built has to significantly outperform it to justify the increased complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide12.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Challenges Title Screen&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What form does that complexity take? Let’s talk about the challenges to developing machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide13.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;There are Challenges&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four big challenges to creating successful machine learning models. They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The volume of data to collect and refine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The compute cost to process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regulatory, privacy and/or ethical concerns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operationalization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this, let’s talk about Google’s Meena chatbot. A sample conversation between Meena and a human is shown in the slide. Google used &lt;strong&gt;341GB&lt;/strong&gt; of text to train the model. In doing so, &lt;strong&gt;they consumed $1.4 million in cloud computation&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s a lot of money. It is also a lot of power. For comparison, it would take the average American household  &lt;em&gt;28 years&lt;/em&gt; to burn the same 292,912 kWh of power. I might argue that the conversation is not noticeably better than Eliza, a program crafted at MIT in the 1960s. As such, there is an ethical question of whether the results warrants that level of energy expenditure (and subsequent carbon footprint).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s before we even get to operationalization and the challenges of doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/cd4ml.html&quot;&gt;Continuous Delivery for Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(More on Meena from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/googles-meena-advances-the-exquisite-banality-of-chat-bots/&quot;&gt;ZDNet article&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide14.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Building Your Own AI Models Can Be Expensive&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider where the compute for your models is being run. If the training can be done anywhere, research which AWS regions carbon offset, for example. For reference, that is &lt;strong&gt;not US-EAST-1&lt;/strong&gt;. If the training is geographically agnostic, take a few minutes and click the necessary boxes to a configuration more carbon friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Articles pictured in this slide include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.co m/s/613630/training-a-single-aimodel-can-emit-as-much-carbonas-five-cars-in-their-lifetimes/&quot;&gt;Training a single AI model can emit as much carbon as five cars in their lifetimes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/614700/the-computing-power-needed-to-train-ai-is-now-rising-seven-times-faster-than-ever-before/&quot;&gt;Computer power needed is rising seven times faster than ever before&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide15.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Building on Other's Work Is Important&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, consider building upon others work. It may be hard to remember, but there was a time when the idea of having a picture of every single inch along every single street in every single place was a problem of seemingly infinite scale. Imagine if every application with a street view had to stand-up and operate their own fleet of vehicles and cameras. Yet today, anyone can call a Google Maps API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, we aren’t that far removed when small and mid-sized businesses maintained their server closets. Handling things like seasonal traffic or DDS attacks was an individual challenge. Now we have APIs on cloud-providers, like AWS, to call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, imagine if every application that wanted to send a text message had to negotiate individual deals with each and every telco provider? The barriers to innovation would be horrible. Better to let someone like Twilio do that once, and then we build upon the abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way that these companies have exposed services via APIs, the future very much looks like leaving the big, precarious, and expensive data collection and model building to the experts. Then we consume that model through an API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide16.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Enter APIs&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APIs are an &lt;em&gt;enabling technology&lt;/em&gt;. AI doesn’t reduce or eliminate the need for APIs. &lt;strong&gt;More AI use demands more sensible and well-designed APIs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide17.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;APIs Provide an Abstraction to Technical Complexity&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web API (or Net API) provides a &lt;em&gt;separation of concerns&lt;/em&gt;. You have your code. You focus on uniquely solving your business problem. Then, through an API, you consume someone else’s generated model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AI provider handles the tricky issues of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collecting and Refining the Data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paying the electricity bill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fielding regulatory inquiries around privacy and security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing the operationalization of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide18.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Language is the Most Used AI Accessed Through APIs&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the industry already moving in this direction. The chart shown was created from a survey of which types of functionality were consumed via API. Things like natural language processing are highest on the list, for the reasons that Princeton’s Arvind Narayan pointed out: these are all perception related. Scaling perception is where AI has proven its usefulness and we’re moving toward a commodification of the feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Chart from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistic
s/1069198/worldwide-ai-machine-learning-api/&quot;&gt;Statista.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide19.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;AI API Claims Require Data Questioning&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When choosing between AI offerings via an API, it will be necessary for consumers to evaluate their claims via intelligent questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vicki Boykis is a data scientist and writer out of Philadelphia. In her essay, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://vicki.substack.com/p/neural-nets-are-just-people-all-the&quot;&gt;Neural nets are just people all the way down&lt;/a&gt;”, Vicki highlights some important revelations on one highly-touted AI use case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“if you’re doing image recognition in 2019, it’s highly likely you’re using an image recognition systems built by images tagged by people using Mechanical Turk in 2007 that sit on top of language classification systems built by graduate students prowling newspaper clippings in the 1960s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s so much we should be asking about our AI providers. However, briefly, consider the incentives. Be wary if there are financial incentives to be less than transparent about how the model is generated or where the data is collected from. Also, be skeptical if an AI product also happens to use the latest blockchain-enabled, agile-Kubernetes, nano-service hype salad. Leverage others’ work, like this article comparing cloud providers; not all pieces are this comprehensive, but there are folks out there that are sharing their results for the community’s benefit. And, finally, interrogate the data. In general, we’re not good at this, in general, but, going-forward it will increasingly be more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Articles pictured in this slide include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/artificial-intelligence/machine-learning/learn-the-red-flags-ofoverhyped-ai-claims&quot;&gt;Three easy ways to evaluate AI Claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altexsoft.com/blog/datascience/comparing-machine-learning-as-a-service-amazon-microsoft-azure-google-cloud-ai-ibm-watson/&quot;&gt;Comparing Machine Learning as a Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide20.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Dataset Nutrition Labels Need Our Support&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A survey was done asking folks whether they had practices in place to determine whether their data was good. Unfortunately, 44% said ‘no’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, that is not going to be an acceptable answer. We need to figure out best practices to interrogate the data. This is especially true of APIs since we may not have our hands on that data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the same survey, a majority of respondents reported that their ability to analyze data was self-taught. Going forward, we will need standardized, reusable approaches to create standardized, predictable results. As proposed in the linked white paper, one idea is using a nutritional label-like representation to compare and contrast datasets used in AI products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adopting a dataset nutrition label &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; help. However, keep in mind that having a robust understanding of the data is only one part of the process necessary to create a working model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Charts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1805/1805.03677.pdf&quot;&gt;The Dataset Nutrition Label Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide21.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Conclusions&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a lot and, again, I’m only showing the tip of the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide22.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Where to Learn More&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more, there are numerous placed to get started. In addition to the many papers, presentations, and courses that I’ve linked to throughout this talk, I would also recommend the following books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/you-look-like-a-thing-and-i-love-you-how-artificial-intelligence-works-and-why-it-s-making-the-world-a-weirder-place/9780316525244&quot;&gt;You Look Like a Thing and I Love You&lt;/a&gt; by Janelle Shane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/rebooting-ai-building-artificial-intelligence-we-can-trust/9781524748258&quot;&gt;A Human’s Guide to Machine Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; by Kartik Hosanagar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/rebooting-ai-building-artificial-intelligence-we-can-trust/9781524748258&quot;&gt;Rebooting AI&lt;/a&gt; by Gary Marcus and Ernest Davies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I would highly encourage those working in the space to have a firm grasp of how these algorithmic approaches can cause harm. For that, I would suggest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/weapons-of-math-destruction-how-big-data-increases-inequality-and-threatens-democracy/9780553418835&quot;&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction&lt;/a&gt; by Cathy O’Neil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/automating-inequality-how-high-tech-tools-profile-police-and-punish-the-poor/9781250215789&quot;&gt;Automating Inequality&lt;/a&gt; by Virginia Eubanks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also surprises me that there aren’t more sites that allow prospective AI users do “comparison shopping” across the major providers. Algorithmia &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to be an online marketplace for algorithms. Similarly, Inten.to &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to allow running sample queries across cloud algorithms. Both appear to have since pivoted. Certain AI APIs can still be found within the Programmable Web directory, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a couple good sources for data, if people are looking for raw ingredients to get started. If you are aware of other sites that provide a similar service, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/01/Slide23.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How to Contact Me&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time and attention. My name is Matthew Reinbold and you can find me online at these fine establishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the presentation given to the DC API Meetup Group, recorded February 4th, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DAm6o9LULts&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/01/08/WhyAISuccessIsAPIBuilt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/01/08/WhyAISuccessIsAPIBuilt/</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>API design</category>
        
        <category>APIs</category>
        
        <category>presos</category>
        
        <category>skynet</category>
        
        <category>Microsoft</category>
        
        <category>machine learning</category>
        
        <category>Sony</category>
        
        <category>Janelle Shane</category>
        
        <category>Accenture</category>
        
        <category>Tractica</category>
        
        <category>Mary Gray</category>
        
        <category>Arvind Narayan</category>
        
        <category>Martin Zinkevich</category>
        
        <category>Google</category>
        
        <category>Meena</category>
        
        <category>Eliza</category>
        
        <category>MIT</category>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>carbon offsets</category>
        
        <category>Google Maps</category>
        
        <category>Twilio</category>
        
        <category>Vicki Boykis</category>
        
        <category>Kartik Hosanagar</category>
        
        <category>Gary Marcus</category>
        
        <category>Ernest Davies</category>
        
        <category>Cathy O'Neil</category>
        
        <category>Virginia Eubanks</category>
        
        <category>Eran Kinsbruner</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Shared Road</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From an individual API producer’s perspective, adherence to an enterprise company’s design style guide may seem puzzling. “Why do we have to learn these naming conventions?” they’ll ask. Other questions include, “What difference does our style of versioning make?” or “Why can’t we use the authentication scheme that worked at my previous company?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2019, I did a series of “Back to Basics” roadshows for my day job. According to various surveys, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackerlife.co/blog/san-francisco-large-corporation-employee-tenure&quot;&gt;the average developer tenure at any company is between one and two years&lt;/a&gt;. My goal, through the roadshows, was to re-establish the principles that have guided our five-year-old program. I’ve used urban planning stories before, whether that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2015/05/12/APIsandGovernance/&quot;&gt;Brazillian Favelas&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/net-api-notes-for-2020-01-24-mailbag-issue-119&quot;&gt;Paris’s tree-lined boulevards&lt;/a&gt;. To justify the need for enterprise standards for a degree of design consistency, I used a traffic regulation analogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of it because of the most recent Postlight podcast, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://postlight.com/podcast/restricting-freedom-for-more-freedom-on-the-parallels-between-wearing-a-mask-and-regulating-tech&quot;&gt;Restricting Freedom for More Freedom: On The Parallels Between Wearing a Mask and Regulating Tech&lt;/a&gt;”. In that show, hosts Paul Ford and Rich Ziade discuss people treating mask requirements during Covid-19 as a violation of constitutional rights (spoiler: &lt;em&gt;they’re not&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes inconveniencing the individual is the best for the larger group. That goes for whether we’re talking about masks, software governance, or traffic. Below a snippet of my argument from that “Back to Basics” deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/08/road.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The Road Forward&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-software-architecture-is-complex&quot;&gt;Modern software architecture is complex&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Ousterhout, in his book “A Philosophy of Software Design”, defines complexity as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“-anything related to the structure of a software system that makes it hard to understand and modify the system.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, a barrier to the kind of business agility that we crave, that is needed to win in competitive marketplaces, is how hard our architectures are to grok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;message-passing-hides-complexity-behind-an-interface&quot;&gt;Message Passing Hides Complexity Behind an Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Message passing is a means of abstracting complexity and hiding behind an interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That abstraction allows programmers to work on a system without being exposed to all a system’s complexity at once. An API is a simplified view that omits unimportant details (or at least those details unimportant to the API’s consumer). It makes it easier for us to think about and get stuff done in complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-faster-and-high-quality-are-not-diametrically-opposed&quot;&gt;“Going Faster” and “High Quality” Are Not Diametrically Opposed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Going faster” is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a matter of getting rid of the rules. Martin Fowler,  elegantly states to the contrary, that this is a false trade-off. In his piece, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/is-quality-worth-cost.html&quot;&gt;Is High Quality Software Worth the Cost?&lt;/a&gt;” he outlines how quality efforts, over time, translate to great speed for the entire system over any individual’s speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quality-design-is-a-financial-imperative&quot;&gt;Quality Design is a Financial Imperative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-quality design, while quick to make, incurs a lifetime tax. Maintenance is harder, requires additional overhead, and compares less favorably in the marketplace. Quality is not a moral argument, something that makes our inner artisan feel good. Quality design is a financial imperative to increase our software return on investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Key to Writing Less code and causing less rework is to write better abstractions” - Eric Elliot, &lt;em&gt;distributed systems expert and author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-need-continual-renewal-and-reflection-on-what-quality-means-for-us&quot;&gt;We Need Continual Renewal and Reflection on What Quality Means for Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why it is essential that each of us, whether we are product managers, architects, or engineering leads, continually renew our understanding and application of basic core principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A garden is not something that you plant in the spring and wander away from. The ability to reap what was sown requires constant attention and care. We have to rededicate ourselves to executing on the fundamental, basic things before overcoming complexity is possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-road-is-shared&quot;&gt;Our Road is Shared&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the most basic thing, the first principle - the one to remember if you remember nothing else - is that we’re in this together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is only one car on the road, then the fastest way to get from point A to B is to ignore all speed limits, go whichever way they want on one-way roads, and view all traffic signage as optional. From their perspective, an individual team will wail and gnash their teeth at how much faster they could get to production if they were only allowed to do whatever they want. Imagine the freedom(!!!)… for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is not a single team. There are hundreds on their journeys, crisscrossing each other and going to and fro. Things like speed limits, lane markings, stop signs, and traffic signals are all there to move the most people to the greatest number of places, safely. We exist within a system. The road we travel is shared between us. If we are going to arrive, it will be through minor, in-the-moment, inconveniences made for the larger, more-long-lasting, good of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~fin~&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/08/05/OurRoadIsShared/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/08/05/OurRoadIsShared/</guid>
        
        <category>covid-19</category>
        
        <category>favelas</category>
        
        <category>Paris</category>
        
        <category>Brazil</category>
        
        <category>Paul Ford</category>
        
        <category>Rich Ziade</category>
        
        <category>API governance</category>
        
        <category>presos</category>
        
        <category>postlight</category>
        
        <category>Martin Fowler</category>
        
        <category>Eric Elliot</category>
        
        <category>John Ousterhout</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technology Aphorisms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I was talking to another professional with decades of technology experience. When I dropped a reference to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#bike-shedding&quot;&gt;bike-shedding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I was met with a blank stare. Given he had never heard of the reference, much less know the difference between that and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#yak-shaving&quot;&gt;yak shaving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I decided something had to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over my professional career, I’ve collected numerous pithy statements about technology. Some of these aphorisms are serious; others, not so much. &lt;a href=&quot;https://daverupert.com/2018/04/eponymous-laws-of-tech/&quot;&gt;But folks seem to find these things useful&lt;/a&gt;. Internalizing may not make you a better technologist. However, the next time you’re stuck, you’ll know you’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/08/yak-shaving.png&quot; alt=&quot;A parody O'Reilly book cover for Yak Shaving.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Yak Shaving. The definitive guide.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the aphorisms!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ashbys-law&quot;&gt;Ashby’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#baader-meinhof-effect&quot;&gt;Baader-Meinhof Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#balks-law&quot;&gt;Balk’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#betteridges-law-of-headlines&quot;&gt;Betteridge’s Law of Headlines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#bike-shedding&quot;&gt;Bike Shedding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#brandolinis-law&quot;&gt;Brandolini’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#brookss-law&quot;&gt;Brook’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cellan-jones-principle&quot;&gt;Cellan-Jones Principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#clarkes-third-law&quot;&gt;Clarke’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#conways-law&quot;&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#correlation-principle&quot;&gt;Correlation Principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cunninghams-law&quot;&gt;Cunningham’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#demeter-law-of&quot;&gt;Demeter (Law of)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dunbars-number&quot;&gt;Dunbar’s Number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#dunning-kruger-effect&quot;&gt;Dunning-Kruger Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#eaglesons-law&quot;&gt;Eagleson’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#finagles-law&quot;&gt;Finagle’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fitts-law&quot;&gt;Fitt’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#galls-law&quot;&gt;Gall’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gilders-law&quot;&gt;Gilder’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#godwins-law&quot;&gt;Godwin’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#goodharts-law&quot;&gt;Goodhart’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hanlons-razor&quot;&gt;Hanlon’s Razor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hofstadters-law&quot;&gt;Hofstadter’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#huangs-law&quot;&gt;Huang’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hyrums-law&quot;&gt;Hyrum’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#jevons-paradox&quot;&gt;Jevons Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#kernighans-law&quot;&gt;Kernighan’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#kiss-principle&quot;&gt;KISS Principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#law-of-leaky-abstractions&quot;&gt;Law of Leaky Abstractions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#law-of-the-second-floor&quot;&gt;Law of the Second Floor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#least-power-rule-of&quot;&gt;Least Power (Rule of)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lindbloms-razor&quot;&gt;Lindblom’s Razor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#linuss-law&quot;&gt;Linus’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#listers-law&quot;&gt;Lister’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#metcalfes-law&quot;&gt;Metcalfe’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#moores-law&quot;&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#murphys-law&quot;&gt;Murphy’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ninety-ninety-rule&quot;&gt;Ninety-Ninety Rule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nivens-third-law&quot;&gt;Niven’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#occams-razor&quot;&gt;Occam’s Razor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#parkinsons-law-of-triviality&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s Law of Triviality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#peter-principle&quot;&gt;Peter Principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#postels-law&quot;&gt;Postel’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#principle-of-good-enough&quot;&gt;Principle of Good Enough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rule-34&quot;&gt;Rule 34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#singhs-inevitable-avoidance&quot;&gt;Singh’s Inevitable Avoidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#socratic-paradox&quot;&gt;Socratic Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sturgeons-law&quot;&gt;Sturgeon’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sunnyvale-principle&quot;&gt;Sunnyvale Principle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#teslers-law&quot;&gt;Tesler’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#wirths-law&quot;&gt;Wirth’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#yak-shaving&quot;&gt;Yak Shaving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#zawinskis-law&quot;&gt;Zawinski’s Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#zenos-paradox&quot;&gt;Zeno’s Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology-aphorisms&quot;&gt;Technology Aphorisms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ashbys-law&quot;&gt;Ashby’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a system to be stable, the number of states that its control mechanism is capable of attaining must be greater than or equal to the number of states in the controlled system. Or, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ruthmalan/status/1158820721184903175?s=09&quot;&gt;in Jade Bloom’s words&lt;/a&gt;, “complex environments (and wicked problems) require complex organizations”. Attributed to British cybernetician W. Ross Ashby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;baader-meinhof-effect&quot;&gt;Baader-Meinhof Effect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name given to a frequency or recency illusion where once something has been noticed, then every instance of that thing is noticed, leading to the belief it has a high rate of occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;balks-law&quot;&gt;Balk’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything you hate about the Internet is actually everything you hate about people. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theawl.com/2014/06/stop-blaming-the-internet-for-how-horrible-we-all-are&quot;&gt;Attributed to Awl co-founder Alex Balk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;betteridges-law-of-headlines&quot;&gt;Betteridge’s Law of Headlines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any article with a headline or title that ends in a question mark can be summarized by ‘no’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betteridge%27s_law_of_headlines&quot;&gt;Attributed to British technology journalist Ian Betteridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bike-shedding&quot;&gt;Bike Shedding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of wasting time on trivial details while important matters are inadequately attended to. See also &lt;a href=&quot;#parkinsons-law-of-triviality&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s Law of Triviality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;brandolinis-law&quot;&gt;Brandolini’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Says “the amount of energy needed to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude bigger than to produce it.” Named for Alberto Brandolini, an Italian programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;brookss-law&quot;&gt;Brooks’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding people to a late software project makes it later. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mythical_Man-Month&quot;&gt;Attributed to Fred Brooks, author of the book Mythical Man Month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cellan-jones-principle&quot;&gt;Cellan-Jones Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can either explain quantum computing so that it’s understandable or factually correct, but never both simultaneously. Attributed to Rory Cellan-Jones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;clarkes-third-law&quot;&gt;Clarke’s Third Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic. Attributed to British science fiction writer Arthur C. Clarke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conways-law&quot;&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any piece of software reflects the organizational structure that produced it. Attributed to computer scientist Melvin Conway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;correlation-principle&quot;&gt;Correlation Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geepawhill.org/2020/08/21/the-correlation-principle/&quot;&gt;defined by software development coach Geepaw Hill&lt;/a&gt;, the Correlation Principle says that our productivity is tightly correlated with the internal quality of software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cunninghams-law&quot;&gt;Cunningham’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to get the right answer is not to ask questions; it’s to post the wrong answer. Attributed to the wiki creator, Ward Cunningham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;demeter-law-of&quot;&gt;Demeter (Law of)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Law of Demeter (LoD) or principle of least knowledge is a design guideline for software, particularly object-oriented programs. It is summarized as (1) each unit should have limited knowledge of other units, (2) each unit should only talk to its friends, and (3) only talk to your immediate friends. First proposed by Ian Holland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dunbars-number&quot;&gt;Dunbar’s Number&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory an individual can only maintain stable relationships with &lt;em&gt;up to&lt;/em&gt; 150 people. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar%27s_number&quot;&gt;Attributed to British anthropologist Robin Dunbar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dunningkruger-effect&quot;&gt;Dunning–Kruger Effect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cognitive bias in which unskilled individuals suffer from illusory superiority, mistakenly rating their ability much higher than average.  Described by social psychologists David Dunning and Justin Kruger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;eaglesons-law&quot;&gt;Eagleson’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any code of your own that you haven’t looked at for six or more months might as well have been written by someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;finagles-law&quot;&gt;Finagle’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything that can go wrong will and at the worst possible moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fitts-law&quot;&gt;Fitt’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A design law that states the longer the distance to move a cursor and smaller the target size, the longer it takes. It was originally described by Paul Morris Fitts in a 1954 paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;galls-law&quot;&gt;Gall’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A complex system that works is invariably found to have evolved from a simple system that worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gilders-law&quot;&gt;Gilder’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bandwidth grows at least three times faster than computer power. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlingo.com/word/gilders-law.php&quot;&gt;Attributed to author George Gilder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;godwins-law&quot;&gt;Godwin’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An adage that asserts that the longer an online discussion goes on, the probability of a comparison involving Nazis or Hitler approaches 1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Godwin%27s_law&quot;&gt;Promulgated by the American attorney and author Mike Godwin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;goodharts-law&quot;&gt;Goodhart’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning a metric into a target makes it a bad metric. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodhart%27s_law&quot;&gt;Attributed to economist Charles Goodhart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hanlons-razor&quot;&gt;Hanlon’s Razor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by stupidity. Coined by Robert J. Hanlon. See also &lt;a href=&quot;#occams-razor&quot;&gt;Occam’s Razor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hofstadters-law&quot;&gt;Hofstadter’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It always takes longer than you expect, even when you take into account Hofstadter’s Law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;huangs-law&quot;&gt;Huang’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang’s Law is named for Nvidia’s chief executive and co-founder Jensen Huang. It was coined by Chrisopher Mims. It says the performance of GPU chips (which excel at parallel processing) will double every year. This is compared to &lt;a href=&quot;#moores-law&quot;&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/a&gt;, which described performance of a single-threaded CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hyrums-law&quot;&gt;Hyrum’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a sufficient number of users of an API, it does not matter what you promised in the contract. All observable behaviors of your interface will be depended upon by somebody. Attributed to Hyrum Wright, a Google software engineer. See also the &lt;a href=&quot;#law-of-leaky-abstractions&quot;&gt;Law of Leaky Abstractions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jevons-paradox&quot;&gt;Jevons Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An economic phenomenon that says when technological process increases the efficiency with which something is used, the rate of consumption exceeds previous consumption due to increasing demand. Named for English economist William Stanley Jevons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kernighans-law&quot;&gt;Kernighan’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debugging is twice as hard as writing code in the first place. Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as possible, you are, by definition, not smart enough to debug it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/weird-programming-principles/&quot;&gt;Attributed to author and C Programmer Brian Kernighan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kiss-principle&quot;&gt;KISS Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘KISS’ is an acronym that stands for “Keep It Simple, Stupid”. Associated with aircraft engineer Kelly Johnson and noted by the U.S. Navy in 1960. See &lt;a href=&quot;#occams-razor&quot;&gt;Occam’s razor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;law-of-leaky-abstractions&quot;&gt;Law of Leaky Abstractions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/11/11/the-law-of-leaky-abstractions/&quot;&gt;Coined by software developer Joel Spolsky&lt;/a&gt;, the Law of Leaky Abstractions states that all non-trivial abstractions are, to some degree, leaky. See also &lt;a href=&quot;#hyrums-law&quot;&gt;Hyrum’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;law-of-the-second-floor&quot;&gt;Law of the Second Floor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built upon &lt;a href=&quot;#dunbars-number&quot;&gt;Dunbar’s Number&lt;/a&gt;, the law of the 2nd-floor states that no person two levels above or below you on an org chart really understands what you do for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;least-power-rule-of&quot;&gt;Least Power (Rule of)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A design principle that suggests &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rule_of_least_power&quot;&gt;choosing the least powerful [computer] language suitable for a given purpose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lindbloms-razor&quot;&gt;Lindblom’s Razor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never attribute to incompetence that which can be adequately explained by systemic issues. See also &lt;a href=&quot;#hanlons-razor&quot;&gt;Hanlon’s Razor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;linuss-law&quot;&gt;Linus’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow. Formulated by Eric S. Raymond in his essay and book &lt;em&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar&lt;/em&gt; in honor of Linus Torvalds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;listers-law&quot;&gt;Lister’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People under time pressure don’t think faster. Attributed to Timothy Lister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;metcalfes-law&quot;&gt;Metcalfe’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally attributed to Robert Metcalfe, Metcalfe’s Law states the effect of a network is proportional to the square of the number of connected users in the systems. While coined to describe the value in connecting compatibile communication devices in the era of the Ethernet, it has carried over and applied to describe users within a social media system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;moores-law&quot;&gt;Moore’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observation that the number of transistors in an integrated circuit, or CPU, doubles approximately every two years. Attributed to Gordon Moore, the co-founder of Fairchild Semiconductor and CEO and co-founder of Intel. See also &lt;a href=&quot;#huangs-law&quot;&gt;Huang’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;murphys-law&quot;&gt;Murphy’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything that can go wrong will go wrong. Named for Edward Murphy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ninety-ninety-rule&quot;&gt;Ninety-Ninety Rule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 90% of the code accounts for the first 90% of the development time. The remaining 10% of the code accounts for the other 90% of the development. Yes, that is supposed to add up to 180%. The rule is attributed to Tom Cargill of Bell Labs and popularized by Jon Bentley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nivens-third-law&quot;&gt;Niven’s Third Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easier to destroy than to create. Part of a series of laws named for science fiction author Larry Niven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;occams-razor&quot;&gt;Occam’s Razor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem-solving principle that is paraphrased as “the simplest explanation is most likely the right one”. Attributed to English Franciscan friar William of Ockham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;parkinsons-law-of-triviality&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s Law of Triviality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any board meeting the amount of time devoted to an item on the agenda will be the inverse proportion to the issue’s difficulty. Said another way, “The time spent on any item of the agenda will be inverse proportion to the sum [of money] involved.” Named for C. Northcote Parkinson. &lt;a href=&quot;#bike-shedding&quot;&gt;See also Bike Shedding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;peter-principle&quot;&gt;Peter Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees tend to rise to their level of incompetence. A management concept developed by Laurence J. Peter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;postels-law&quot;&gt;Postel’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Named after Jon Postel from his work on TCP/IP, the Postel law says computer protocols should be strict in what is sent and forgiving in what they accept from others. &lt;em&gt;Also known as the Robustness Principle&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;principle-of-good-enough&quot;&gt;Principle of Good Enough&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also known as the “good enough” principle. A rule in software and systems design that says consumers will use products that are good enough for their requirements, despite the availability of more advanced technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rule-34&quot;&gt;Rule 34&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule 34 is an internet meme which states, “If it exists, there is porn of it. No exceptions.” Thought to have originated from a comic drawn by Peter Morley-Souter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;singhs-inevitable-avoidance&quot;&gt;Singh’s Inevitable Avoidance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When organizations don’t know how to solve their problems, they will tweak their process to accommodate their dysfunctions. &lt;a href=&quot;https://agileotter.blogspot.com/2015/10/principles-for-large-organizations.html&quot;&gt;Spotted by Tim Ottinger&lt;/a&gt; and attributed to Asshok Singh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;socratic-paradox&quot;&gt;Socratic Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A saying, attributed to Greek philosopher Socrates, stating, “I know that I know nothing”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I_know_that_I_know_nothing&quot;&gt;It is derived from Plato’s account but not one that Socrates ever recorded as saying.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sturgeons-law&quot;&gt;Sturgeon’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ninety percent of anything is crap. Coined by Theodore Sturgeon, an American science fiction author and critic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunnyvale-principle&quot;&gt;Sunnyvale Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s never time to do it right, but always time to do it over. Attributed to Jack Bergman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;teslers-law&quot;&gt;Tesler’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every app has an inherent amount of irreducible complexity. The challenge is how to deal with it. On the surface, spending a development week to save a minute on a common task may seem unjustifiable. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.programmersparadox.com/2008/08/17/teslers-law/&quot;&gt;However, if there are a million users, the consumer is penalized for making the engineer’s job easier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wirths-law&quot;&gt;Wirth’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is getting slower more rapidly than hardware becomes faster. Named after Niklaus Wirth who discussed it in his 1995 article, “A Plea for Lean Software”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;yak-shaving&quot;&gt;Yak Shaving&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refers to a task that leads you to perform another related task and so on, with each subsequent task leading one further from their original goal. This continues until, eventually, you find yourself shaving a yak. Coined by Carlin Vieri after viewing an episode of &lt;em&gt;The Ren and Stimpy Show&lt;/em&gt; featuring “Yak Shaving Day”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;zawinskis-law&quot;&gt;Zawinski’s Law&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every program attempts to expand until it can read mail. Those programs which cannot so expand are replaced by ones which can. Named for American computer programmer Jamie Zawinski.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;zenos-paradox&quot;&gt;Zeno’s Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The belief in change actually occurring is a mistake, and that any motion forward is nothing but an illusion. Thought to be devised by Greek philosopher Zeno of Elea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/08/03/Technology-Aphorisms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/08/03/Technology-Aphorisms/</guid>
        
        <category>Jade Bloom</category>
        
        <category>W. Ross Ashby</category>
        
        <category>Alex Balk</category>
        
        <category>Ian Betteridge</category>
        
        <category>Fred Brooks</category>
        
        <category>Rory Cellan-Jones</category>
        
        <category>Arthur C. Clarke</category>
        
        <category>Conway's Law</category>
        
        <category>Melvin Conway</category>
        
        <category>Ward Cunningham</category>
        
        <category>Robin Dunbar</category>
        
        <category>David Dunning</category>
        
        <category>Justin Kruger</category>
        
        <category>George Gilder</category>
        
        <category>Mike Godwin</category>
        
        <category>Charles Goodhart</category>
        
        <category>Charles Goodhart</category>
        
        <category>Hyrum Wright</category>
        
        <category>William Stanley Jevons</category>
        
        <category>Brian Kernighan</category>
        
        <category>Kelly Johnson</category>
        
        <category>Linus Torvalds</category>
        
        <category>Eric S. Raymond</category>
        
        <category>Timothy Lister</category>
        
        <category>Gordon Moore</category>
        
        <category>Tom Cargill</category>
        
        <category>Jon Bentley</category>
        
        <category>Larry Niven</category>
        
        <category>William of Ockham</category>
        
        <category>C. Northcote Parkinson</category>
        
        <category>Laurence J. Peter</category>
        
        <category>Peter Morley-Souter</category>
        
        <category>Tim Ottinger</category>
        
        <category>Socrates</category>
        
        <category>Theodore Sturgeon</category>
        
        <category>Jack Bergman</category>
        
        <category>Niklaus Wirth</category>
        
        <category>Carlin Vieri</category>
        
        <category>The Ren and Stimpy Show</category>
        
        <category>Bike Shedding</category>
        
        <category>Yak Shaving</category>
        
        <category>Jamie Zawinski</category>
        
        <category>Alberto Brandolini</category>
        
        <category>Joel Spolsky</category>
        
        <category>Robert Metcalfe</category>
        
        <category>Demeter</category>
        
        <category>Ian Holland</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leading People in Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2020/07/road.png&quot; alt=&quot;An image of the road running to the horizon.&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The road ahead.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update, 7/22&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;At the same time I was posting this, Cassie McDaniel published “&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@cassiemc/everyones-sad-and-getting-sadder-c8e6b23e69a5&quot;&gt;Everyone’s Sad and Getting Sadder&lt;/a&gt;”. It wonderfully expresses some of that which I brushed past on the way to solutioning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update, 7/23&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2020/07/microsoft-analyzed-data-on-its-newly-remote-workforce&quot;&gt;Microsoft has published compelling data on new remote work trends&lt;/a&gt;. Revelations include that “managers are enabling employee resilience through this disruption. Employees across our team saw their work hours spike after the shift. But looking at one-on-one meetings, a key connection point in the manager-employee relationship, we found that the employees who averaged the most weekly one-on-one time with their managers experienced the smallest increase in working hours. In short, managers were buffering employees against the negative aspects of the change by helping them prioritize and protect their time.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being responsible for employees is challenging, even in the best of times. It is something else entirely to care for people during simultaneous health, inequality, justice, governance, economic, and education crises caused by Covid-19. We, collectively, are undergoing a transition to &lt;em&gt;something else&lt;/em&gt;. Like with many transitions, there is discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When stressed, fight-or-flight reflexes engage. Our minds brace for an oncoming challenge. However, with this global pandemic, there is no enemy to overcome and no timeline for resolution. We remain on high alert for an all-clear that won’t come. Further, previously simple actions, like going to the grocery store or getting a check-up, are filled with new and unfamiliar processes that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90515519/tech-workers-are-showing-the-effects-of-covid-19-related-burnout&quot;&gt;generate additional micro-bursts of stress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re shadowboxing with history. It is no wonder we’re exhausted each evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your team, dealing with Covid-19 is more than just virtual happy hours and disrupted travel plans. Uncertainty breeds anxiety, no matter what your resilience level was going into this year. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/bill-murphy-jr/want-to-be-a-truly-exceptional-leader-neuroscience-says-do-these-5-simple-things-right-now.html&quot;&gt;About one-third of Americans have exhibited signs of anxiety or depression in the wake of Covid-19&lt;/a&gt;.  And anxiety erodes our energy, patience, and ability to absorb new information. It does so, slowly, at first, but this prolonged experience aggregates into significant mental health concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’m doing to care for my team during these times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-up-lightweight-check-ins-but-let-them-lead&quot;&gt;Keep Up Lightweight Check-ins, But Let Them Lead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This transition requires all of us to process a lot. Even with a great rapport, your co-worker may not have the time, energy, or ability to articulate what they need. Respect your team member’s choice if they aren’t ready to talk. In that case, impress on them that epiphany has no deadline. When they’re ready, you’ll move mountains to meet them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue your regular cadence of check-ins, but let them tell you what they need. Ask a multiple-choice question designed to require as little energy, on their part, as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Just wanted to check-in. Would it be more helpful to keep our one-on-one today, reduce it to 15 minutes, or skip it? I’m happy no matter what— just want to make sure you have what you need.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strike-how-are-you-from-your-opener&quot;&gt;Strike “How Are You?” From Your Opener&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your team member does opt to meet, avoid the weak “How are you?” or “How you doing?” opener. It will, most likely, result in a reflexive “OK”. Instead, prepare questions that will provide additional insight and present more profound opportunities to help. Lara Hogan is a management coach. &lt;a href=&quot;https://larahogan.me/blog/check-in-questions-for-one-on-ones-during-crisis/&quot;&gt;She lists several excellent items appropriate for 1-on-1’s during this time&lt;/a&gt;. Some examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s been working for you so far?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s been the hardest? What’s been the most surprising thing during this time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your north star?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s one thing you want to experiment with right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; questions, check out the Elizabeth Weingarten article, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/work/1836105/20-great-questions-to-ask-instead-of-how-are-you-doing-right-now/&quot;&gt;20 Questions to Ask Instead of ‘How are You Doing?’&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-present&quot;&gt;Be Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve engaged, apply active and &lt;em&gt;empathetic&lt;/em&gt; listening.  Everyone needs something different right now. Don’t presume to know what challenges are occupying your people’s head space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look into the camera rather than sidelong at yourself in the video. Avoid scrolling through email. Close Slack. Turn off text notifications. These meetings are not to bolster your hierarchical imbalance through the zillion alternatives you could do. This time is about them. Catharsis through connection is possible only through focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be able to solve every problem. You shouldn’t attempt to spin what you’re hearing into a silver-lining. &lt;strong&gt;And never, never, invalidate what the individual is thinking or feeling the first time they’re attempting to process, out-loud, what is impacting them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-the-cliches-or-false-bravado&quot;&gt;Avoid the Cliches or False Bravado&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing hope or expressing wishes for the future is one thing. Inauthentic promises or thoughtless chest-beating will create distance from those who have a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a business management playbook filled with cliches. War metaphors, in a time with unprecedented death, ring particularly hollow at this moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Rally the troops.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Let’s win this battle!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This is our fight.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Weaponize this opportunity!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Who’s killing it?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s OK to admit that you might not have answers for a once-in-a-lifetime event. It’s OK if your team isn’t fired up to storm the beaches of Normandy. Admitting “I don’t know” and allowing oneself to be vulnerable goes a long way toward connecting and creating authentic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offer-positive-feedback-and-encouragement&quot;&gt;Offer positive feedback and encouragement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. David Rock, who has a doctoral degree in neuroleadership, says Covid-19 has made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/bill-murphy-jr/want-to-be-a-truly-exceptional-leader-neuroscience-says-do-these-5-simple-things-right-now.html&quot;&gt;people hyper-sensitive to their standing&lt;/a&gt;. Through this filter, normally benign questions are now interpreted as negative or even discouraging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proceed thoughtfully. Instead of asking, “Why is your delivery late?”, which may be inferred as a personal attack, reframe it as, “What’s happening with this project?” It’s not about lowering expectations or letting performance slide. This shift in language is about acknowledging the sensitive spot people are in and reducing anxiety, not making it worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;strive-to-create-certainty&quot;&gt;Strive to Create Certainty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambiguity heightens stress. The more variables you can remove from employees’ lives right now, the better. Lara Hogan has another piece on &lt;a href=&quot;https://larahogan.me/blog/predictability-stability-terrible-times/&quot;&gt;Creating Predictability and Stability in Times of Rapid Change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One approach for creating certainty is sharing information. Sharing helps create certainty and builds trust, even if that news isn’t always positive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/savvy-parenting/201406/when-parents-lie&quot;&gt;Research shows that children can deal with almost any disappointment if provided with appropriate support. However, if children feel that they were lied to, they will act out&lt;/a&gt;. Similar dynamics exist between a leader and their team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;accept-were-all-human-in-a-crisis&quot;&gt;Accept We’re All Human in a Crisis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/seven-rules-of-zoom-meeting-etiquette-from-the-pros-11594551601?mod=e2tw&quot;&gt;A recent Wall-Street Journal article called for a return to an idealized professional esthetic&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No more dogs, chips or lurkers — as video-conferencing becomes a fixture in working life, it’s time to shed the rookie moves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps if everyone had chosen their current work predicament, I’d agree. However, not everyone has the optimized quiet place. We’re all distracted, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowingdata.com/2020/07/13/parenting-and-work-schedule-during-the-pandemic/&quot;&gt;doing the best we can with those we’re surrounded with&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;who are also going through a thing&lt;/em&gt;. We’re humans in a crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-asserting workplace norms adds undue performative expectations on those already struggling. When we feel like we have no control or choices, even a small stress becomes overwhelming. Leaders should offer unexpected autonomy and flexibility. Relax the always-on camera requirements. Or forgive the hastily assembled lunch on the part of a busy parent. And honor those aspects of human experience - delivery person interruption, pets barking, kids video-bombing - that remind us these aren’t just workplaces, but our lives co-opted into a global event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-care-of-yourself-too&quot;&gt;Take Care of Yourself, Too&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your employees aren’t the only ones dealing with volatile levels of attention and energy. Your reserves are also being siphoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To best serve them, it is vital you’re managing yourself. That may mean not scheduling the back-to-back-to-back marathon meetings that you’d typically be able to do. It may mean saying no or pulling back on worthwhile, yet not primary, initiatives. It might mean being an example and figuring out how staycations work, not because you need more time at home, but because you’re illustrating how important mental breaks are for the marathon we’re running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relationships rooted in psychological safety are like an oak tree: the best time to plant them was years ago. The second best time is now. If you haven’t spent the time to cultivate trust, your employees are less likely to share what they’re struggling with. That makes it harder to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that people choose to lead will be remembered for years to come. Some leaders are just trying to command through goal setting and stretching people to their limits. Then there will those exhibiting empathy, making sure that people feel heard and are taken care of for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be that latter type of leader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/07/22/LeadingPeopleInCrisis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2020/07/22/LeadingPeopleInCrisis/</guid>
        
        <category>people management</category>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>Capital One</category>
        
        <category>Lara Hogan</category>
        
        <category>David Rock</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
