<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
    <description>This is the website for Matthew Reinbold, the Director for Capital One's   Platform Services Center of Excellence. I also write the 'Net API Notes' email  newsletter and curate NetAPI.events. Much of what appears here dated prior to 2017 was  previously published at VoxPop.co and VoxPopDesign.com. There's also a bit  of legacy detritus from older experiments like mutednoise.com,  miltiantgeek.com, codeaway.org, etc. Adult fan of Lego. And trying to make Dakota Gothic a thing. 
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 08:25:45 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 08:25:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>APIs and Digital Transformation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/05/digital-midi-controller.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Digital Midi Controller&quot;, Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/jUwvjOmCTWc&quot;&gt;Luca Bravo on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Bill Doerrfeld interviewed me for a piece that appeared on the Adobe CMO blog entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmo.com/features/articles/2019/5/13/entering-the-platform-economy-why-apis-and-integrations-are-crucial.html&quot;&gt;The Platform Economy: Why APIs And Integrations Are Crucial&lt;/a&gt;”. As usual, I ended up preparing &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more than what eneded up on the final piece. An sampling of my expanded responses is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my Net API Notes email newsletter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/api-academy-and-new-beginnings-net-api-notes-for-2019-01-31&quot;&gt;I talked about the changing API space&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. Hopefully that, as well as the answers below, provide some clarity for executive leadership on how the landscape is evolving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-the-current-state-of-the-api-economy&quot;&gt;What the current state of the API economy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The API economy, however it is defined, is in a state of transition. For the last several years companies have limited, or even shuttered, their “open” developer in favor of explicit partner-to-partner relationships. From, most recently, Lyft, to Venmo, Facebook, and Twitter, companies that aren’t perusing an explicit platform strategy have significantly changed how they think about the strategic potential for APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of factors have driven this. On the one hand, I see an end to companies who released public APIs with a “build it, and they will come” philosophy. Without a vision of how corralling 3rd party developers would bolster a company’s strategic execution, these developer portals were cost centers primed for elimination as soon as the platform fervor passed. (For some comprehensive thinking on the role of software platforms, I’ve been enjoying “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Platform-Ecosystems-Aligning-Architecture-Governance/dp/0124080669/ref=sr_1_3&quot;&gt;Platform Ecosystems: Aligning Architecture, Governance, and Strategy&lt;/a&gt;” by Amrit Tiwana.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, I see companies increasingly aware of their expanded risk profile due to public API access. Even with robust security, and the API is behaving as intended, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-04-11&quot;&gt;the Cambridge-Analytica scandal awakened many&lt;/a&gt;. We now see how the seemingly benign exchange and aggregation of information can have huge ramifications. Simply “putting something out there” not only can be expensive, but it has consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that’s a footnote in the larger story. The more significant economic impact of APIs is how companies are using them to achieve greater marketplace agility. It’s the internal decomposition - the reduction coupling and coordination overhead - where the real digital transformation lies. The economic benefit from Netflix’s API approach is not from the developer program (something they ended in 2014). Highly modular architecture allows experiences, powered by APIs, everywhere on everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-have-apis-historically-disrupted-digital-business-how-will-platform-platform-integrations-continue-to-evolve&quot;&gt;How have APIs historically disrupted digital business? How will platform-platform integrations continue to evolve?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APIs have had, and will continue to have, an out-sized effect on reshaping the cultures of the companies that truly adopt them. Whether it is adoption of the “infrastructure as code” and CI/CD pipelines necessary to efficiently deploy them, or the rearrangement of teams to support bounded context modularity (the “reverse Conway maneuver”), APIs challenge existing organizational and operational structures. (For more information exploring the cultural implecations of APIs, please see the writeup of my conference talk, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2018/10/31/Gardeners-Approach/&quot;&gt;A Gardner’s Approach to Growing an API Culture&lt;/a&gt;”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’ll see is a continued diversification of useful interactions patterns beyond HTTP’s traditional request/response model. The need for real-time workflows will necessitate investment in, and understanding of things like webhooks (also referred to as callbacks or subscriptions), websockets, and more. The interest in machine learning, along with a greater emphasis on storing and leveraging data, will necessitate more ‘algorithms-as-a-service’ APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-apis-be-used-in-b2b-partner-strategies&quot;&gt;How can APIs be used in B2B partner strategies?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More businesses realize the impact data, not only theirs but others, can have on their operations. The responsible exchange of this data is critical. APIs make organizing and managing these partnerships more easily possible due to the wide variety of proven technologies. Everything “speaks” HTTP, securing and monitoring API gateways have vetted playbooks and standards (like OAuth), and there’s a mature talent pool available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-the-major-takeaways-for-cmos--ctos&quot;&gt;What are the major takeaways for CMOs &amp;amp; CTOs?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical leadership is experiencing pressure from all directions. To one side, they are expected to deliver impactful digital transformation to compete in the future marketplace. Simultaneously, they have to meet new (and growing) data governance expectations. APIs, with their standardization of message exchange and centralized points of control, can play an essential role in both objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/06/APIs-and-Digital-Transformation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/05/06/APIs-and-Digital-Transformation/</guid>
        
        <category>digital transformation</category>
        
        <category>APIs</category>
        
        <category>OpenAPI</category>
        
        <category>AsyncAPI</category>
        
        <category>OAuth</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Plan for Continuous Learning and Win Sharing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/05/open-notebook.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Laptop and notepad&quot; by Nick Morrison on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/FHnnjk1Yj7Y&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most at Capital One, my team is currently busy with &lt;em&gt;talent management&lt;/em&gt; activities. Rather than being a backward-looking review of work previous done, talent management is forward looking. When done correctly, it produces honest conversations about each’s professional ambitions. Those ambitions, subsequently, are then &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2014/01/23/SystemsNotGoals/&quot;&gt;deconstructed into the repeatable systems necessary to produce accumulating wins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A significant component of &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; talent management plan is &lt;strong&gt;continuous learning&lt;/strong&gt;. That learning could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online coursework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grokking Books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professional Organization Participation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experimenting with new technologies and techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there’s no shortage of resources, what is in short supply is time to make it happen. A challenge, for all too many managers, is supporting ongoing learning goals not just in lip service, but with meaningful scheduling. It’s great to say you’re investing in team development. It is another thing to foist the raised expectations on an employee’s outside-of-work time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I instituted a new, dedicated “continuous learning’ plan with my team. Every &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; Friday is reserved for team members to focus on their learning objectives. (I created two cohorts, each of which is staggered with each other’s Fridays so that there’s still a subset engaged with our stakeholder communities.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members track their progress via a card in our Trello system stating how their work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contributes to the company’s mission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progresses them toward their talent management objective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will be shared with a larger group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Win sharing” is a critical component of continuous learning&lt;/strong&gt;. Once a month, the team will get together to discuss what worked and what didn’t. I expect there to be surprises. There will be those pursuits that don’t pan out as expected. However, it remains a “win” if the team member not only discovers that new insight but shares it for the benefit of the larger group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all busy. I anticipate the biggest criticism of this proposal is whether the Center of Excellence can take 10% of our time and devote it to something other than processing team submissions for review. In my perspective, however, I don’t know how we can afford &lt;em&gt;not to&lt;/em&gt;. Technology moves fast. Things that were prudent even only a year ago may be persnickety today. One of the core pillars of the CoE activity is to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2017/10/03/API-Governance-Blueprint/&quot;&gt;define healthy ecosystems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Understanding the technology landscape to guide others across it requires a continuous investment in ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than being a tax on our time, I view this as a calculated investment our talent growth, relevance, and retention. In setting this continuous learning plan, we’ve also created a forcing function. We create the habit by reserving the space and observing the ritual. If that means we need to be more efficient in our other work to meet current expectations, then so be it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, this is subject to change. We may try this for a few months and, with some initial learning, reformat our whole approach. Much like the individual experiments, using the experience to inform refinement our approach is a win. The only way we lose is if we never bother to try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/06/ContinuousLearningAndWinSharing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/05/06/ContinuousLearningAndWinSharing/</guid>
        
        <category>continuous learning</category>
        
        <category>win sharing</category>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>talent management</category>
        
        <category>Capital One</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diffusion of Innovation, Digital Transformation, and Dynamic Systems Theory</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/04/foggy-bridge.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A bridge through the fog.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the crudeness of the phrase, I consume a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of online content. The internet is awash in things to pass the time. Most of it is crap, the mental equivalent of cotton candy. However, there are a handful of talks that I continue to return to. They are the ones that, even after years, I highlight in presentations and compare and contrast with new information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a selection of some of my foundational references. Hopefully, you’ll find them as influential as I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-design-a-good-api-and-why-it-matters-by-joshua-bloch-google-tech-talks-2007&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Design a Good API and Why it Matters&lt;/em&gt;, by Joshua Bloch, Google Tech Talks (2007)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written some form of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/netapinotes/&quot;&gt;Net API Notes Email Newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for the past several years. In that time, I’ve reviewed &lt;em&gt;gobs&lt;/em&gt; of API-related content. However, &lt;strong&gt;I have yet to come across another piece which as powerfully states the importance of great API design, and what it is, like this video&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joshua rightly argues that good API Design is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to Learn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to Use, Even Without Supplemental Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hard to Misuse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to Read and Maintain Code that Uses It&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sufficiently Powerful to Satisfy Requirements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to Evolve&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appropriate to the Audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kicker here is that Joshua isn’t even talking about web, or net, APIs. The APIs he is talking about are lower-level, intra-language interfaces. However, the fact that these things continue to apply to other contexts is a testament to the universality of the message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=heh4OeB9A-c&quot;&gt;How to Design a Good API and Why it Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meeting-resistance-and-moving-forward-by-linda-rising-goto-conference-2017&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meeting Resistance and Moving Forward&lt;/em&gt;, by Linda Rising, GOTO Conference (2017)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having lived (survived?) through several digital transformation efforts, each with various degrees of success, I have an appreciation for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diffusion_of_innovations&quot;&gt;diffusion of innovation theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The theory outlines “the process by which an innovation is communicated over time among the participants in a social system”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Said another way, a disruptive change, like those brought about by digital transformation, is adopted by different audiences at different rates. Subsequent research has shown that &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; changing population breaks down into the same percentages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovators (2.5%): Will something for no other reason than it is new&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Early Adopters (13.5%): More discrete in their selections than innovators, adopters use status as early pioneers to maintain social credibility with their peer group while taking on less risk (cutting verses bleeding edge)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Early Majority (34%): Willing to adopt innovations, but only after seeing what success with the innovation looks like among their peers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Late Majority (34%): Are loath to adopt the innovation unless specifically told they have to, after which they require higher levels of support and encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laggards (16%): Those who actively resist change, and will actively work to thwart an innovation for no other reason that it is new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be warned: the opening five-ten minutes to Linda Rising’s talk is rambling and referential to the events at the time; &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2016/12/27/EmpathyForAll/&quot;&gt;many were still attempting to process the results of the 2016 presidential election&lt;/a&gt;. However, when you scrub past that, you get a wonderful insight into people’s relationship with technology. Any change agent attempting big things, &lt;em&gt;at scale&lt;/em&gt;, needs this foundational awareness before developing their strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DrCD1wmK9oM&quot;&gt;Meeting Resistance and Moving Forward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seeing-whole-systems-by-nicky-case-the-long-now-foundation-2017&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seeing Whole Systems&lt;/em&gt;, by Nicky Case, The Long Now Foundation (2017)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software governance at enterprise scale is tricky. To explain reoccurring phenomenon, I had to expand my research beyond typical software fare. Donella H. Meadows &lt;em&gt;“Thinking in Systems”&lt;/em&gt;, and related systems dynamics education, has been incredibly relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software environment in most companies is a complex, dynamic system. A defining characteristic of a complex system is that the behavior cannot be understood by knowing about the individual components. There is not a linear relationship between a top-down mandate and the desired outcome. A complex system will exhibit &lt;strong&gt;emergent behavior&lt;/strong&gt; when nudged; behavior that is always unexpected, and sometimes undesirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is one thing to realize you’re a participant in (or victim of?) a complex system. A logical next step is identifying what to do about it. Nicky Case’s video on &lt;em&gt;Seeing Whole Systems&lt;/em&gt; goes into that detail. Nicky, correctly, articulates how too much of governance thinking presumes clear causality between actions and outcomes. This is the mentality of “something bad happened, so we’ll create a rule to prevent the bad thing from happening”. Instead of edicts or directives, Nicky demonstrates how virtuous feedback loops (either positive or negative) can work on a dynamic system over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://longnow.org/seminars/02017/aug/07/seeing-whole-systems/&quot;&gt;Seeing Whole Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a brief, first list of references that I return to regularly. If folks find this useful or know of related material I should check out, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/18/OtherLessonsToLearnFrom01/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/18/OtherLessonsToLearnFrom01/</guid>
        
        <category>API Governance</category>
        
        <category>Nicky Case</category>
        
        <category>system dynamics</category>
        
        <category>Linda Rising</category>
        
        <category>diffusion of innovation</category>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        <category>Joshua Block</category>
        
        <category>API Design</category>
        
        <category>digital transformation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>APIs, Specifications, and Pedantry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent edition of my newsletter, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/net-api-notes-for-2019-02-25-1&quot;&gt;Net API Notes&lt;/a&gt;, I finished with an off-the-cuff remark about hating how one term was used interchangeably for another. If I said chaos ensued, I would be making a gross overstatement. However, it was, despite the numerous pointed and carefully crafted statements that I make on an ongoing basis, the thing that people responded to the most to in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludwig Wittgenstein was an Austrian-British philosopher. His is, perhaps, most famous for inspiring the phrase “&lt;strong&gt;language is use&lt;/strong&gt;”. To explain what that means, &lt;a href=&quot;http://existentialcomics.com/comic/268&quot;&gt;here is a snippet from everyone’s favorite technical companion, &lt;em&gt;Existential Comics&lt;/em&gt;, explaining why a hot dog is not a sandwich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/02/hotdog.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Finally, an answer to whether a hotdog is a sandwich (&lt;a href=&quot;http://existentialcomics.com/comic/268&quot;&gt;be sure to read the whole thing, too&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the comic explains, we can pick apart the semantics of a term any of a thousand ways. We can debate the taxonomy, history, and context. We can make inferences and wring our hands over future outcomes, both seen and unseen. And, as Wittgenstein argued, all of that is irrelevant if it isn’t how &lt;em&gt;people use the language&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my time doing API governance, I’ve seen thousands of what I’ve come to call “&lt;em&gt;API descriptions&lt;/em&gt;”. I use this term to disambiguate between many things that get mushed together. If a team says they “need help with &lt;strong&gt;their API&lt;/strong&gt;,” they could be referring to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the code that implements some business functionality, exposed through a standardized interface (usually over HTTP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an endpoint (the unique combination of URI and method [as wrong as it is to refer to a single endpoint as an API, it does happen])&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the collection of endpoints that comprise the bounded context as defined by the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the affordances made possible by their work, and the work itself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the file or artifact that articulates the business intent provided by that interface (written to a specified standard like OpenAPI, AsyncAPI, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the documentation of all of the above, and source code, mock data, CI/CD pipeline, and key registration shenanigans necessary to create a pleasurable Time-to-Hello-World (or TTHW) experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the right terminology for all this stuff? Unfortunately, Wittgenstein can’t help us settle this debate. The way people use language is all over the place. The way they use ‘API’ (and related terms) is not the way we talk about hotdogs. There isn’t one, singular cultural understanding that we could point to and say “this is the one way”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To aid comprehension, I’ve adopted the following language model. It doesn’t mean that this is the right way. As the famous George Box quote goes, “all models are wrong, but some are useful”. When somebody says they have a problem with their API, I ask questions to clarify which of the following things, in my mental model, they are referring to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Specification&lt;/strong&gt; - A technical standard, like OpenAPI 3.0, that defines how to describe an API’s interface in a general, broadly applicable way that is both a machine-parsable and human-readable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Description&lt;/strong&gt; - A file articulating a single API’s interface that fulfills the requirements and expectations of an API specification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Interface&lt;/strong&gt; - The obvious or described (and, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hyrumslaw.com/&quot;&gt;Hyrum’s law&lt;/a&gt;, not so obvious) means to communicate with a set of functionality within a system.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Implementation/Code&lt;/strong&gt; - The gobbledygook created by software developers necessary to accomplish a business function to be exposed via an interface.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Executable/Deployable&lt;/strong&gt; - The version of code that is promoted to a live environment and responding to production requests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Documentation&lt;/strong&gt; - The collection of things necessary to convey sufficient meaning so that clients can successfully use the deployed API through the interface. This includes, but is not limited to, the API Description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my model. It works for me but if you’re comfortable with a different set of terms, great! As long as those that interact with you regularly share the same model, communication is happening with the least amount of cognitive overhead as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/02/thug-life.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;I wake up every day with a mission to be this baller.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading that, I know what you’re thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If this is your model, and people having different models is ok, why did you say ‘it drives me &lt;em&gt;crazy&lt;/em&gt; that they refer to these documents as “specifications”’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problem, particularly with vendors, is when the language is imprecise. I chafe when words are used interchangeably, often without disregard. Sometimes it is even on purpose, a targeted erosion of discourse in order to make a sale. I hate when words become less about clear communication and more about memetic highjacking, attempting to associate, expand, and/or co-opt organic phenomena in the pursuit of shipping product. That’s how a useful term is rendered all but meaningless (see ‘AJAX’, circa 2005 to 2008, or what is happening to ‘microservices’ now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a model, and using it consistently, implies there is a certain amount of thought and rigor put into coexisting with your fellow folks. Words mean things, dammit, and the time you invest in your words is time invested in helping communicate meaning to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other way, best case, is lazy. Worst case, its calculated obfuscation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/27/APIsandPedantry/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/27/APIsandPedantry/</guid>
        
        <category>Ludwig Wittgenstein</category>
        
        <category>language</category>
        
        <category>hotdogs</category>
        
        <category>Hyrum's law</category>
        
        <category>ajax</category>
        
        <category>microservices</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Manager README for Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2019/02/jigsaw.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Management is, to some degree, figuring out how all the pieces fit.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screaminginthecloud.com/episodes/2019/1/2/episode-43-heres-a-document-on-how-to-best-deal-with-my-foibles&quot;&gt;a recent episode of the Screaming in the Cloud podcast&lt;/a&gt;, host Cory Quinn interviewed Etsy’s Matt Newkirk. They discussed the value of a &lt;strong&gt;‘Manager README’&lt;/strong&gt; document. There has been a long tradition of README documents in software development. However, typically those files contain information about a program. This podcast was the first time I had ever heard about one for &lt;em&gt;managers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer they discussed the usefulness, the more I realized that I needed to create one for my team. Since becoming a people manager at Capital One (and having gone through several rounds of hiring folks), I know valuable information isn’t always shared during on-boarding. I also know that just commenting on these things in passing, during the fire-hose of other new-hire information, only adds to the stress and anxiety of a delicate period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done well, a Manager README can be a helpful and proactive piece of content. It prompts conversations, sets the context, and serves as a “living reference” for team cultural norms. Here’s what I put together for my first attempt. Did I miss anything? Is there something that is unclear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, is this something that you do within your organization? Let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-and-welcome-to-my-team&quot;&gt;Hello, and Welcome to My Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Howdy! My name is Matthew, and I’m thrilled to have you on the team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get a tremendous amount of information in the coming months. This is a big place, with a lot going on &lt;em&gt;at tremendous speed&lt;/em&gt;. It may feel overwhelming. Know that (1) that is entirely normal, (2) it may take several months (or more!) to feel on top of things, and (3) your newness can be a superpower!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-this-a-manager-readme&quot;&gt;What is this? A ‘Manager README’?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Manager README is a way to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Describe My Approach to Managing You&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer Some Questions (and Raise Some You May Not Have Previously Thought Of)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect you to memorize this document. I don’t even expect you to read it given the vast amount of other onboarding things currently happening. But it is here when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-this-document-isnt&quot;&gt;What this document &lt;em&gt;isn’t&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document isn’t a list of my personality quirks. Or the cliff notes guide to getting a promotion. Or where to find the free food. There is a time and a place for each of those things. But not here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Matthew Reinbold. I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter stream&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewreinbold&quot;&gt;LinkedIn profile&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/netapinotes/archive&quot;&gt;API newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, among other things. Since starting my professional career in 1999, I’ve worked as a software developer, tester, architect, community builder, and product manager. That work has included everything from small startups to companies including IBM, Microsoft, and Adobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love well-crafted storytelling and have a passion for business strategy. I am a visual learner. I do not drink but don’t mind hanging out with those that do. While I can be comfortable in social situations, I may prefer to be alone when I need to re-energize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-approach-to-managing-you&quot;&gt;My Approach to Managing You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-being-your-manager-means-to-me&quot;&gt;What Being Your Manager Means to Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;job&lt;/strong&gt;, at a minimum, is to attract, retain, and grow world-class talent for the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I do something that negatively impacts my ability to retain you, you would be doing me a huge favor if you let me know about it, as soon as possible. Likewise, if I do something that feels more like telling you how to do your job than setting context, also let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe everyone has things they can get better at. We hired you because of your positive traits. I’m excited to work with you to continue to grow those traits, as well as help you discover and refine new ones in the course of working together. In the process, I hope to become your biggest advocate to the rest of the company!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-we-communicate&quot;&gt;How We Communicate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous conversation channels at our disposal: Skype, Slack, Hangouts, Trello, etc. However, I treat those as ephemeral; because of the volume of commentary, I don’t tend to go back and read any missed history. If you send an email, it will be seen (&lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt;). If you want to ensure that I see what you have to say, send it to me in an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an issue which requires my immediate attention and I’m not immediately available, the best channel to reach me is via text message. I will do my best to respond promptly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise to do my best to avoid emailing or texting over the weekend or in the evenings. If I do contact you, it is either to convey breaking, important information or a pressing thought has just occurred to me. I &lt;strong&gt;do not expect that you should work outside of regular work hours&lt;/strong&gt;. Unless I say that things are URGENT, it can always wait until we’re back in the office on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-availability&quot;&gt;My Availability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings can seem like a way of life. My calendar is no exception. It may seem intimidating to schedule something with me. However, my direct reports come first. If there is an urgent need and there doesn’t appear to be an available upcoming time, send me a text message (see above). I do my best to accommodate you at the first available moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-i-follow-up&quot;&gt;How I Follow Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in software governance, we are called on to make difficult calls on regularly. I have 100% faith and confidence that you will make the best decision given your professional experience, your expectations, and the information available at that moment. That is why I hired you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be times when I will contact you to revisit that decision. I may have questions. I may ask for additional nuance. When this happens, it isn’t because I am second guessing your judgment. Rather, what is much more likely happening is that I am attempting to gather the necessary context to explain the action to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviewing past work and ensuring that it holds up under inspection is a healthy thing. It is how I learn from you. Do not mistake this as looking to assign blame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11s&quot;&gt;1:1s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will schedule a dedicated, bi-monthly meeting for a half hour between us. This is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; time to ask questions about what you’ve seen/heard/read and talk about your concerns. &lt;strong&gt;You set the agenda&lt;/strong&gt;. It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to deliver a status update to me unless you want to update status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of these meetings is to give you a chance to be heard. I am a big believer in &lt;a href=&quot;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-update-the-vent-and-the-disaster/&quot;&gt;Michael Lopp’s approach to this time&lt;/a&gt;. When I ask “How are you?” you can take that whichever direction you feel is appropriate. I’m still learning how to be better at this and thank you in advance for your patience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will, to the best of my ability, try to maintain the same time for this meeting so that it becomes habitual. However, there may be times when there’s a conflict that can’t be avoided. When those situations arise, I (or my admin) will do our best to reschedule within the same week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-things-about-how-we-work&quot;&gt;Important things About How We Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;worklife-balance&quot;&gt;Work/Life Balance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not track hours in the office. I, also, do not believe that “clocking-in” at a specific hour is the key to productivity. I don’t hand out kudos just because you are in before I am. Likewise, I don’t keep points on who is still in the office when I leave. I trust you will put in the necessary time to do a good job. I also believe you are an adult capable of balancing your professional and private obligations. If you have an outside commitment during the workday, however, I ask that you let the team, including me, know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, if you take time off (illness, vacation, etc.), I ask that you give the entire team as much heads-up as possible. We do this by sending a calendar to the team inviting them to your ‘OOO’ (out of office) event. The first few times it may feel odd inviting your teammates to your time off. However, I’ve found, it is a lightweight way of keeping folks in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be cases, like associates in California, where time off needs to be accurately tracked. In those cases, I expect that you accurately record your hours worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fridays are work-from-home days. You are free to come into the office these days. However, most on my team take advantage of this perk to avoid lengthy commutes and concentrate their “deep focus” work. On these days I maintain a weekly team meeting where we discuss common challenges and share information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I feel that this approach is being abused and is negatively impacting the team’s ability to deliver, I will talk to you about it. Together, we’ll figure out how to arrive at the appropriate balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disagreements-are-valuable-arguments-are-not&quot;&gt;Disagreements are Valuable. Arguments are Not&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve hired you, in part, because you are a different person than I am. You have your own values, experience, education, and ambition that is different than mine. Your uniqueness reinforces in some spots, and supplement gaps in others. When combined together, our productive sum can be greater than the sum of the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because I am your manager &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; mean that you should defer to me without question. I ask for your input, not your fealty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of those differences, there may be times when we disagree. Some even might be substantive and ongoing. That is completely normal. What can’t happen is for an argument to occur. This is when discussions get emotional, even heated and feelings can be hurt. When that happens, either one of us can ask for each other to take a step back, with a promise to circle back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be times when consensus is not possible at the moment. Despite the lack of alignment, a way forward is needed. In those times I will rely on my best judgment given all available information. If I make a call counter to your recommended guidance, it is not personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;putting-your-feedback-to-work&quot;&gt;Putting Your Feedback to Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback is critical for anyone to get better. If you provide feedback for me during our time together, I do my best to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a safe environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sharing easy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a positive outcome from what is shared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could do any of these things better, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transparency-candor-and-discretion&quot;&gt;Transparency, Candor, and Discretion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a high bias toward authenticity and candor.  However, there may be situations (for example, an ongoing strategic discussion or pending external opportunity) that I may not be able to discuss. I may be limited in what I can share in situations where you are not in a position to influence the outcome. If things have not yet been decided, I may defer the conversation rather than conjecturing. I may say that I can’t talk about something at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be times when I say “I don’t know.” I guarantee that I don’t have all the answers. But if it matters to you, I promise to work with you to find one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-value&quot;&gt;What I Value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minding the details can be the difference between incredible success and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mars_Climate_Orbiter&quot;&gt;a 327 million dollar failure&lt;/a&gt;. Solving the immediate problem is the most important thing, whether that is putting together a persuasive presentation, responding to an email question, or consulting with a team. However, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; the problem is solved is where the attention to detail can pay dividends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aggregation-of-marginal-gains&quot;&gt;Aggregation of Marginal Gains&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in the compounding benefit of continually fixing small things; if you say something more than once, write it down, share it, and point to it later. Over time, those references add up to a significant amount of saved time. Furthermore, at the end of the year, you’ll have a body of work to point to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, your job security is not dependent on how busy we are (or appear to be). We should continuously be looking for ways (processes, tools, collaborations with other groups) that make us more efficient. Reducing the tedium from our activities without harming outcomes means we free ourselves for more professionally rewarding opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on this, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/10/how-1-performance-improvements-led-to-olympic-gold&quot;&gt;Aggregation of Marginal Gains Theory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;meeting-acumen&quot;&gt;Meeting Acumen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be courteous to your fellow associates. Show respect by being on time for meetings. If possible, schedule meetings so that they end five minutes before the top (or bottom) of the hour to allow people to start their following sessions on time. Figure out the best configuration for your remote meeting software and practice it. State what the specific outcome is for any meeting scheduled. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindtools.com/CommSkll/RunningMeetings.htm&quot;&gt;There are lots more useful tips for running successful meetings&lt;/a&gt;; while applying every tool every single time is a bit much, being adept with the basics will carry you far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;presentation-skills&quot;&gt;Presentation Skills&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slide presentations (or “decks”) are a critical part of Capital One culture. They are the primary means of socializing ideas. Some assume that slides are inferior to other ways of sharing information. Creating powerful and persuasive arguments is possible. The problem is that many reach a basic level of proficiency and never advance beyond it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may feel as though you’ve got this talking thing down cold; you were hired, in part, for your communication skills. In the same way a skilled craftsman selects and applies the specific tool to a job, however, you should also see this as an opportunity to attune your skill set for this particular audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creation of a successful deck, particularly accounting for ‘Capital One style’, is beyond the scope of this document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it just kind of stops… so far. I envision this being a work in process. If you were working for me, what kinds of things about having me as your manager would you want to know? What things are missing? I’d love to get your opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/14/AManagerREADME/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/14/AManagerREADME/</guid>
        
        <category>management</category>
        
        <category>etsy</category>
        
        <category>Matt NewKirk</category>
        
        <category>Cory Quinn</category>
        
        <category>Capital One</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>! &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There's plenty of API hoot and nanny to cover. However, I take a moment to highlight not only some recent accomplishments, but thank readers for their time and attention. And there is also a colorful summation of Thanksgiving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you're in the United States, this email probably finds you either in transit or in preparation (or both!) for the Thanksgiving holiday. It is a time that is associated with indulgent shopping, strained family conversations, and overeating while the Detroit Lions find less entertaining ways to lose.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-thanksgiving-special-2018-11-21&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-thanksgiving-special-2018-11-21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2019/01/24/NetAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2019/01/24/NetAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>Net API Notes</category>
        
        <category>Mike Ralphson</category>
        
        <category>Mark Nottingham</category>
        
        <category>W3C</category>
        
        <category>Google</category>
        
        <category>API Days</category>
        
        <category>Matthieu Breen</category>
        
        <category>Daniel Jacobson</category>
        
        <category>experience layer</category>
        
        <category>Ruben Verborgh</category>
        
        <category>solid ecosystem</category>
        
        <category>JSON-LD</category>
        
        <category>Laure Jouffre</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>Simon Wardley</category>
        
        <category>Richardson Maturity Model</category>
        
        <category>Christian Posta</category>
        
        <category>API Gateway</category>
        
        <category>API Management</category>
        
        <category>Kin Lane</category>
        
        <category>Dredd</category>
        
        <category>OpenAPI</category>
        
        <category>Zdenek Nemec</category>
        
        <category>SuperModel.io</category>
        
        <category>Fran Mendez</category>
        
        <category>AsyncAPI</category>
        
        <category>Kafka</category>
        
        <category>Kong</category>
        
        <category>Mashape</category>
        
        
        <category>newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>! &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Running the numbers for the year:
43% growth in subscribers
31 email newsletters published
and 21,571 words written&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for a fantastic year of REST #API Notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's plenty of API hoot and nanny to cover. However, I take a moment to highlight not only some recent accomplishments, but thank readers for their time and attention. And there is also a colorful summation of Thanksgiving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you're in the United States, this email probably finds you either in transit or in preparation (or both!) for the Thanksgiving holiday. It is a time that is associated with indulgent shopping, strained family conversations, and overeating while the Detroit Lions find less entertaining ways to lose.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-28&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-28&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/28/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/28/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST API Notes</category>
        
        <category>gRPC</category>
        
        <category>GraphQL</category>
        
        <category>Guardian</category>
        
        <category>MongoDB</category>
        
        <category>Postgres</category>
        
        <category>GeoPlaces</category>
        
        <category>Pitney Bowes</category>
        
        <category>Bing</category>
        
        <category>Facebook</category>
        
        <category>AirBnB</category>
        
        
        <category>newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>! &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A piece describing AirBnB’s microservice journey by Jessica Tai, an incredibly useful guide on orchestration v choreography from Bern Ruecker, and more gems of guidance from Phil Sturgeon on health routes. This and more in the latest REST API notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's plenty of API hoot and nanny to cover. However, I take a moment to highlight not only some recent accomplishments, but thank readers for their time and attention. And there is also a colorful summation of Thanksgiving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you're in the United States, this email probably finds you either in transit or in preparation (or both!) for the Thanksgiving holiday. It is a time that is associated with indulgent shopping, strained family conversations, and overeating while the Detroit Lions find less entertaining ways to lose.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-14-1&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-14-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/14/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/14/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST API Notes</category>
        
        <category>AirBnB</category>
        
        <category>InfoQ</category>
        
        <category>Jessica Tai</category>
        
        <category>microservices</category>
        
        <category>orchestration</category>
        
        <category>Bernd Rücker</category>
        
        <category>Phil Sturgeon</category>
        
        <category>gRPC</category>
        
        <category>Kubernetes</category>
        
        <category>Hashicorp</category>
        
        <category>Cambridge-Analytica</category>
        
        <category>Facebook</category>
        
        <category>Google</category>
        
        <category>Google+</category>
        
        <category>REST Fest</category>
        
        
        <category>newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>! &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this edition, I look at “Consumer-Driven APIs” with a talk by Mark W. Foster, cover that “Post-#REST” piece that made the rounds in the past few months, and sprint through a whole heap of notes. That and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's plenty of API hoot and nanny to cover. However, I take a moment to highlight not only some recent accomplishments, but thank readers for their time and attention. And there is also a colorful summation of Thanksgiving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you're in the United States, this email probably finds you either in transit or in preparation (or both!) for the Thanksgiving holiday. It is a time that is associated with indulgent shopping, strained family conversations, and overeating while the Detroit Lions find less entertaining ways to lose.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-03&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-for-2018-12-03&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/03/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/12/03/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST API Notes</category>
        
        <category>Mark Foster</category>
        
        <category>Consumer-Driven</category>
        
        <category>Tim Bray</category>
        
        <category>GraphQL</category>
        
        <category>gRPC</category>
        
        <category>eventing</category>
        
        <category>ThoughtWorks</category>
        
        <category>Technology Radar</category>
        
        <category>ESB</category>
        
        <category>Kafka</category>
        
        <category>microservices</category>
        
        <category>API Gateway</category>
        
        <category>USPS</category>
        
        <category>POSTMan</category>
        
        <category>OpenAPI</category>
        
        <category>Palantir</category>
        
        <category>Conjure</category>
        
        <category>Sebastian Caceres</category>
        
        
        <category>newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Newsletter Thanksgiving Special! &amp;#x2709;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There's plenty of API hoot and nanny to cover. However, I take a moment to highlight not only some recent accomplishments, but thank readers for their time and attention. And there is also a colorful summation of Thanksgiving:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you're in the United States, this email probably finds you either in transit or in preparation (or both!) for the Thanksgiving holiday. It is a time that is associated with indulgent shopping, strained family conversations, and overeating while the Detroit Lions find less entertaining ways to lose.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the web version of the newsletter email here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-thanksgiving-special-2018-11-21&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/letters/rest-api-notes-thanksgiving-special-2018-11-21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past editions of the newsletter can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive&quot;&gt;http://tinyletter.com/NetAPINotes/archive﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive list of upcoming web events that I maintain can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://webapi.events&quot;&gt;webapi.events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/11/21/RESTAPINotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/newsletter/2018/11/21/RESTAPINotes/</guid>
        
        <category>REST API Notes</category>
        
        <category>thanksgiving</category>
        
        <category>NFL</category>
        
        
        <category>newsletter</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
