<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:44:28 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:44:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lion in Love</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/lion.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After pioneering a plastic-eating enzyme and subsequent refusal to patent the discovery, Leo became a celebrity. He parlayed his new status into sustainable activism and diplomacy.  After several successful coalitions, he sought his next major initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leo found a project he loved with one of the few remaining international conglomerates, a company that specialized in constructing sustainable arcologies. With nature healing and the carbon buildup of the last century abating, the time to resettle the most ravaged areas and return the land to the descendants of climate refugees drew near. It was be an engagement powerfully symbolizing the correction of past sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conglomerate was happy to have Leo as a figurehead but insisted on the highest levels of compartmentalization, secrecy, and “just-in-time” information sharing. Its arcologies were marvels of cutting-edge engineering and environmental science. It insisted that such aggressive protection of its intellectual property was necessary to recoup the vast amounts of research and development it performed. While the approach clashed with Leo’s preference for open cooperation and transparency, he mollified himself that the arrangement would be temporary. When pressed, he argued that that the destination justified the means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the scandal later broke, its virality was due, in large part, to the apparent contradiction between the virtuous person the public believed Leo to be and the double-dealing that the conglomerate engaged in behind closed doors. While Leo had advanced the cause in the name of the refugees, it was revealed that sizable portions to be reclaimed were being gifted to wealthy or politically connected individuals, a rush for new land that hewed to the old ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust broken, “The Lion of the Languished” was declawed and Leo resigned in disgrace. It took some time for Leo’s reputation - his most important asset which he had wielded so successfully - to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A LION demanded the daughter of a woodcutter in marriage. The Father, unwilling to grant, and yet afraid to refuse his request, hit upon this expedient to rid himself of his importunities. He expressed his willingness to accept the Lion as the suitor of his daughter on one condition: that he should allow him to extract his teeth, and cut off his claws, as his daughter was fearfully afraid of both. The Lion cheerfully assented to the proposal. But when the toothless, clawless Lion returned to repeat his request, the Woodman, no longer afraid, set upon him with his club, and drove him away into the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, caution should be exercised when sacrificing one’s strength or essential qualities to appease others or achieve a short-term goal. The Lion, by giving up his teeth and claws, loses not only his physical capabilities but also his dignity and the respect he commanded. The stories underscore the importance of not compromising one’s power or fundamental characteristics, as doing so can lead to vulnerability and loss of respect or position.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/22/TheLionInLove</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/22/TheLionInLove</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Salt Merchant and His Ass</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/merchant.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 22nd century, there was a Code-Burner who became known for his unique and effective ways of “salting” data before permanently lasering it to ceramic for long-term preservation. While his methods were time-consuming, the Code-Burner was often overbooked, with a backlog sometimes spiking into the zettabytes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During one of these busy periods, the Code-Burner took on a young, brash apprentice. It wasn’t long before the Code-Burner noticed the apprentice purposely implementing simpler and faster, albeit more error-prone,  methods to clear the backlog. Vulnerabilities in the areas the apprentice had overseen became apparent, exposing the Code-Burner’s reputation and clients to potential harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After showing the apprentice the errors of his ways, the Code-Burner destroyed the problematic ceramic disks, dropping and letting them shatter across the floor. The apprentice now had two messes to clean up: the time-consuming work of redoing the engraving &lt;em&gt;the right way&lt;/em&gt; and sweeping the entire workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PEDDLER drove his Ass to the seashore to buy salt. His road home lay across a stream into which his Ass, making a false step, fell by accident and rose up again with his load considerably lighter, as the water melted the sack. The Peddler retraced his steps and refilled his panniers with a larger quantity of salt than before. When he came again to the stream, the Ass fell down on purpose in the same spot, and, regaining his feet with the weight of his load much diminished, brayed triumphantly as if he had obtained what he desired. The Peddler saw through his trick and drove him for the third time to the coast, where he bought a cargo of sponges instead of salt. The Ass, again playing the fool, fell down on purpose when he reached the stream, but the sponges became swollen with water, greatly increasing his load. And thus his trick recoiled on him, for he now carried on his back a double burden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, trying to exploit a situation through shortcuts can backfire spectacularly, resulting in a much heavier burden in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cunning might offer short-term advantages, it can lead to unforeseen consequences that outweigh the initial gains. Adaptability and patience can lead to better long-term outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/21/TheSaltMerchantAndHisAss</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/21/TheSaltMerchantAndHisAss</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Girl and the Filberts</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/filberts.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young Girl, helping tend the living classroom, put her hand up and into a seed dispenser. She grasped as many filberts as she could hold from the tank, but when she tried to pull out her hand, the narrow neck of the opening prevented her from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustrated by being stuck but unwilling to drop any of what she clutched in their hand, she began to cry. An assistant, observing quietly, came over and knelt. “If you only take a little, your hand will slide right out. You can always come back again if you need more.” The assistant balled their fist and held it by the wrist with their other hand, “Take on too much, too fast, and problems will follow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BOY put his hand into a pitcher full of filberts. He grasped as many as he could possibly hold, but when he tried to pull out his hand, he was prevented from doing so by the neck of the pitcher. Unwilling to lose his filberts, and yet unable to withdraw his hand, he burst into tears and bitterly lamented his disappointment. A bystander said to him, “Be satisfied with half the quantity, and you will readily draw out your hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, an incremental approach often works best. Trying to accomplish something all at once, or taking more than one’s share, will cause unanticipated problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/20/TheGirlAndTheFilberts</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/20/TheGirlAndTheFilberts</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>gardening</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Boastful Traveler</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/traveler.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was always an affair when a Fixer came to town. Not only were they skilled at finding and freeing the code the villagers presented them with, but they often brought news of other communities they had visited in their travels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular Fixer boasted about their exploits, recounting many fantastic and clever feats he had performed across the archipelago. Among other things, he said that while in Rhodes, he had partnered with the great Leo himself, the reclusive elder that, long-ago, open-sourced the plastic-eating enzyme genome. However, this “next big thing” had to remain private until it was ready, which is why no one outside of Rhodes had seen it at the top of their feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the bystanders interrupted him, saying: “Now, if this partnership were true, there would be no need for feeds, which can be gamed. Leo’s work is open and his signature known. He is transparent, and commits regularly. Suppose we’re interested in what happened in Rhodes. Show us the repo.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A MAN who had traveled in foreign lands boasted very much, on returning to his own country, of the many wonderful and heroic feats he had performed in the different places he had visited. Among other things, he said that when he was at Rhodes he had leaped to such a distance that no man of his day could leap anywhere near him as to that, there were in Rhodes many persons who saw him do it and whom he could call as witnesses. One of the bystanders interrupted him, saying: “Now, my good man, if this be all true there is no need of witnesses. Suppose this to be Rhodes, and leap for us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, the integrity of one’s work and character are paramount. In spaces where claims can be rewritten ad nauseam, transparency, accountability, and verifiable contributions take on outsized importance. Then, as now, actions speak louder than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/19/TheBoastfulTraveler</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/19/TheBoastfulTraveler</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lioness</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/lioness.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, around the fishing hole, the developers who were casting about for software solutions started a friendly debate among themselves. Each fisherman boasted about the volume they caught and reassembled, but none could agree upon the best productivity metric. With no arguments reaching consensus, the group stowed their equipment and sought out the Loiness, an elder of great renown and architect in her own right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They found her walking in the gardens. With much joshing, they demanded to know who had the most plentiful body of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lioness laughed at them and said, “Long ago, the amount we could create effectively became infinite, yet here you are arguing over who has more. That is the scarcity mindset. Making and maintaining the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; thing?” She continued, “&lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is the mindset of enlightenment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CONTROVERSY prevailed among the beasts of the field as to which of the animals deserved the most credit for producing the greatest number of whelps at a birth. They rushed clamorously into the presence of the Lioness and demanded of her the settlement of the dispute. “And you,” they said, “how many sons have you at a birth?” The Lioness laughed at them, and said: “Why! I have only one; but that one is altogether a thoroughbred Lion.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One’s total contribution should be thought of as depth and impact; two things that may be beyond easy summation. The value is in the worth, not in the number.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/18/TheLioness</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/18/TheLioness</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>metrics</category>
                
                <category>productivity</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Father and His Sons</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/farming.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Father farmed with his family of Sons beyond where the commuter rail ends, the vast expanses where the permaculture systems cover kilometers. The Sons constantly bickered over everything from plot use to energy application, and nothing the Father said did any good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, when the Sons were nearly at each other’s throats, the Father asked each of them to bring him a solar module under repair. He had them run a meter over it and noted the charge. He then had them remove the photovoltaic shingles for each of his Sons to read one by one. The energy was a fraction of the panel when it was even detectable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“United,” said the Father, “we have power. Together, these shingles shade the crops when the sun is harsh and take the worst of the hail when it storms. We irrigate less and feed more.  If you let others divide you, you’re no stronger than a single shingle in that array - something people of the old ways will use against you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A certain Father had a family of Sons, who were forever quarreling among themselves. No words he could say did the least good, so he cast about in his mind for some very striking example that should make them see that discord would lead them to misfortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day when the quarreling had been much more violent than usual and each of the Sons was moping in a surly manner, he asked one of them to bring him a bundle of sticks. Then handing the bundle to each of his Sons in turn he told them to try to break it. But although each one tried his best, none was able to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Father then untied the bundle and gave the sticks to his Sons to break one by one. This they did very easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My Sons,” said the Father, “do you not see how certain it is that if you agree with each other and help each other, it will be impossible for your enemies to injure you? But if you are divided among yourselves, you will be no stronger than a single stick in that bundle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, individuals can withstand challenges and adversities much better when they work together and support one another.  Embracing a diversity of opinions and experiences will mean there will be conflict. However, our energies are better served by discovering peaceful ways of compromise and resolution rather than division and escalation. There is strength in unity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/15/TheFatherAndHisSons</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/15/TheFatherAndHisSons</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>power</category>
                
                <category>energy</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bear and the Fox</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/bear.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the evening shade grew long, the Code-Burners, Fishermen, and any migrant Fixers passing through would gather in the commons. While each had a professional interest in being there, more often than not, the evening would slip into night with rollicking tall tales and screening of the latest whopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one of these forums, a Bear began to boast of their skills. “Out of everyone here, I am the most user-friendly,” they proclaimed. “While you’re still sorting out what ends up in your error messages and stressing your operators out, I just suppress them!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Fox overheard Bear’s declarations and paused their gesture control. “Really, Bear? Maybe instead of hiding messages when things go wrong, how much more helpful would it be if you focused on preventing errors from happening in the first place?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BEAR boasted very much of his philanthropy, saying that of all animals he was the most tender in his regard for man, for he had such respect for him that he would not even touch his dead body. A Fox hearing these words said with a smile to the Bear, “Oh! that you would eat the dead and not the living.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, professing virtues or positive qualities means little if one’s actions do not support the claims. We need to be alert against superficial or false displays of respect. Instead, we should look at the practical outcomes of someone’s behavior. In short, we should value deeds over words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/14/TheBearAndTheFox</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/14/TheBearAndTheFox</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>development</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Farmer and the Stork</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/stork.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the vast, distributed social network of the 22nd century, a Farmer set about a trap for those he suspected of market manipulation. An agent surfaced with peculiar frequency: Stork, a being entwined in a complex web of digital interactions across the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stork protested mightily about the unfairness of the situation when confronted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Certainly,” he said over chat, “there has been some mistake. My only crime was accepting every friend request and follow. I was only trying to build an impressive list of contacts. I didn’t realize, at the time, what some of these others might have been up to. Just look at my profile - I’m a good person!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Farmer laughed. “While what you say when caught says one thing, your connections imply something else. The shadows cast extend far beyond any one individual.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A FARMER placed nets on his newly-sown plowlands and caught a number of Cranes, which came to pick up his seed. With them he trapped a Stork that had fractured his leg in the net and was earnestly beseeching the Farmer to spare his life. “Pray save me, Master,” he said, “and let me go free this once. My broken limb should excite your pity. Besides, I am no Crane, I am a Stork, a bird of excellent character; and see how I love and slave for my father and mother. Look too, at my feathers—they are not the least like those of a Crane.” The Farmer laughed aloud and said, “It may be all as you say, I only know this: I have taken you with these robbers, the Cranes, and you must die in their company.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, you are judged by the company that you keep. The quality of one’s connections far outweighs the quantity. Indiscriminately lending your reputation to others can lead to unforeseen consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/13/TheFarmerAndTheStork</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/13/TheFarmerAndTheStork</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>social media</category>
                
                <category>networking</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Fisherman Piping</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/fisherman.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the solarpunk 22nd century, software development was vastly abstracted from the rote assembly that had come before. Where once creating executable functions required carefully crafted trains of inscrutable squiggles, future developers “fished” for their solutions, hoping to hook functionality from a vast ocean of probability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this world, that a Fisherman, skilled in music, stood at the digital shoreline looking to seed a solution. He played several tunes hoping his latest melodies would attract the components needed onto his net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after nearly completing his playlist but receiving nary a nibble, the Fisherman switched tacks. While more comfortable with musical composition than elocution, he gradually found the words necessary to bait his net to fullness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A FISHERMAN skilled in music took his flute and his nets to the seashore. Standing on a projecting rock, he played several tunes in the hope that the fish, attracted by his melody, would of their own accord dance into his net, which he had placed below. At last, having long waited in vain, he laid aside his flute, and casting his net into the sea, made an excellent haul of fish. When he saw them leaping about in the net upon the rock he said: “O you most perverse creatures, when I piped you would not dance, but now that I have ceased you do so merrily.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software, as in life, practical solutions are often more effective than wishful thinking or overly complicated solutions. While creativity and innovation are valuable, they must be grounded in reality and practicality to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/12/TheFishermanPiping</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/12/TheFishermanPiping</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Wolf and Crane &amp; Co. PLLC</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While technology may change, human behavior does not. At least, that’s what reading the collection of Aesop’s Fables suggests. The characters and motivations in the parables, attributed to Aesop after he died in 564 BCE, remain relevant today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesop 2021 projects these well-known (and not-so-known) stories into an age only a stone’s throw from our own. When cynicism and pessimism abound, hope becomes a rebellious act against the tyranny of the default. Each story recasts a fable’s lesson from our upcoming solarpunk future as a software tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aesop 2021 project is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.writinganalytics.co/challenge/65de2439a653549bd3537227&quot;&gt;Never Break the Chain March Writing Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The original sources were translated by George Fyler Townsend and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gutenberg.org/cache/epub/21/pg21-images.html#link2H_4_0077&quot;&gt;provided under the Project Gutenberg license&lt;/a&gt;. Addition reference provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://read.gov/aesop/about.html&quot;&gt;a Library of Congress interactive book&lt;/a&gt; adapted from the public domain book “The Aesop for Children: with Pictures by Milo Winter,” published by Rand, McNally &amp;amp; Co in 1919.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;below-is-the-latest-installment&quot;&gt;Below is the latest installment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/03/crane.png&quot; alt=&quot;A picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last billionaire, who others derided as “The Wolf”, faced a legal quandary. In the before times, only human authors could receive copyright. However, recent renewed calls for what constituted a “recognizable living entity” threatened a century of established case law - a threat to the status quo that was The Wolf’s bone to pick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wolf turned to Crane &amp;amp; Co., PLLC, a legal firm renowned for its ability to navigate the labyrinthine corridors of IP law. Jumping directly into the problem’s maw,  Crane ingeniously sowed seeds of dissent and doubt among the public and lawmakers. Cries of “We’ll be replaced!” stirred a considerable amount of fear, uncertainty, and doubt across the societal spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crane, having navigated the murky waters of public opinion and legal intricacies, approached The Wolf for their agreed-upon fee. It was a considerable amount, considering the complexity and scale of their undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, The Wolf dismissed all payment requests. He argued that the exposure and injection of the firm into public discourse were compensation enough. “Crane should be thanking &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; for the publicity they received for &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; case”. Privately, The Wolf also suggested that Crane &amp;amp; Co. was fortunate that he didn’t seek further compensation - after all, they had profited from using his expansive portfolio to make their case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Fable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A WOLF who had a bone stuck in his throat hired a Crane, for a large sum, to put her head into his mouth and draw out the bone. When the Crane had extracted the bone and demanded the promised payment, the Wolf, grinning and grinding his teeth, exclaimed: “Why, you have surely already had a sufficient recompense, in having been permitted to draw out your head in safety from the mouth and jaws of a wolf.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software as in life,  serving those with wealth and power is perilous. Expecting gratitude or fair compensation from individuals who have achieved their stature by subverting such expectations remains a precarious venture, at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, in serving the wicked, expect no reward and be thankful if you escape injury for your pains.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/11/TheWolfandCraneCoLLC</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2024/03/11/TheWolfandCraneCoLLC</guid>
                
                <category>Aesop2121</category>
                
                <category>scifi</category>
                
                <category>writing</category>
                
                <category>fables</category>
                
                <category>ai</category>
                
                <category>law</category>
                
                <category>copyright</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>