<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Matthew Reinbold</title>
        <description>This Matthew Reinbold&apos;s website. I am a Digtial Engagement Lead within the Concentrix API Change Practice. I write the &apos;Net API Notes&apos; email newsletter, am working on a book, a few comics, and like taking long walks whenever I have a chance. Born at 334 ppm CO₂ and my pronouns are he/him.</description>
        <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://matthewreinbold.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 12:56:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 12:56:01 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Separating AI Fact from Fiction</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was asked to return to speak at the CarMax/Edmunds DevOps Days 2023 event. Rather than asking about a specific topic, the organizers graciously asked me (paraphrasing) to prepare “whatever was currently on my mind”. Like a lot of folks, AI has been something I’ve not only heard a lot about, but spent time working with. In this presentation, I share some of my current thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, everyone. My name is Matthew Reinbold, and I am a software strategy consultant with a couple of decades of enterprise integration experience to call on. I’m passionate about creating better software – you might remember me from the presentation that I gave last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/06/28/SevenSkillsToSaveSoftware&quot;&gt;Seven Skills to Change Complex Software Systems&lt;/a&gt;. I’m delighted to have been asked back to present what’s been on my mind this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the guy behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/&quot;&gt;Net API Notes&lt;/a&gt;, an API industry newsletter I’ve authored since 2015. In that time, I’ve seen various tools, techniques, and trends come and go. However, regarding today’s discussions about AI, I don’t know if I have seen anything as simultaneously under &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; overhyped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time that we have here today, I’ll:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight opportunities where Large Language Models (or LLMs) can enhance everyday tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shine a light on how to use the tools better for API design and development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw some distinct boundaries where LLM users - API creators or not - should continue to be careful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must stress that LLMs aren’t just something that happened in the last few years. I led the Capital One API Center of Excellence for over a half-decade. Because of my team’s success with APIs, we were asked to contribute to later data transformation and event-streaming initiatives, creating the &lt;em&gt;operational backbone&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;digital capabilities&lt;/em&gt; necessary for LLMs execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing amount of my API work in recent years has explored what it means to use powerful natural language models in software environments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/01/08/WhyAISuccessIsAPIBuilt&quot;&gt;Why AI Success is API Built (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/07/16/GithubCopilot&quot;&gt;Machine Learning Prompts Within IDEs (2021)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2019/11/25/ARoadMapForAIGovernance&quot;&gt;A Road Map for AI Governance (2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/p/what-happen-when-githubs-ai-copilot&quot;&gt;What Happened When Github’s AI Copilot Wrote My OpenAPI Description (2022)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/p/the-thing-about-using-chatgpt-for&quot;&gt;The Thing About Using ChatGPT for API Design (2022)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/p/why-quantifying-good-api-design-even&quot;&gt;What Quantifying Good API Design, Even With AI, Is Not the Homerun Metric You Think It Is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide3.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a challenge in covering such a fast-moving topic. Those familiar with the long history of AI will readily acknowledge that it goes through periods of boom and bust. Initial excitement at sprouting new approaches quickly melts under the bright lights of reality. Much of the 80s and 90s was dominated by times of under-investment, referred to as ‘AI winters’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed like we reached something a plateau in 2019 or 2020, after an especially intense period of excitement around new LLM methods. However, the rapid release of AI tools in recent years – tools like Dalle-2, Midjourney, Stable Diffusion, and ChatGPT, has poured gasoline on an already brightly burning fire. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/02/chatgpt-sets-record-for-fastest-growing-user-base-in-history-report-says/&quot;&gt;ChatGPT recently set a record for the fastest-growing user base in history&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tool users and creators, evaluating the impact of these developments is part of our jobs. My field of expertise is APIs, so for much of this presentation, I’ll try to answer how LLMs can supplement and create better APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Image taken from “&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10506-022-09309-8&quot;&gt;The winter, the summer, and the summer dream of artificial intelligence in law&lt;/a&gt;” paper by Enrico Francesconi]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide4.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we can start talking about how today’s current crop of Large Language Models (or LLMs) can help you in your API creation, I first need to make sure that we’re all on the same page about what we’re talking about, because, like so many extremely popular things, there have been lots said. Terms have been distorted to support people’s preferred or self-serving narratives, causing confusion for general comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the presentation, I will try and avoid using the term ‘artificial intelligence’ or AI. The term is incredibly overloaded, almost to the point of meaninglessness. Further, when many of us hear “AI”, we’re actually thinking about “Artificial GENERAL Intelligence”, or the kind of self-aware conscious construct we see in sci-fi movies and read about in futuristic books. The current crop of LLMs is &lt;em&gt;not that&lt;/em&gt; – in fact, they are very far from it. However, some of the biggest names in the space are working hard to present that very impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide5.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, creators of ChatGPT and image generation Dalle-2, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2023/05/30/sam-altman-ai-risk-of-extinction-pandemics-nuclear-warfare/&quot;&gt;has warned that AI poses ‘risk of extinction’ to humanity, on par with pandemics and nuclear warfare.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, an open letter has been circulated, signed by several prominent figures, calling for a temporary halt to LLM training and development so the potential risks can be studied. That sounds like a reasonable request until you dig deeper into what is being asked for. Those concerns are not about paying the creators whose work was used to train the model. They are not about mitigating existing injustice. Rather, the risks were imagined ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-general-intelligence&quot;&gt;AI Apocalypses&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As scientist, author, and current AI-hype critic Emily Bender points out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Powerful corporations hype about LLMs and their progress toward AGI create a narrative that distracts from the need for regulations that protect people from these corporations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a certain amount of hubris in going before the world’s governments and declaring that “we’re so good at our jobs, you must acknowledge us”. Especially when at the same time, you’re marketing your products as “too good”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/6288245/openai-eu-lobbying-ai-act/&quot;&gt;you undermine good faith efforts to regulate AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a decent amount of my career in software governance. I know what regulatory capture looks like. Or in other words, this is a deliberate attempt to maintain the status quo of existing leaders while creating onerous burdens on those attempting to enter the space. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semianalysis.com/p/google-we-have-no-moat-and-neither&quot;&gt;there’s reasons for AI incumbents to be concerned&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The danger with automation isn’t some remote, far-off sci-fi dystopia. Instead, the harms are the much more mundane, everyday negligence that Virginia Eubanks documented in her 2018 book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Automating-Inequality-High-Tech-Profile-Police/dp/1250074312&quot;&gt;Automating Inequality&lt;/a&gt;. Software can perpetuate bad systems. Automation can perpetuate bad systems &lt;em&gt;at scale&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide6.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If today’s generative AI isn’t a pending AI Apocalypse, then what is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are incredibly creative in imagining human-like properties in the things we interact with. People using a simple program in the 1960s named Eliza believed they were having a conversation with a live human being. People see pictures of Jesus in a Dorito. As a species, we’re good at projecting human qualities in the things surrounding us. However, that creativity causes problems when we try to get at what LLMs are good at. Saying that LLMs are “creating” or “hallucinating”, anthropomorphizes the technology and muddies our understanding how to be productive with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining the mathematical basis of how these systems work is outside the scope of this presentation. However, one helpful way of thinking about LLMs is as “word calculators”. Or, as the title of the slide says, the way that LLM’s statistical probability routines work is that a model will try and complete a document in the most statistically likely way possible. It is not trying to be correct. It is trying to complete a document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to illustrate this is shown in the slide. “Which is heavier, one pound of feathers or one pound of lead” is a common introductory science question for exploring mass, density, and weight concepts. In its training, ChatGPT ingested copious amounts of text where the answer appearing after the question was “a pound of feathers and a pound of lead weigh the same amount”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I slightly tweak the question and ask what is heavier, “a pound of feathers or five pounds of lead” ChatGPT isn’t parsing the sentence and applying logic the way we do. Rather, it is attempting to answer the question in the most statistically probable way – since it has seen that similar questions often result in “they’re the same”, it too replies that the weights are the same. Amusingly, it then goes on to contradict itself in the next sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An essential part of successfully working with an LLM, like ChatGPT, is following an iterative process that allows us to surface and correct these internal assumptions. It is less about creating the perfect, singular prompt to perform work – asking ChatGPT to “Write an application that will make me rich” &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; end in disappointment. Instead, it is about thinking critically and creatively about refining what we’re after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide7.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re almost to the point where we’re about to play with some responses. However, let’s cover some final important warnings if you use something like ChatGPT for business use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide8.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THESE TOOLS ARE OWNED BY OTHERS&lt;/strong&gt;
Some of you might have heard this story. Soon after Samsung’s semiconductor division started allowing engineers to use ChatGPT, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/three-samsung-employees-reportedly-leaked-sensitive-data-to-chatgpt-190221114.html&quot;&gt;workers leaked secret info to it on at least &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; occasions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One employee reportedly asked the chatbot to check sensitive database source code for errors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another asked for advice in optimizing code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A third fed a recorded meeting into ChatGPT and asked it to generate minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-restricts-use-of-chatgpt-joining-other-companies-wary-of-leaks-d44d7d34&quot;&gt;Apple soon followed suit in restricting ChatGPT access&lt;/a&gt;. In response, Microsoft is said to launch a private alternative sometime this summer – a version of ChatGPT that runs on dedicated cloud servers where the data will be kept separate from those of other customers. While that will be nice, a proportional cost will most likely accompany it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHATGPT HAS EXPANDED TYPOSQUATTING MALICIOUS PRACTICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ll cover, asking ChatGPT for package or library suggestions can be easy. This month, some clever security researchers realized that sometimes ChatGPT recommends URLs, references, code libraries, and functions that don’t exist. The story goes from annoying to alarming when we know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://vulcan.io/blog/ai-hallucinations-package-risk and https://www.infoworld.com/article/3699256/malicious-hackers-are-weaponizing-generative-ai.html&quot;&gt;malicious actors could create code with those same names, which are subsequently incorporated inside legitimate codebases by naïve developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is like the practice of “typosquatting” but updated for LLM output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNAVAILABILITY AND UNPREDICTABILITY ARE THE NORM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following examples, you’ll see lots of screenshots, which is very much on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT’s availability has been much better in recent months. However, there are still times when the service is unavailable or returns an unknown error. Having this occur during a live demo is not desirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, LLMs like ChatGPT are non-deterministic, meaning we’ll get different answers if we ask the same question multiple times. That can be a problem when trying to recreate behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to use a technical term, I would describe the current state as “squirrely”. I wouldn’t trust it to do a live demo, and I certainly wouldn’t rely on it as part of a 24-7, client-facing activity, at least at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide9.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough caveats!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to briefly run through several much less well-known, but useful ways to apply a natural language LLM, like ChatGPT, to your everyday activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;None of these things will do your job for you&lt;/em&gt;. However, when approached with a bit of creativity, they can take tedious or time-consuming tasks and make them trivial, leaving more time for building APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide10.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a simple example and rapidly get to more complex cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, sometimes I have difficulty remembering a specific word. Often, I’ll have an image in my mind of the word’s silhouette – how it rises and falls with its letters. I usually have clarity on the starting letter, but when I reach for the rest of it, there’s just a gap. I’ll struggle for a bit, use something else, and then get smacked upside the head during dinner or while in the shower when the word pops into my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to Google for ‘words that mean kind of like this that start with this letter’ are hit or miss. Sometimes it works, but more often, I get frustrated wading through advertising and content marketing spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this is a task that LLMs are good at – again, they’re working with statistical probability, and providing the right criteria will create the odds-on match for what you’re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also works great for quickly getting up to speed on industry jargon – terms of art that would be useful to know but would take a long time to pick up through meeting osmosis. You’ll also notice here that creating structured output, like tables, is as simple as just asking. No need to try and remember markdown’s syntax – something that I often had to lookup in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide11.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about these tools is that they provide a base level of competence in communication. Much has been written about the predictable, even cliché, writing that ChatGPT 4 currently outputs. It is true: spend any amount of time with these tools and the framing in the introductory statement, a series of bullet points, and a conclusion restating the main point is an easily identifiable pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, given how most communication is structured, even this is a step above what I usually see in daily business messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From tricky emails to performance reviews to more critical business communication, I strongly recommend not copying the generated output directly. Instead, take 30 seconds to recognize how the stereotypical (yet clear and concise) response has been formatted. Then, customize it with the unique details of your situation. It is slightly more work, but it will help you overcome the tyranny of the blank page – rather than starting with nothing, you’re kickstarted with an example of how someone saying something like what you wish to say has structured their argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example shown, I was asked to write a blurb supporting the humanities department for one of my alma maters. I was flattered and immediately began to procrastinate – what would I say? I asked ChatGPT for an example, not intending to use what it outputted, but to get me unstuck. While the result on the right is my voice and feeling, I had to go through a crappy first draft to get there. And ChatGPT is great for generating a crappy first draft quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another approach is to take something you’ve already written and ask ChatGPT or fix grammar or punctuation. You can even ask it to rewrite to clarify the main points or apply more professional polish than what currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is helpful just to have a starter reference. Things like performance reviews, things to cover in 1-on-1s, internal CMS documentation, and more are all opportunities to overcome initial inertia (the structure) and get to the fun parts – injecting your personality to make it something special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide12.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Busse, a former co-worker of mine, inspired this next one. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/chrisbusse_chatgpt-custom-learning-plan-prompt-assuming-activity-7059564093698957312-Iy9R&quot;&gt;He uses ChatGPT to create learning plans&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a logic here that makes a lot of sense: with the entire corpus of the web used during training, ChatGPT would know which concepts are statistically probable to appear next to each other. All that is then required is providing the correct context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is the context that makes this approach very powerful and efficient. Rather than having to wade through generic, trying-to-be-all-things-to-all people, I can create a &lt;em&gt;tailored&lt;/em&gt;, custom plan that covers &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what I need (and very little that I don’t). In the process, I save time not re-reviewing things outside of what I would want to learn, as would be the case with starting a course from scratch at Pluralsight or Codecademy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, I have a problem. I learned JavaScript in the aughts. So, when I try to write Node code today, I’m still thinking about functions and callbacks. However, many of the code samples I find or packages I try have the expectation I know &lt;strong&gt;promises&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could attempt to scour the web for a variety of general JavaScript courses, scraping together something useful here and something relevant there. But discovering and reconciling everything together is a lot of work. Instead, I can ask ChatGPT to create a series of steps that would work well for my situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide13.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another place where I am more efficient is keeping up with industry trends. I love Ben Thompson’s Stratechery. But with pieces regularly coming in at more than two thousand words, it can be a commitment to keep up. (To be fair, many people probably say the same about &lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/&quot;&gt;my newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than setting aside an hour when the latest email drops, I can ask ChatGPT to summarize the contents to only those unique points. That takes this recent article from 2353 words to a much more skimmable 393 words. If, after reading the summary, I see something of interest I can go back and have a better idea that my investment of time in the large piece will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide14.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond summarization is inference. Suppose I am a product manager or tech lead interesting in understanding my own or competitor products. In that case, I can quickly get an idea of perception with any collection of customer reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I have the 1st edition of the ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Continuous-API-Management-Decisions-Landscape/product-reviews/1492043559/ref=cm_cr_dp_d_show_all_btm&quot;&gt;Continuous API Management&lt;/a&gt;’ book. Copying in the review contents, I then asked ChatGPT to summarize the top 3 things people liked and disliked about the book. That is not just rehashing what is said but inferring whether those comments are positive or negative. ChatGPT also must infer whether one comment is saying something like another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t shown it here, but one of the comments was also in French. I didn’t translate it before handing it to ChatGPT. However, after I did, I discovered sentiments in that foreign language comment appeared in ChatGPT’s summaries. That is another thing I want to emphasize – ChatGPT performed that translation and incorporated that sentiment into the results automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That can be highly beneficial when doing competitive analysis. Imagine being able to take a user forum filled with customer feedback and easily identifying new feature opportunities. ChatGPT, in this case, is not just summarizing the reviews, but can infer whether the comment is overall good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide15.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough potpourri! Those things may be helpful, but how do we use a natural language LLM, like ChatGPT, to create APIs? I’ll get into that with this next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started designing, we should follow a repeatable, predictable process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long been a proponent of an API-Design-First approach when creating APIs. In 2020, I had the good fortune of being asked to review James Higginbotham’s book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Principles-Web-Design-James-Higginbotham/dp/0137355637&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Principles of Web API Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In that book, James codifies a rich API-Design process, referred to as the ADDR (or ‘Align-Define-Design-Refine’) model. While the result is a detailed and complete set of exercises used to explore a space before creating an API, a fair amount of work is involved. Further, due to the high levels of communication necessary, it could be a challenge for remote or solopreneurs like myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there ways we can leverage an LLM like ChatGPT to aid to provide rapid collaboration on some of these tasks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide16.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work through the ADDR process, it makes sense to have a specific example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a writer that frequently links to other material in my newsletters, I am very aware of the prevalence of tracking and advertising codes that often are included as query parameters. Whether bookmarking or resharing the links in my newsletter, I don’t want to include these tracking codes or highlight fragments. The extra cruft obscures the original URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my initial vision, the service would accept a URL, strip off all the unnecessary query params (probably with a regular expression) and return a ‘clean version’. When I have that API, I can call it with everything from browser plugins to native applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide17.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating Jobs-To-Be-Done (or JTBDs) from scratch can be tedious to write. In addition, let’s remember what an LLM is – a pattern matching-machine. So let’s ask ChatGPT what other text – or what other jobs – is commonly associated with the text we’re interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT has created a good JTBD for our initial prompt. ChatGPT also listed several subsequent jobs that someone interested in URL simplification might also want to use. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redirection Handling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blacklisting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canonicalization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list includes several services I wouldn’t have thought of. For example, the ‘URL Canonicalization’, which follows references of &lt;em&gt;rel=”canonical”&lt;/em&gt; in a page’s header, would be useful. Authors publishing to Medium, for example, do this all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these initial job stories in hand, I then iterated. That included replacing the term “blacklisting” with “blocklisting”, replacing “URL Generation” with “URL Shortening”, and more. Through this back and forth, I’m getting feedback that clarifies my ideas about what the service should and shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide18.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating job stories helped identify the desired outcomes and the digital capabilities necessary to produce those outcomes. Following the ADDR API design process, the next step is to detail the digital capabilities as the activities and activity steps required to do these jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activity steps decompose activities into tasks that need to be performed to complete the story. Once all necessary activities are completed, the job story outcome will be met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By decomposing the problem in this way, we continue to uncover assumptions or misunderstandings that we can correct before jumping to a design or code output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide19.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to work through the steps, it becomes clear that I have a problem with the Blocklisting. While the JTBD description made sense, having ChatGPT expand the result into activity steps has uncovered an assumption that I would build and maintain a blocklist for people to submit a URL to. That’s beyond my scope. Instead, I want to leverage existing work – surely, specialists are already maintaining lists of malware and spam sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having ChatGPT rewrite the JTBD and activity steps is easy enough. However, I know that services that maintain blocklists of bad URLs should exist, but I’ve never used them. Where would I start? So I asked ChatGPT that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT provided a list of a half-dozen results, which – I want to emphasize this because it is crucial to do because of the ‘typosquatting’ issue mentioned earlier – &lt;em&gt;I then independently verified to ensure they were real sites&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After identifying the option that made sense for my project, I asked ChatGPT to update the activity step participants with that additional information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like extraneous steps – however, the reason that we’re following a formal path like this is &lt;strong&gt;precisely&lt;/strong&gt; for this reason – to surface assumptions. I could have asked ChatGPT to try and generate code from my initial idea. However, by continuing to chip away and refine the underlying assumptions, we’re ensuring we can get a better result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide20.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After additional, similar refinements to both the jobs to be done and activity steps to make sure any assumptions were aligned with my expectations, it was time to take a moment to reassess what was being proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose I was working with an engineering team and stakeholders. In that case, this is the point where we would walk through our activity steps, or the output of an activity like event storming, and begin to identify our API boundaries. We would see places where we might have shared terminology. Similar language is a clue that there is a bounded context that should be grouped together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that ChatGPT can infer words that are statistically similar, let’s use it to analyze what we’ve created thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While iterating with the steps, I had already begun to consider redirection and canonical header handling as similar functionality. What I had not considered was what ChatGPT pointed out – that all these subsystems would require URL validation before performing their respective tasks – which was a great point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide21.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s more in the ADDR model, like building style-agnostic API profiles and identifying emitted events. Those are essential steps for larger, more complex initiatives. For demonstration purposes, I will jump ahead to create a high-level API description to the OpenAPI specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I directed ChatGPT to use our refined JTBD and activity steps to create an OpenAPI description. To make things interesting, I also required it to use the 2.0 (or ‘Swagger’) version of the specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results could have been better. While the OpenAPI description validates, it is clear that the jump from activities to resource design in a RESTful manner was too much. I hadn’t provided &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; in what I expected from a REST-like API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Functionality like “URL simplification” and “URL Blocklisting” became RPC-like endpoints where a request would POST to ‘/simplify’ and ‘/check-blocklisting’. Also, I’m not a fan of baking version numbers into the path, but there’s “/api/v1” right there to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important elements were also missing. As ChatGPT warns, “Here’s a basic example of how you might describe this API using the OpenAPI 2.0 (Swagger) specification. This only covers some basic paths and doesn’t include all potential error responses, security definitions, tags, etc., that a full OpenAPI spec might include.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide22.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More work is necessary here; luckily, we have a tool that has ingested the entire internet (give or take a forum). Others have experienced and written about what they do in this situation. That means we should be able to ask for what lies along that probability. Specifically, when dealing with operations related to &lt;em&gt;validation&lt;/em&gt;, how do other services model that without making an explicit “validation” resource?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer provided by ChatGPT isn’t the &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; answer, but it did point the way to a resourced-based design approach that won’t lead to an explosion of custom-named, function-based endpoints in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide23.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll spare you the iteration at this point. Bottom line, using the design performed in the previous steps, I entered my IDE and quickly created a revised OpenAPI description that captures the functionality I want to provide. In addition, the design matches how I would expect the affordances to be modeled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now take this intermediate format –machine parsable while still being human-readable – and begin working on my implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide24.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot written about how well (and not so well) natural language models like ChatGPT are at writing code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our OpenAPI description, and a handful of my other code generation experiences to draw on, let’s see how far we can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide25.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like our design process, having a series of steps to follow is beneficial– in all but the simplest cases, going from an idea to telling the LLM to “make me some code” is too much of a leap. Proceeding along a series of steps to unpack assumptions and clarify direction goes a long way toward creating more valuable (and less buggy) code generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/2023-chatgpt-xu-hao.html&quot;&gt;One useful approach I’ve found was written by Xu Hao and shared on Martin Fowler’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Begin with context and instruction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask ChatGPT to outline its approach, splitting the interactions into multiple addressable steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After refinement, regenerate the plan with names for program elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then ask, step by step, for tests and implementation code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide26.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in developing code, following Xu’s model, is to provide context and generate a series of steps. That includes providing a brief of our intent, our desired tech stack, and the required output format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our context, we now have a preliminary plan. Much like our design process, we should proceed through each of these elements and, where appropriate, update any assumptions or misunderstandings. Doing that at this level is much easier than modifying generated and possibly interrelated code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide27.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As before, asking for an update to the plan with components, methods, and properties allows us to preview the upcoming code execution and, where necessary, make changes to avoid problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this step, ChatGPT has helpfully included numerous items related to our project. However, even at the beginning of the output, there is some cause for concern. In the creation of the project, ChatGPT has included several packages that are relevant. Express makes total sense – we asked for it. Body-parser does, too, as we’ll be parsing the body of submitted requests. &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, as of September, 2017, Express has included body-parser as part of the default Express package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, there seems to be some confusion. While we’re using an OpenAPI description to provide additional context for code generation, nothing about our service requires using an OpenAPI file in production, let alone the need to validate one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more positive note, including “dotenv” is a welcome surprise. We will deal with keys and secrets if we call other 3rd parties for processing. But we need to be aware that some of how that is handled will depend on the cloud service we use for production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide28.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After multiple rounds of providing instructions for our more detailed plan, we get to the point where we have a very robust understanding of what the code should be doing and how we’ve organized it. Note that this isn’t just throwaway work for satisfying the LLM – this also provides a robust set of documentation to refer to later, like for onboarding new developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to create the necessary test cases which exercise the functionality that we’ve described. In addition to asking for a plan for end-to-end testing using a tool like Postman, I can easily tell ChatGPT to generate sample test information for use as part of a test runner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide29.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some cautions that we need to be aware of while creating code. These LLMs can only learn from the past. And while they have a vast amount of information as part of their training data, that data includes those old tutorials and quickstarts as we saw with the inclusion of ‘body-parser’ in our express code. The model has no concept of deprecation over time, at least not yet – something that is a problem for programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue is that larger projects require more tokens. GPT-4 has a token limit of 8,192. Another variant increases that to 32,768. That is more but both variations can quickly be consumed on tricky problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once ChatGPT receives enough tokens, it begins to lose context, starting with the earliest material. And given the importance of maintaining context to create logical results, this can be a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the number of tokens used with &lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.openai.com/tokenizer&quot;&gt;OpenAI’s tokenizer tool&lt;/a&gt;. For our example, my simple 110-line OpenAPI description already constitutes 1,522 tokens. Bigger, more realistic applications are going to consist of significantly more tokens. That is why, when performing this kind of development, the problems must be decomposed into highly focused, discrete work units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide30.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could keep going. This entire thought exercise assumed that I was creating a new service from scratch. I didn’t even address situations where we might have an existing codebase. There’s a host of different applications, from creating documentation to identifying redundant points, from translating to different languages to inferring operations based on logs that I could go into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in the time that we have left, I want to return to a high-level conversation and discuss the implications of LLMs being widely used in software development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide31.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the immediate future, we will see all manner of existing software tools incorporating ‘AI’ or ‘Copilot’ features. It is just too much of a compelling selling point now. Some of this will be genuinely beneficial and create new opportunities for productivity. In other cases, existing algorithmic automation will get rebranded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this ‘AI’ advertising, we need to be able to evaluate the claims made. There will be helpful functionality. There will also be a tremendous amount of ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/talks/MIT-STS-AI-snakeoil.pdf&quot;&gt;AI snake oil&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide32.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of what we discussed in both the &lt;em&gt;design&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;development&lt;/em&gt; sections has the potential to create better results. However, it is crucial to recognize that both of these steps pale when discussing software’s &lt;strong&gt;total cost of ownership&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, 90+% of the cost of any code, let alone APIs, is in the maintenance and operation. We treat getting into production as checking the box, completing a goal, and being “done”. Then, the thinking goes, the more things we can get “done”, the more productive we can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating something faster is not the boon to business that you think it is. LLMs, done incorrectly, are the equivalent of throwing more things at the wall, faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should aspire to create &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; software, not necessarily &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide33.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the more we use these tools, the more likely these model’s outputs will be included in the training sets. When this happens, it leads to an interesting phenomenon known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.17493&quot;&gt;model collapse&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datasets that contain LLM-generated text experience worse performance; it is almost like making a copy of a copy of a copy. Subsequently, volumes of data compiled before 2020 will be at a significant premium for people looking to continue training models. And the more we put the output of these tools out into the world where they can be scraped for the next generations of LLMs, the more problems those LLMs will have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide34.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if we could uncover another Reddit or Wikipedia, which somehow had avoided being used in training models thus far, there is the question of whether we’d see the same leaps in perceived performance that we have seen to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.06162&quot;&gt;As suggested by papers in the space&lt;/a&gt;, we could be reaching the point of diminishing returns in raw training data set size. There is a high likelihood that performance improvements in the immediate future will be because of targeted, task-based optimizations for specific industries, as opposed to larger training data sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that is some interesting, challenging technical problems. I’m not saying that we won’t see improvements in LLMs in the future. What I am trying to impress upon you is that the rate of progress isn’t up and to the right forever – at least not using current techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide35.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even with what we have, what we have is pretty amazing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2023/Mar/27/ai-enhanced-development/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison perfectly captures the sentiment I’ve felt while exploring these tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘AI-enhanced development makes me more ambitious with my projects.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As an experienced developer, ChatGPT (and GitHub Copilot) save me an enormous amount of “figuring things out” time. For everything from writing a for loop in Bash to remembering how to make a cross-domain CORS request in JavaScript—I don’t need to even look things up any more, I can just prompt it and get the right answer 80% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“This doesn’t just make me more productive: it lowers my bar for when a project is worth investing time in at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a cutting or even leading-edge developer. My production code days are at least a decade behind me. I cut my teeth in the era of responsive web design, database normalization, and three-tier software architecture apps. I still think of software in model-view-controller terms. I moved to organizational concerns before the big shift to cloud, containers, complex frontend libraries, and intricate deployment pipelines. As such, launching a new project is intimidating for me. Even attempting to follow getting started tutorials can be a frustrating experience; so many of them start from a place of high background knowledge and assumed pipeline guardrails that I have difficulty following along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to quickly bridge that experience gap by asking for what I need to know - rather than having to stitch together the missing puzzle pieces from here, there, and everywhere else – is &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt;. In some ways, it is personal for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide36.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to my last point. We’re not talking about a model when we say ‘AI did this’ or ‘AI disrupted that’. Whether we’re talking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2023/05/02/ai-jobs-takeover-ibm/&quot;&gt;laying off nearly 8,000 people&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2023/05/20/1177366800/striking-movie-and-tv-writers-worry-that-they-will-be-replaced-by-ai&quot;&gt;undermining a workers’ strike&lt;/a&gt;, those are decisions being made by people. And we need to hold them accountable for their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Emily Bender, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dair-community.social/@emilymbender/110463454245744395&quot;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Rather than asking, ‘can AI do that?’, the more appropriate question is ‘Is this an appropriate use of automation?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That applies to a lot more than just ChatGPT.  From our dev pipelines to our call center support, how do new forms of automation enable us to BEST serve our customers and what they are trying to do? In whose interest is it to lay off journalists, creatives, and even technology professionals?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide37.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Dismissing today’s current crop of LLMs, or “generative AI” as only capable of “telling lies” or “hallucinating” projects far more personhood and sentience - a will or agenda present during interactions - than what exists. In a world that has seemed more chaotic and randomly cruel, particularly in the last several years, our brains are working overtime to see a pattern, an intelligence, an intent anywhere we can find it. Sadly, those looking for a savior (or an opponent) will be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does exist is a set of tools - useful, powerful tools that tighten the feedback loop for creators. Further, these tools leverage the power of language. Rather than requiring a priesthood versed in ritualized incantations, the promise is that anyone who speaks can create software. While much of the low or no-code effort has focused on greater visual metaphors, from Visual Basic to Scratch, the promise with tools like ChatGPT is to forgo that learning ramp entirely.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grady Booch, an American Software Engineer perhaps best known for developing the Unified Modeling Language, once said, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://redmonk.com/sogrady/2023/04/27/ai-questions/&quot;&gt;the entire history of software engineering is one of rising levels of abstraction&lt;/a&gt;”. There is a solid argument to be made that LLMs represent the next major abstraction in software development. The key to unlocking ever greater levels of software potential was not enriching our communication with more rigid semantic meaning. Instead, it was about training the machines to be more comfortable with our language’s ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, as those most able to understand these tools’ nature, we must use them wisely – to empower where necessary and avoid perpetuating a status quo of inequality and apathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2023/06/Slide38.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for and inviting me back again to speak this year and the opportunity to share some of my most recent work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2023/06/23/SeparatingAIFactFromFiction</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2023/06/23/SeparatingAIFactFromFiction</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>AI</category>
                
                <category>API Design</category>
                
                <category>Presentations</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Seven Skills to Save Software</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This June, I had the good fortune to present my recent work to several different venues. As I progress in my career, I’m increasingly more interested in &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; change happens than the bits and bobs of the change itself. In other words, I started out with a career in technology and have ended up caring a lot more about the people involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my most recent work, ‘Seven Skills to Change Complex Systems (And Save Your Software)’. A recording of the &lt;em&gt;Deliberate Complexity&lt;/em&gt; delivery is embedded at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide1.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Title Slide&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Matthew Reinbold. I am happy to be here. I am also  grateful for the technology that allows us to have these kinds of conversations, regardless of whatever is happening in the world. Today, I will be talking about the seven skills to change complex systems and, subsequently, save your software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide2.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;To Identify The Barrier to Change, We Need to Rethink Relationships&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get to the skills, we need to  illustrate the relationships in modern software development. We need to talk about what happens with a change in a complex system and why it seems so hard to facilitate large-scale improvement programs within the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of change am I referring to? When I say improvement program, I refer to a variety of things. This could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Becoming more customer-responsive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improving the agile processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increasing your security posture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever that thing is within your company, chances are you found it was like moving through molasses. Change in a complex system is not just difficult, but new wrinkles seem to constantly emerge, threatening to undo whatever progress has been made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide3.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Once Upon a Time, Software Was Simple&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a gross oversimplification of the way things used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, the software a company was responsible for could be modeled as a single unit. This is not a perfect metaphor, but it is useful. In this case, we’ll say that there was a single team working on a single code base, and everybody was working toward the same release date. Everyone celebrated when the “gold master” was published. When it was time to update things, getting everyone moving in the same direction was simple, since there were “of a piece”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve had a firsthand seat to how software creation and distribution have changed. As a Digital Engagement Lead with the Concentrix Catalyst group, I help large enterprises accelerate their API-led digital transformations. I also write about sociotechnical issues on my website, MatthewReinbold.com. Previously, I helped multiple Fortune 500 companies establish software improvement efforts, covering tens-of-thousands of developers across numerous geographical locations and different Lines-of-Business. As a writer for Net API Notes, my email newsletter, I’ve chronicled the changing nature of service interaction for more than seven years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the ability to peek behind the curtain, I know this model on the screen is not how companies’ internal operations look today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide4.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Software Composition Has Changed&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where once we might have had a singular monolith - both in concept, team resourcing, deployment, language, framework, and objective - our software capabilities resemble something more akin to abstract art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jackkleeman/status/1190354757308862468&quot;&gt;This network traffic map is from a UK company called Monzo&lt;/a&gt;. This was in 2019, so it’s probably more sophisticated now. This graph represents the network traffic between their 1500 different microservices. Rather than having a single monolith, they have 1500 tiny individual pieces that make up the capability that they ultimately deliver to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Monzo is not alone. These ominous charts are called “microservice death stars,” and similar charts exist for Netflix, Amazon, Twitter, and probably – to some degree – the company where you work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide5.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Today, Software Is Composed of Systems&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, you’re not attempting to manage 1500 microservices. But the odds are that the software capability or experience you’re trying to deliver comprises multiple pieces, and for a good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As software has been challenged to more significant problems, it has become increasingly difficult for any person, or even one team, to comprehend the entire software scope. As a result, we (software practitioners) have increasingly sought reductive techniques for turning a large problem into smaller chunks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agile is a reduction in the size of the work unit to be delivered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CI/CD is about reducing the time it takes to deliver through automation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even the concept of two-pizza teams is about reducing the scope of ownership to something that isn’t swamped by coordination overhead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a boon for the individual units and, subsequently, is why the modern enterprise is no longer a single “blob” of software, but a complex, interconnected distributed system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide6.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Reductionism Can Lead To Incoherence&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reductionism has been the primary mechanism that we’ve attempted to scale the systems. However, that has led to an interesting side effect: each one of these subsystems potentially becomes uncoordinated from the larger whole. The lack of visibility into other parts of the system, schedule crunch, and comprehension overload cause developers to make decisions optimized for a local scope and often suboptimal for the overall system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each may work toward its local optimized maximum. Examples may include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upgrading to a new dependency version&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responding to an audit request&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding a feature in response to a customer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleansing data for ML initiative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working on performance improvements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewriting in the latest framework mentioned on HackerNews because “it looks cool”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We optimize subsystems to the detriment of the entire system all the time. And that becomes its own form of “conceptual debt” for the whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide7.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The Incoherence Penalty Stifles Change&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomy, on its own, is insufficient to address the incoherence penalty. For companies to benefit from better, faster decision-making on the part of their autonomous teams – to meet the volume and velocity of critical decisions to be made during a time of change - those decisions need to be aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hardest part of modern software development has less to do with the technology itself, it has much more to do with maintaining coherence across the parts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Nygard is an author and frequent speaker on software development. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.michaelnygard.com/blog/2018/01/coherence-penalty-for-humans/&quot;&gt;In a powerful blog post, he defined the “Incoherence Penalty” as&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Whatever time the team members spend re-establishing a common view of the universe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Michael points out, the penalty might be small for a half-dozen people in a single shared workspace or across a half-dozen components. A whiteboard session every week or so is enough to keep everyone aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the effort necessary to maintain alignment grows as we scale and as the system becomes more complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For another perspective on this scale challenge, and why it is so difficult to teach at the university level, &lt;a href=&quot;https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2022/04/23/software-engineering-in-the-large-the-coordination-challenge/&quot;&gt;see this great blog post from Lorin Hochstein&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide8.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;We Often Model the Architectural Relationships&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a complex system, the power is in the relationships between the pieces, the places where these things interact. With dynamic systems, these are the API interfaces. When we diagram these things, it is almost always in terms of technology. We go in hoping to identify a new architecture or tool that will provide the silver bullet to the incoherence problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide9.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;However, We Often Leave Human Systems Vague or Undefined&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what is missing from these diagrams are the interactions between humans. In creating change, we shouldn’t ignore a significant source of the relationships in an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if we’re going to save software, if we’re going to create change in modern development environments, we need to be able to create coherence. And to create coherence, that means applying skills to the human relationships equally, if not more, than the energy we expend on the software integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide10.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;This Is Unfortunate, As Tech Doesn&apos;t Create Alignment; People Do&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology does not create alignment - people do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autonomy and alignment are not opposing ends of a spectrum but complimentary. The more alignment you have, the more autonomy can be supported, assured that the decisions made will move the organization in the same direction, not pull it apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to be successful, here are, rapid-fire, seven skills essential to addressing the human system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide11.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;There Are Seven Skills For Extending Influence Over a Complex System&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about each of these, comprehensively, could be an entire talk on its own. What I will attempt to do is introduce the concept in the time we have left, reference some powerful places to get started for further exploration, and we’ll go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide12.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Crafting a Compelling Vision&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an idea for how something could be better is not the same as having a compelling vision. If all success needed was a good idea, then my domain name registrations would have made me rich long ago. It takes work to go from an idea of what to do to a vision that rallies other to the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@pavement_special&quot;&gt;Riccardo Annandale&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/7e2pe9wjL9M&quot;&gt;Unsplash &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide13.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Start at the End: What Are You Celebrating?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book, Agendashift, author and Agile coach Mike Burrows lays out a formal process for creating a compelling vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He starts with the concept of this celebration. So perhaps in my organization, I might say, “&lt;em&gt;I wish we had every API on the same gateway, rather than everyone punching holes through the firewall with their own redundant infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;”. Going through this exercise, called the celebration, we need to reframe that because, in my head, I’ve already picked a solution. I’ve already said, “&lt;em&gt;I want this external vendor and I want everybody to be on it&lt;/em&gt;”. But that’s not an outcome. In terms of the business value to be delivered, it’s already assuming a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following this exercise, called the celebration, we proceed to answer the “5 questions that start with ‘W’” – who, what, when, where, and why. When I’m doing is I’m unpacking, this preconceived notion of everybody on a single vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide14.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Recast Obstacles As Outcomes, Not Absences&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike also defines this other exercise called the 15-minute FOTO, which is also incredibly adept at reframing, but this time reframing obstacles to outcomes. What obstacles keep us from getting to this wonderful celebration? Well, this obstacle that I’m writing down, more likely than not, is in the form of an absence. So, for example, I might say one of our organizational problems is that we don’t have meaningful postmortems. That’s an absence of something. And again, that absence assumes a solution; it assumes that postmortems should be done, but it doesn’t necessarily define the outcomes we’re trying to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recasting obstacles in this way can have two significant benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It encourages you to be specific (perhaps the request for postmoterms has nothing to do with learning, but rather an individual wishing closure, a milestone, after a significant effort)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoids describing the problem only in terms of the absence of some prematurely defined solution (there may be other prompts or activities to re-incorporate learnings other than a postmortem event)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, maybe the reason that somebody is suggesting postmortems is not that they want to incorporate learnings. Perhaps they wish they had a more definitive milestone. When a project is done, maybe there’s a backlog that seems endless. A postmortems would act, in this case, as a milestone, as a means of recognizing achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in reframing things you go beyond obstacles to discover what people value. That true value is at the heart of a compelling vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide15.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A Vision Comprises More Than Just An Idea&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have what you’re trying to accomplish in terms of outcomes, you can go ahead and create your compelling vision. Your vision should include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-clear-articulation-of-the-current-state&quot;&gt;A Clear Articulation of the Current State&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A transition story will highlight how the past way of doing things is unsustainable and how it has led to the current crisis; a crisis which requires new ideas (your ideas!) to overcome. The articulation must explain why the change should happen now. As I work with companies, we spend a lot of time here. Sometimes the source of urgency is obvious: things like a pending bankruptcy or a public security breach are in the driver’s seat. But, often, your idea must confront a suboptimal, yet functional, status quo. The key is creating a sense of urgency, not panic, about why the change must happen now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-attractive-future&quot;&gt;An Attractive Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A story must emphasize that the future is not a fixed, predetermined point but something that can be changed. We can’t predict the future, but we can try to invent one with more desirable outcomes. If instituting a change is worth doing, we must have a coherent story about the new possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-identity-for-participants&quot;&gt;A New Identity for Participants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System change requires working in new configurations, often with new (to you) people. Stepping beyond the comfort zone of our friends and colleagues means engaging with strangers and opponents who may not have a shared understanding. A story should enable people to recognize their shared interdependence in the system, thus creating a shared identity. It must show how the sub-optimal future cannot be solved by individual stakeholders alone and how a new network with new relationships can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-path-connecting-it-together&quot;&gt;A Path Connecting It Together&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, a story must point people toward needed change. Part of this includes articulating what progress along the path looks and feels like.
A vital aspect of a story is how it links current actions to the desired future destination. Connecting these things increases the understanding of our responsibility and agency within a system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/10/CreatingCompellingStories&quot;&gt;I’ve written an example arguing for remote work elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide16.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Coalition Building&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major change is challenging to accomplish. No one individual, no matter how charismatic, can develop the perfect vision, communicate it to everyone, eliminate all obstacles, perform all the experiments, and tally all the short-term wins. What is needed is a coalition able to shoulder the load and recruit new help as the effort grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the most critical aspects of coalition building is that &lt;strong&gt;you’re attempting inclusion, not assimilation&lt;/strong&gt;. A coalition should elevate the participating members’ unique skills, experiences, and desires. A sense of belonging is essential to sustaining a movement through difficult times. This means that members should still feel uniquely valued. They’re going to be bringing their ideas, assumptions, experiences, and preferences. A sign of a healthy coalition is if the vision is evolving, changing, and adapting because of the participation of new individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jasongoodman_youxventures&quot;&gt;Jason Goodman&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/6awfTPLGaCE&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide17.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Create Onramps For All Interests And Abilities&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are just a handful of activities for involving people in your coalition-building. Your call to action can be much more diverse than “please read this blog post” or “attend our office hours”. Those, in a vacuum, are not that compelling. People have a variety of different availabilities, talents, and inclinations. In building your coalition, create inclusion points or on-ramps that can accommodate that variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book &lt;em&gt;More Fearless Change&lt;/em&gt; is not like a regular book; you don’t read it from beginning to end. Instead, like a cookbook, it includes numerous recipes for things to try. They start from very simple like “attend this lunch-n-learn” and escalate to holding an internal developer conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide18.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Move From Mobilizing To Organizing&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be able to launch an internal developer conference at the beginning of your change effort. But the critical thing is accommodating and allowing for people to engage with your effort as they are able. And once you start doing that, you need to start thinking about moving people from mobilizing to organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transactional mobilizing&lt;/strong&gt; is a relatively straightforward concept– people offer to help, and you give them a task to do. This is the kind of low-effort “Retweet if you agree” campaigning on social media. While that may be easy to do, the actual, long-lasting impact is low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transformational organizing&lt;/strong&gt; is about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying, recruiting, and developing other people with whom we share purpose to form a collective identity for the change distinct from their previous role&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Growing a group of people that recognize and express responsibility to each other (if they had to pay dues, would they still belong)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transforming the resources of that group into the power needed to make and sustain change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many folks are happy to help if it doesn’t cost them time, energy, budget, or resources. A significant task of coalition building is moving people who are already concerned about the issue to those willing to do something, even at a cost to themselves. Organizing deepens participants’ understanding of who they are and why they want to make the change. In doing so, they then identify others who share their values and recruit to continue building change momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j4_nFUX6Z2Q&quot;&gt;check out this video from Hahrie Han on the difference between Mobilizing and Organizing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide19.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Communicating&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So obviously, that includes a lot of communication. When I say communication, I don’t mean standing on the top of your building with a bullhorn and yelling your awesome idea at people. When it comes to change, people don’t need a good talking to – to make a change, they need a good listening to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to be more successful, efficient, and capable in their roles. However, as important is retaining their autonomy. Just ordering people to do something, even if it is in their best interest, rarely works. For example, I absolutely understand that I should eat healthier but still bristle whenever my wife brings it up. If communicating comes across as a command or a mandate, it will most likely create resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@brookecagle&quot;&gt;Brooke Cagle&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/g1Kr4Ozfoac&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide20.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Evoke The Reasons For Change They Already Have&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of our daily conversation is a default activity: it just happens. By contrast, strategic conversations deliberately use limited time and attention with another person to achieve a specific goal. In our case, it is about furthering our change initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivational interviewing&lt;/strong&gt; is a conversation technique designed to strengthen personal motivation and commitment to a specific goal. It does this by eliciting and exploring a person’s values and beliefs within an atmosphere of acceptance and compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So rather than charging into a forum to say, “Hey everybody, listen to my idea,” motivational interviewing starts with asking open questions to find out more about the person:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did they join the company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is it about the company that they enjoy?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the recent accomplishments that they’re proud of?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do they find challenging?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through that listening, you’ll get an understanding of the things that they value. You can then affirm the strengths of their beliefs system that align with the kind of change you’re trying to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflective listening underscores the individual is being listened to; not everything needs to be rephrased or repeated. Much of the exchange should be those things that support or bolster already existing attitudes or beliefs that align with the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, summarize. Connect the dots between the things that they already believe and want to accomplish in their own careers with the things you are trying to make happen within the organization. Create that alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bakadesuyo.com/2022/05/get-people-to-change/&quot;&gt;A more detailed description of the usefulness of motivational interview is available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional perspective on having strategic conversations with potentially resistant people, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2021/03/persuading-the-unpersuadable&quot;&gt;see the article “Persuading the Unpersuadable by Adam Grant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide21.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Bring Schwag And End With A Call To Action&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, during these conversations, bring schwag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a picture of my laptop. And as you can see, I’ve been part of a few efforts. What is important to remember is that the more abstract the change effort, the more helpful it is to have a physical manifestation. It doesn’t have to be just stickers. Challenge coins, pins, posters, t-shirts, or polos are all valid. What you pick ultimately depends on the culture and what kind of currencies are exchanged. But bottom line, have something representing the mission that can extend and communicate change after you are gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both the conversation, and with your swag, end with a call to action. If you study this image, you might notice that few of these images even have a link where people might go to find out more. Ultimately, you don’t want to miss an opportunity to connect people with one of your carefully crafted coalition on-ramps created in step 2. Invite people to the next step on their journey as part of your communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide22.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Experimenting&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make change possible, we likely need to understand more about what is required – we need to adapt and adjust based on what we learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often, we think great change requires atomic, massive events that stand out like a fork in the road – at Amazon, they refer to these as “one-way doors”. And as you might imagine, trying to do that huge thing will generate a proportional amount of resistance. However, a powerful skill is shrinking the change being asked for, running several simultaneous experiments, and then leveraging the learnings to make the change more effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, during our vision creation in step 1, we’ve reframed our obstacles and we’re looking for outcomes. We know that there might be a host of things we might do to deliver and achieve that outcome. From the coalition we’re assembling in step 2, we might have people in a position to try different things and report back. This is where we engage them to run experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jkoblitz&quot;&gt;Julia Koblitz&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/RlOAwXt2fEA&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide23.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Small Experiments Equate To Less Resistance&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experimentation skill is how we engage those groups, gather the results and continue to create a flywheel of exciting revelations that subsequently inform more experiments, getting us closer to our ideal state. Small experiments equal less resistance. We always need to understand and consider how we make an experiment safer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an experiment is too big to fail, it’s no longer an experiment. And that becomes very, very, very scary for your leadership team to rally behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@johnpcutler/why-experiment-1169339b2ddc&quot;&gt;More from John Cutler and the importance of experiments here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide24.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Experiments Create Short Term Wins&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of things make a good experiment? Good experiments are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unambiguous&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clearly relate to the change effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cutlefish.substack.com/p/tbm-953-some-mvp-and-experiment-tips&quot;&gt;For a host of additional considerations when running experiments, I again refer you to John Cutler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide25.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Celebrating&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once our experiments begin generating results, we need to celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I’m not talking toga parties, or gender reveal events. When done strategically in a business context, celebration is a skill to help further influence a complex system to align behind the change you seek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us don’t have a plan for celebrating accomplishments. Moreover, the past 2-and-a-half-years of remote work and pandemic isolation has meant that regular notice and elevation of good work has been much more difficult. That is a problem because celebration is a significant opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;cement the lessons learned&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;strengthen the relationships between people that make future achievement more plausible&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change and growth are promoted through positive emotions more than through disciplined practice&lt;/strong&gt;. Celebrating small wins produced by our experimentation reinforces the learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@priscilladupreez&quot;&gt;Priscilla Du Preez&lt;/a&gt; on Unsplash. *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide26.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Leverage Your Company&apos;s Internal Recognition Pyramid&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as the accomplishments we celebrate don’t have to be large, our celebrations don’t have to be grandiose; they just need to be meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every company of decent size has an internal kudos or recognition program. There might be that yearly dinner with the CEO for the people nominated and selected for extraordinary effort. This formal type of program is at the top of the pyramid. And while those are nice, they only impact between 1% and 10% of the employees at any given company, and they do so infrequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are the informal programs where you can give people kudos or send a gift card. That might be monthly or quarterly (if people remember). Perhaps that gets between a third and half of employees. A $50 gift card to Amazon is nice, but it still isn’t the kind of continuous reinforcement we need to see for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested in the sincere, daily detailed word of thanks to a person illustrating the desired behavior. When done correctly, these expressions of gratitude become their currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday recognition is about expressing thanks to people and acknowledging others for doing fantastic work in distinctive ways. It should be weekly, if not daily, and can impact 80-100% of employees, if done correctly. While formal, “big” recognition activities may be appropriate for significant milestones, it is the regular, persistent reinforcement that can have 2 to 3 times greater impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous roles, I had calendar time blocked out once a week to express gratitude. In some cases, this might have been a note to people that had presented an above-average API description. Other times, it might have been someone that asked a great question during a group event. Sometimes, it might have been a team that had their big launch. Regardless of what it was,  I made sure that I spent some time reflecting the positive qualities they exhibited and connecting how their success was related to the change underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, like most corporate kudos systems, their manager also saw these messages. Managers are busy. They’re usually grateful for any additional signals to help them triangulate where their team is and how they’re doing. What makes these nudges valuable is that they’re scarce– we take it for granted that people know how they’re doing. Taking the time to create something “official”, that persists as part of the employee’s work history, creates a currency that can be paid out during performance reviews and quarterly sync-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in more on authentic recognition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://authenticrecognition.com/where-should-i-focus-my-time-on-improving-recognition-at-work/&quot;&gt;there’s more available elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide27.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;There Are Several Ways To Frame Success&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting, it may be challenging to find ways not to feel like a broken record, repeatedly telling people “good job”. The encouragement that is delivered needs to be authentic. Furthermore, some people respond differently to different types of feedback. Some like feedback about their own performance. Others react more strongly to a favorable comparison with their peers. Others prefer to hear good news despite disappointing performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework is from Dr. BJ Fogg’s book, Tiny Habits. It is not meant as a checklist, but as a handful of examples when framing encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide28.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Empowering Others&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical momentum is lost whenever you let up before the job is done. Regression may follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In successful transformation, the guiding coalition uses the credibility afforded by the short-term wins to push forward faster, tackling even more or more extensive projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@heylagostechie&quot;&gt;Mars Sector-6&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/IgUR1iX0mqM&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide29.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Different People React To Change Differently&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incumbent to realize that not everybody embraces change to the same degree. This illustration is of the innovation distribution curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curve illustrates that within any population, you have the following distribution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovators (2.5%): Will something for no other reason than it is new&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Early Adopters (13.5%): More discrete in their selections than innovators, adopters use status as early pioneers to maintain social credibility with their peer group while taking on less risk (cutting versus bleeding edge)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Early Majority (34%): Willing to adopt innovations, but only after seeing what success with the innovation looks like among their peers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Late Majority (34%): Are reluctant to adopt the innovation unless specifically told they have to, after which they require higher levels of support and encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laggards (16%): Those who actively resist change and will actively work to thwart an innovation for no other reason than it is new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide30.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Different People Require Different Resources&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that I point this out is that different people will require other support. A mistake would be to treat all those necessary to change as a single, monolithic group. To best support them, it is vital to recognize where they are in their journey and meet them where they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide31.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Terraforming the Culture&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New practices, if they are to continue beyond the effort of the guiding coalition, need to grow deep roots. Without them, the existing cultural norms will reassert themselves when the transformation program or initiative stops working day and night. Shallow roots require constant watering. Without the attention, the practices dry up, wither, and die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the new practices made in a transformation effort are not compatible with the relevant cultures, they will always be subject to regression. Changes in a workgroup, a line of business, or even an entire company can come undone, even after years of effort, because the new approaches haven’t been anchored firmly in-group norms and values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, the final stage in changing complex systems is terraforming the culture to make change last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@danteov_seen&quot;&gt;Nikola Jovanovic&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/OBok3F8buKY&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide32.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Inverse Conway Maneuvers Are Hard In Practice&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the last step in influencing a complex system to align behind a change, I want to touch on culture briefly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those familiar with the API space, you’re probably familiar with the concept of Conway’s Law. You may also be familiar with the Reverse or Inverse Conway Maneuver. In the Inverse Conway Maneuver, the idea is that redesign your organizational structure to produce the kind of software that you want. It is a powerful idea, but having lived through my share of enterprise re-orgs, I can definitively say this is easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2017/12/07/ConwayAndAPIDesign&quot;&gt;I’ve written about the impacts of Conway’s Law on software design before&lt;/a&gt;. For coverage of the &lt;em&gt;nuance&lt;/em&gt; required for successful Inverse Conway Maneuvers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tnetapinotes.substack.com/p/net-api-notes-for-2022-06-07-issue-199&quot;&gt;check out this recent edition of my newsletter, Net API Notes #199&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide33.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Plant The Change In Operations, Processes, and Rewards&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for a seed of an idea to grow, it must be firmly planted in the company’s culture. This means that it is part of the ongoing activities. That could mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People with experience with the idea are explicitly sought as part of the hiring process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The importance of the change is specially highlighted as part of employee onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demonstration of the change is part of the reward performance structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason that this is step 7. While some steps, like coalition building, communication, and experimentation should be done simultaneously, changing cultural norms should only be attempted when sufficient momentum is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide34.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Next Steps&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to end with a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This second - think about something in your current work you wish (or needs) to be better. This shouldn’t be hard - nothing is perfect and we’re not trying to prioritize here - that can be done later. What’s the first thing that comes to mind?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Today - whether it is through Slack, Microsoft teams, an email, or your corporate HR feedback system, send a note of gratitude to someone that you’ve seen handle the problem well. “Hey Tim, I just wanted to let you know I was really impressed with how you keep the test suite current. That takes care and consideration I don’t always see. Thank you.” The goal here is not to solve all the things for all the time - the goal here is to begin a practice of reinforcing positive behaviors.
Create a recurring task to do this on a regular basis. And make sure the feedback is genuine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This week - schedule a chat - over lunch, if you’re back in the office, or a casual “sync” with someone who might feel the same way. Explore what they might have tried and what the results were. And ask if they are aware of others to have further conversations with.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably won’t be able to enact the entirety of your change immediately. But you will have taken the important first steps of acknowledging the &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; system at play. You started down the path of creating greater alignment and, in doing so, begun to bridge the fragmentation that exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/06/Slide35.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Better Bits - A Book To Expand On These Ideas&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had mentioned that there was so much more that could be said for each skill. I also strongly believe that successfully learning these skills is essential for us to navigate not just our complex software systems, but life itself. That’s why I’m writing a book called &lt;strong&gt;Better Bits&lt;/strong&gt;. If these topics are of interest to you, &lt;a href=&quot;betterbits.substack.com&quot;&gt;sign up for updates at betterbits.substack.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A video recording of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fLr1l4nUIgQ&quot;&gt;Deliberate Complexity delivery of this talk is available online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/06/28/SevenSkillsToSaveSoftware</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/06/28/SevenSkillsToSaveSoftware</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>Presentations</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Software Pipelines As Behavioral Prompts</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/06/25/ArchitectureIsLaw&quot;&gt;previously discussed how important the environment is in creating meaningful behavioral change&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/07/16/GithubCopilot&quot;&gt;also suggested that the developer’s IDE (or Integrated Development Environment) was an influential source of positive behavioral prompting&lt;/a&gt;. If we move beyond just the single IDE, the software development pipeline could &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be an environment capable of prompting desirable outcomes. This process is known as &lt;strong&gt;The Golden Path&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charity Majors is the co-founder and CTO of Honeycomb, makers of code observability software. &lt;a href=&quot;https://charity.wtf/tag/scaling/&quot;&gt;She describes the Golden Path like so&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Tell all your engineers that going forward, the Golden Path will be fully supported by the org.  Upgrades, patches, security fixes; backups, monitoring, build pipeline; deploy tooling, artifact versioning, development environment, even tier 1 on call support.  Pave the path with gold.  Nobody HAS to use these components … but if they don’t, they’re on their own.  They will have to support it themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all but the smallest of dev shops, there are advantages to having centralized processes and infrastructure. “Approved” tech stacks are standard to ensure proper staffing and triage is possible. A single log standard can save copious amounts of time and effort when in the thick of an outage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, governance - either in the form of an Architectural Review Board, Center of Excellence, or some other bureaucratic entity - dictates the software development behaviors they expect others to follow. An example might be “We are a Spring Boot and Node shop” or “Every new service must implement Open Tracing”. The bulk of energy is then expended on detection and enforcement, which - honestly - is probably not how anybody dreamed they’d be spending their productive waking hours. (The lack of of career development path for this work is a topic for another post; all too many enterprises end up parking their most passionate system thinkers into these professional cul-de-sacs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, employing a Golden Path strategy directs that energy to create a superior developer experience. Sure, each team that needs to make an API &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; select, configure, and operate their own API gateway. They &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; roll their own authentication and key provisioning server. They &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; customize their own CI/CD pipeline. But if there is a platform team providing a well-supported, consistently performant,  and feature-compatible equivalent, why would they? And some point, the novelty of tinkering with configuration files wears off, and a realization sets in: dithering with non-differentiating technology is not the same as delivering business value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a Golden Path is work. However, suppose you can create an environment where doing the right thing is the easy thing. In that case, you are significantly further along than relying on best faith efforts and goosing external incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022/golden-path.png#wide&quot; alt=&quot;A trail through fall trees in northern Colorado. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2022-05-05&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along these same lines is Yunong Xiao’s 2017 presentation entitled, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/news/2017/06/paved-paas-netflix/&quot;&gt;The Paved PaaS to Microservices at Netflix&lt;/a&gt;”. “Paved Path” is the same concept as “Golden Path”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/04/14/GoldenPath</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/04/14/GoldenPath</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>&quot;Just Tell Me What To Do&quot;</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.acast.com/s/ctrlaltdelete/falling-out-of-love-with-the-internet-disconnected-audiobook&quot;&gt;In a recent edition of the Ctrl Alt Delete podcast&lt;/a&gt;, host Emma Gannon described her discovery of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/290368045246716/&quot;&gt;a Facebook group that helps individuals make small decisions&lt;/a&gt;. “Can’t decide between two shirts?” it asks. “Can’t choose pizza or spaghetti for dinner? Let this group make small decisions for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “the before times”, I would have no use for a group like this. However, in the pandemic times, there are simply some evenings where this sort of “outsourcing of the banal” seems attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/22/StandardsAsAccelerant&quot;&gt;I wrote about decision fatigue before&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Decision fatigue, or when the mind becomes exhausted after a sustained period of decision making, often follows. Many became acutely aware of decision fatigue during the Covid-19 pandemic. Suddenly, even trivial activities like opening doors and touching elevator buttons were a puzzle. Not only had the number of decisions skyrocketed, but the heavier impact that those decisions carried (the possibility of illness or death) created outsized effects: stress, loss of energy, and lowered mental capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last several years have been stressful. When individuals weren’t navigating a pandemic, they were experiencing everything from political unrest to supply chain bottlenecks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2022/03/10/1085792118/americans-stress-is-spiking-over-inflation-war-in-ukraine-survey-finds&quot;&gt;And then there was a war&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses dealing with API sprawl are also stressed. The unprecedented events have meant that software architects, already stretched thin, have experienced higher levels of decision fatigue.  “&lt;strong&gt;Just tell me what to do&lt;/strong&gt;” is a common request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-software-strategic-impact&quot;&gt;The Software Strategic Impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is understandable how individuals would desire to bypass the hurly-burly of defining first principles - those are yet more decisions! “If it is good enough for Stripe or Twilio”, the thinking goes, “it is good enough for us- we don’t have energy for that vision quest stuff; there’s too much to do!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my concern is what happens on &lt;em&gt;Day-2&lt;/em&gt; with this “made to order” approach to API standards. “&lt;strong&gt;Day-2&lt;/strong&gt;” is a DevOps term. It relates to the challenges that arise not from changes to a specific application but the more significant abstract processes and operations. For API standards, Day-2 problems relate to how a set of design standards, architectural guidance, or run-books get disseminated, adopted, and improved upon over time. It is one thing to gather key leaders together to announce expectations for a newly established API program. It is another thing entirely to continue to drive engagement and improvement among stakeholders in month 6. Without creating the crucible to form first principles, this greater identity and shared purpose aren’t formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, without discussion, adopting standards developed elsewhere may lead to bloated and ill-fitting style guides. Every standard a developer must follow introduces a grain of cognitive friction. Sometimes, the price paid is worth the production-environment benefit. However, every organization is different, with its own experience, style maturity, expertise, market, and desired end goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each requirement in a standards doc should be able to answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the better API outcome created by this standard?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are we willing to sacrifice (stop doing) to make this standard possible?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will “better” manifest in our day-to-day activities, behaviors, and interactions?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will we know if the standard is working?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has anyone done this before?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are we inviting others to a better future or imposing a singular vision of a future onto others?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the non-obvious implication of this standard?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Bonus) How will we automate the education and enforcement of this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without considering the above questions, adopting standards from a different context will (best case) result in unnecessary effort and (worst case) be ignored. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://catalyst.concentrix.com/&quot;&gt;consulting practice I work for&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of incorporating this nuance through careful, considered conversations. Together, we arrive at a healthier place for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good-news&quot;&gt;The Good News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Cutler is a product management expert and frequent communicator. He also sees the stress among the change agents he works with. Through that work, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cutlefish.substack.com/p/tbm-46b52-7-lessons-for-sustainable&quot;&gt;he also shares some hope&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In the last eight months, I have spent countless hours speaking with change agents. They reach out to me for product management advice, but these conversations inevitably seem to turn to the topic of how to nudge their organizations in new directions. During the pandemic these discussions have acquired a new sense of urgency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Their anxiety is palpable.  They care for their teams but are overwhelmed by the challenges, and the opportunities, facing them.  To be sure, the pandemic has been catastrophic on every level, but many of the change agents I have spoken to are finally receiving the support they need and bringing about the impact they have long wanted to see. Their work is paying off, at the most inopportune time. There is movement in the right direction.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these unprecedented times, we must recognize the inherent opportunity in the status quo fracturing. Introducing change now does not have to contend with bursting people’s “normal” bubble. Nothing is normal! &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Moved_My_Cheese%3F&quot;&gt;The cheese has already been moved&lt;/a&gt;. Energy is available if someone dares to channel it. That is not to say that change, like defining a set of API standards for a sprawling and increasingly problematic ecosystem, is easy. &lt;em&gt;However&lt;/em&gt;, it does mean people are more likely to accept something new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/03/29/JustTellMeWhatToDo</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2022/03/29/JustTellMeWhatToDo</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Standards as Accelerant</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/11/willy-wonka-rules-of-the-house.gif&quot; alt=&quot;An animated GIF of Willy Wonka stating &apos;Sorry, rules of the house.&apos;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When debating IT governance structures, people make lots of claims. One is that decentralized governance “maximizes” team freedom. Or, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Increased standardization decreases the freedom for teams and people to innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/01/PolarityMappingAndAPIGovernance&quot;&gt;I argue in my piece on the usefulness of polarity maps&lt;/a&gt;, we shouldn’t treat IT governance as a false dichotomy or “centralized versus decentralized”.  There is a spectrum of implementations that can blend positive aspects from both sides. Standards and guidelines tactics can help focus and direct work in productive directions &lt;em&gt;when used correctly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;decision-fatigue-happens-when-too-many-decisions-are-delegated-to-the-lowest-level&quot;&gt;Decision Fatigue Happens When Too Many Decisions Are Delegated To The Lowest Level&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision paralysis&lt;/strong&gt; is when an individual or group has difficulty taking action because the solution space is too large (also called “analysis paralysis”). &lt;strong&gt;Decision fatigue&lt;/strong&gt;, or when the mind becomes exhausted after a sustained period of decision making, often follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many became acutely aware of decision fatigue during the Covid-19 pandemic. Suddenly, even trivial activities like opening doors and touching elevator buttons were a puzzle. Not only had the number of decisions skyrocketed, but the heavier impact that those decisions carried (the possibility of illness or death) created outsized effects: stress, loss of energy, and lowered mental capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse, attempting to make decisions on rapidly shifting data impedes speed and confidence. It is reasonable that pandemic guidelines would change to reflect new information. However, the early lack of a single, centralized message and delegation to local authorities (many of whom were ill-equipped to be making epidemiolocal judgments) created a cacophony of competing, sometimes contradictory, guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar conditions exist in IT environments where &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; decision-making authority has been deferred to individuals or small teams. It is challenging to “be innovative” under such circumstances. Encouraging folks to “just make better decisions” will not create the desired outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;standards-free-focus-for-what-matters&quot;&gt;Standards Free Focus For What Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear, concise standards serve as guide rails that steer limited bandwidth toward productive activity. Rather than debating how to express pagination for the thousandth time, teams can adopt a pre-existing company style, thus diverting their energy toward creating unique business value. Instead of wrestling with the decisions involved in understanding and coding around another bespoke datetime format, internal API producers could accelerate delivery by uniformly adopting a widely known standard, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO_8601&quot;&gt;ISO 8601&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all implements in the governance toolkit, standards, guidelines, and rules can be misused. However, when applied appropriately, clear policy and regulation can reduce decision fatigue and free teams’ time and energy for more meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/22/StandardsAsAccelerant</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/22/StandardsAsAccelerant</guid>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pandemic-Led Digital Transformation; You&apos;re Doing it Wrong</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The pandemic impacted businesses in many ways, some obvious (hello, work-from-home) and some so subtle that they may not even be apparent for several more years. One aspect pointed to in business and technology press is how the pandemic “sped up” digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How true that statement is depends to large degree with how you define digital transformation. I was recently asked for my thoughts on the matter and I thought I’d also share them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;was-the-pandemic-a-catalyst-for-digital-transformation-or-do-you-think-most-companies-missed-the-chance-to-drive-their-digital-transformation-initiatives-forward&quot;&gt;Was the pandemic a catalyst for digital transformation? Or do you think most companies missed the chance to drive their digital transformation initiatives forward?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change is hard, even under the best of conditions. We often see a change in moments of crisis (takeovers, bankruptcy, or public scandal) when the call-to-action is finally loud enough to overcome people’s comfort with the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic (and ensuing intertwined crises including supply chain disruption, political upheaval, and social unrest) provided plenty of impetus to change. However, companies need to assess whether what changed is simply doing the same thing as before, but over video and instant messaging? Or did they embrace the situation to introduce new norms, processes, and products to their business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the same thing as before, but more efficiently, is called &lt;em&gt;digitization&lt;/em&gt;. It &lt;strong&gt;was not&lt;/strong&gt; a digital transformation. At the beginning of the pandemic, I can’t fault leaders for this response; they did the best they could to maintain any semblance of “normal” even in the most adverse conditions-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-even if that meant attempting rituals that were a poor fit for this new reality. A cringe-worthy example was the rash of post-pandemic “virtual happy hours”. The attempts to connect came from a place of good-intentions: replicate the after-hours get together to foster a sense of team. People assumed they’d do the same thing as before but BYOB over Zoom with everyone working from home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, rather than being something to look forward to, these become loathsome, dreary affairs that only reminded people of how weird and isolated the pandemic made all of us. After a day filled with imperfect video meetings, the last thing most people wish for is more time at their makeshift desk, glued to the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital transformation requires examining these things that used to work, identifying what was valuable, and imbuing those properties in forms better adapted for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-would-you-advise-companies-to-take-on-digital-transformation-in-2022&quot;&gt;How would you advise companies to take on digital transformation in 2022?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into 2022, we have a better sense that there will not be an exact return to pre-pandemic “business-as-usual”. Leaders need to stop thinking about Band-Aids and temporary fixes while waiting to return to the way things were before. Instead, leaders need to take a hard look at which parts of their business fared better than others. Which areas were ill-suited to the rapid, consistent change? And how vital is fixing those areas before the next shock?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital business design is the holistic organizational configuration of people (roles, accountabilities, structures, and skills), processes (workflows, routines, procedures), &lt;strong&gt;and then&lt;/strong&gt; technology (infrastructure and applications). Someone somewhere is experimenting with providing employees with meaning, connection, and advancement in these necessary new ways. That person can either be at your company or employed by a disruptive rival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where are your experiments? How do you measure whether the new ways, made possible by digital technology, are better than the old ways? How are you discovering new, uninterruptible ways of delivering business value? If companies haven’t thought about or answered these questions, now is the time to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update, 2021-11-12&lt;/em&gt;
While wargaming likely 2022 API scenerios, I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forrester.com/blogs/predictions-2022/&quot;&gt;this 2022 set of predictions from Forrester&lt;/a&gt; (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Business leaders are grappling with big employee-related questions right now. When (or if) to return to the office environment and how? We predict that only 10% of firms will shift to a fully remote model, and 30% will go back to a fully in-office model. The remaining 60% of firms will shift to a hybrid model, and one-third of those firms will fail in their first attempt at anywhere work. Why? &lt;em&gt;Because shifting to a hybrid model while still designing meetings, job roles, and promotion opportunities around face-to-face experiences will send productivity plummeting and lead execs to question the model instead of the processes they cling to.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have not only the opportunity, but the imagination to create new forms. A return to “business-as-normal” is a strategic mirage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/09/DigitalTransformation-YoureDoingItWrong</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/09/DigitalTransformation-YoureDoingItWrong</guid>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                <category>Software Management</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why is there no &apos;Correct&apos; API Lifecycle?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, my colleagues in the Postman Open Technologies Program and I were discussing API lifecycles. It quickly became apparent that we each had our own mental models for what was (and *most certainly &lt;strong&gt;was not&lt;/strong&gt; *) worthy of inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick survey of search results hints that the industry has as many opinions about what constitutes an API lifecycle as we had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://searchapparchitecture.techtarget.com/feature/5-stages-of-an-API-lifecycle-explained&quot;&gt;TechTarget has a five-step lifecycle&lt;/a&gt;: plan, dev, test, deploy, retire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apigee.com/about/cp/api-lifecycle-management&quot;&gt;Apigee promotes an 8-step version&lt;/a&gt;: design, develop, secure, publish, scale, monitor, analyze, monetize&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.axway.com/amplify-products/api-management/api-lifecycle-management&quot;&gt;Axway lists three steps&lt;/a&gt; (with many, many substeps): creation, control, consumption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://swagger.io/blog/api-strategy/what-is-api-lifecycle-management/&quot;&gt;SmartBear mentions 5&lt;/a&gt;, but a &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; five than TechTarget: planning and designing, developing, testing, deploying, retiring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mulesoft.com/webinars/api/full-lifecycle-api-management-anypoint-platform&quot;&gt;Mulesoft mentions 4&lt;/a&gt;: design, implementation, security, management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2019/02/25/full-api-lifecycle-management-a-primer&quot;&gt;Redhat features a confusing conjoined set of circles&lt;/a&gt;, and 13(!) kitchen-sink steps: strategy, design, mock, test, implement, deploy, secure, manage, discover, develop, consume, monitor, monetize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process that evolved during my time as Capital One’s Center of Excellence Director skewed heavily to the needs of a large, mature, and internal system. As a result, our API lifecycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made no mention of monetization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emphasized discrete team ownership and end-of-life elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hand-waved past development requires as code creation had its process, controls, and oversite group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process that resonated for us, eventually, was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover&lt;/strong&gt;: Has someone already solved this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define&lt;/strong&gt;: Who will own the work at a team and LOB level, what access models will be in place, what SLAs need to be met, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage with stakeholders, make an OpenAPI representation, get feedback, iterate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop&lt;/strong&gt;: Code the thing (subject to many, many other criteria outside the API group)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deprecate&lt;/strong&gt;: Plan for ending or superseding with a subsequent version; includes communication plan, timeline expectations, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete&lt;/strong&gt; Define what info sticks around for historical purposes while ensuring any executables, access tokens, and gateway routing is removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why all the variation? Why isn’t there a “right” or “correct” API lifecycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the variation is largely because lifecycles are created within companies to generate particular outcomes. Nobody installs a lifecycle for the sake of having more to train and enforce. If sloppy design leads to losses in a competitive marketplace, a company should have an explicit “design” step in its lifecycle to drive better outcomes. If security has been a mish-mash, a dedicated “security” step should be elevated as part of a lifecycle process to prompt more focus on correcting that behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A monitoring company is sure to list monitoring as part of its lifecycle. A company that sells documentation software will also elevate documentation to a high-level concern. It will depend on the vendor, but whatever their product excels at will probably be part of whatever lifecycle they promote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With companies looking at instituting a lifecycle, I’d &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; find the burning problem that would benefit from additional learning, creativity, and focus. That would be the first touchstone called out in the path between an idea’s inception and production runtime. I’d then continue to build up and out from there. Dropping an entire thirteen-step lifecycle where none previously existed isn’t just introducing a massive amount of disruption all at once - it also summons &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/22/OvercomingChangeResistance&quot;&gt;a proportional amount of resistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/02/WhatIsTheAPILifecycle</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/02/WhatIsTheAPILifecycle</guid>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Finding API Governance Balance With Polarity Mapping</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of my most rewarding conversations in my professional career are when I coach folks on their emerging API governance needs. A common myth is that companies &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; settle for one extreme decision-making structure or the other regarding governance. Either they grant API teams full autonomy and suffer from the fragmentation and associated overhead it brings. Or they gain alignment and consistency through centralized oversight and heavy bureaucratic processes while losing innovation opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unquestionably, anything done to an extreme can create negative consequences. However, in my experience, too many companies only see a total commitment to one position or another as their only option. What companies need, in reality, is a blending of the two approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we find the Goldilocks (the “just right”) amount of governance? With a &lt;em&gt;polarity map&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reintroducing-the-polarity-map&quot;&gt;(Re)Introducing the Polarity Map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/11/polarity-map-template-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 1: An Empty Polarity Map; &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamboard.google.com/d/1H4Vj1I6SlgWUPUPCgfzqZIKBIrKNlARG9WJe5xXO180/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;I&apos;ve Made A Google Jamboard Template Available&lt;/a&gt; based on the example from &lt;a href=&quot;https://uxmastery.com/the-joys-of-polarity-mapping/&quot;&gt;UXMastery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ruthmalan.com/Bredemeyer/Org_Dynamics_Masterclass_Overview.htm&quot;&gt;Ruth Malan’s Organizational Design Masterclass&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to polarity mapping. A polarity map recognizes there are benefits and unintended consequences with each extreme. It encourages participants to describe these in detail. Once we’ve identified benefits, we then discuss activities to achieve these desirable traits in our system. After that, we can define a series of measurable indicators. The purpose of these metrics is to signal when we’ve overcorrected and risk unbalancing the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We might use polarity maps for a variety of “versus” articles popular software architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build versus Buy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microservice versus Monolithic Architectures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synchronous versus Asynchronous&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Batch versus Real-Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing versus Debugging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;API-Design First versus API-Code First&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tabs versus Spaces (joking, kinda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polarity maps help explain a phenomenon I observed in previous roles: the “pendulum effect”. If we begin to fill in the map according to the “decentralized versus centralized” API governance, as I described in the beginning, the map looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/11/pm-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 2: A Beginning Polarity Map for Centralized Versus Decentralized Governance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most organizations start API governance in the upper left of the quadrant, “decentralized”: individual API teams have nearly total decision-making autonomy. While this is efficient initially, the problems with this model become more apparent as the size of the API ecosystem grows. The map represents this change with the downward arrow leading to the lower left quadrant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the negatives accrue, support for the opposite pole, or “centralization”, grows. The organization seeks the benefits of the upper right quadrant. This change works, for a while, until the overcorrection creates its adverse effects. If we continue to follow the arrow’s path, we end up in the lower right area. When the downsides reach a critical mass, the organization moves back toward decentralized decision-making and repeats the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting both extremes on a single plot, we can demonstrate benefits to both sides. Moreover, in establishing the oscillation between sides, we can make a case that adopting one or the other is not an argument to be won but a set of properties to balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-a-sample-map&quot;&gt;Getting Started With A Sample Map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the process, let’s walk through an example polarity map that shows what many burgeoning API ecosystems struggle with: *do we promote &lt;strong&gt;centralized&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; API management?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When doing a polarity map, it is essential to remember that each will be different; every company has unique needs, people, goals, and available resources that impact what is listed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/YMMV#English&quot;&gt;YMMV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, based on my own experience, a set of benefits and unintended consequences for both sides might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/11/pm-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 3: An API Governance Polarity Map With Example Benefits and Unintended Consequences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;defining-action-steps-and-early-warnings&quot;&gt;Defining Action Steps and Early Warnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defining &lt;em&gt;benefits&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;unintended consequences&lt;/em&gt; is a significant first step. Talking through effects and their placement on the map is beneficial for building organizational or API leadership team alignment. Where things get truly useful is going to the next level and identifying &lt;strong&gt;action steps&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;early warnings&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/11/pm-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 4: A Polarity Map with Action Steps and Early Warnings Added&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Steps&lt;/strong&gt; are how we will gain or maintain the positive results from focusing on a given pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Warnings&lt;/strong&gt; are quantifiable indicators to signal when a system is straying into the downside of a pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose we want to take actions to promote the positive aspects of centralization (the upper right: “visibility”, “predictability”, “consistency”, etc.). Action may include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documenting API standard operating procedures (including, but not limited to, style guides, production environment readiness requirements, &lt;a href=&quot;https://adr.github.io/&quot;&gt;architectural decision records for changes&lt;/a&gt;, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating compensation or recognition structures for teams demonstrating API excellence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forging communication channels to both promote the best work as well as solicit feedback for further refinement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early warnings for the centralized side of the map may be more challenging to define but not impossible. There could be a problem if there’s a growing clamor of teams waiting on the centralized group for a decision, or a noticeable uptick in meetings to reconcile a tricky edge case. Identify which areas are of most concern for your organization, identify how to quantify changes, and continue to iterate until you have something actionable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The left side is left as an exercise for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polarities&lt;/strong&gt; involve two equally valid and necessary points of view or truths. Despite how we usually think of them, polarities are interdependent pairs that need each other to maintain and gain performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A polarity map is a tool that API leaders can use to  understand where they are in the system and accentuate positive aspects of both worlds. When it comes to API ecosystems, polarity maps suggest that centralized or decentralized decision-making is not final governance destinations but part of a whole to be managed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/01/PolarityMappingAndAPIGovernance</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/11/01/PolarityMappingAndAPIGovernance</guid>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>We Made an API Description, Now What?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Title slide for the deck.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, thank you for being here. I hope you’re healthy and you’re safe, and those that you care about are secure as well. We’ll get through this. I’m sure of it, and someday we will see each other again in person. However, until then, thank goodness we have these kinds of arrangements to share and continue to learn from one another in some form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This presentation is entitled “We wrote an API description, now what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_02.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many organizations, OpenAPI has become the way to capture and share API intent and function. In API-Design-First shops, the creation of an OpenAPI description is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after you’ve created this machine-parsable description, what is next? How do you get the most significant amount of ROI for the time and energy you invested in it? How are others using their OpenAPI artifacts beyond just documentation? And how do you get started? I’ll answer those questions and more in this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_03.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Matthew Reinbold, and I am Postman’s Director of API Ecosystems and Digital Transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Postman, I’m a member of the Open Technologies Program. Our mission is to improve API practice, education, and research for companies of all shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, I also write a weekly API email newsletter. The amount of API-related things published on the web can be overwhelming; Net API Notes started as my attempt to filter the signal from noise - it just turned out that the persistent act of sense-making was valuable to others as well. It also prepares me for conversations like the one we’ll have today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_04.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, though, let’s establish a few things. I’m not going to cover the history of how OpenAPI and AsyncAPI became nearly the defacto API specifications. There are plenty of other talks covering that ground in greater detail - some at this very conference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I do want to clarify how I will use a couple phrases of throughout this presentation. If you use these words differently in your day-to-day work, that is completely fine. For this presentation, however, when I say &lt;strong&gt;API Specification&lt;/strong&gt;, I refer to the specific documented, syntactical requirements an API designer writes to. Examples of API specifications include OpenAPI and AsyncAPI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talk about an &lt;strong&gt;API Definition&lt;/strong&gt;, I refer to the JSON or YAML document that captures your unique API’s business intent, written to meet a specification requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, when I talk about an API specification, I talk about what a standards body writes. When I talk about an API definition, I am talking about what you write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also - in this presentation, I will be sharing or referencing numerous links. If you are interested in those links and don’t want to wait until this presentation is published on my website, go over Twitter and look up the username libel_vox, shown in the footer. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/libel_vox/status/1442929462685757441&quot;&gt;All the links are in a Tweet pinned to my profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_05.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by rewinding the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guido of Arezzo (ur-EH-zoe) was a Benedictine monk living in Italy at the turn of the millennium before last, around 1000 AD. And Guido had a standardized notation problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the pinnacle of popular music was liturgical chants. People went crazy for them. But as Guido visited churches, he noticed how much younger singers struggled to learn the songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was common to have parchments with the words and some occasional squiggles that suggested the performer move their voice higher or lower. However, there was no representation of pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image source: original uploader was Robbot at Dutch Wikipedia. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=1621845*&quot;&gt;Transferred from nl.wikipedia to Commons., Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_06.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution, Guido reasoned, was to invent a means that would allow someone to sing along even if they had never heard the music before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Guido invented the staff. With fixed notes and a specification for conveying them, young students could “better detect the level of pitch”, as Guido wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_07.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People new to APIs also have trouble getting started. And API documentation is usually the first thing people think of when they think of what to do with an API description. Unfortunately, that’s often where it ends, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image on the slide is a grossly simplified development process, but one that is all too common. In it, a bunch of work is done to create a thing and, when it is ready to “go live”, some documentation is made for “the customer”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong - documentation made this way is better than a random PDF or CMS entry - both of those are akin to non-uniform random squiggles Guido’s students previously had. There are many places where you can insert an OpenAPI description and get out some beautifully rendered documentation, either for your dev portal or for sharing with a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, documenting at the end means that the context and nuance of why something is the way it is has to be recreated and reassembled. Because of this, things get left out. The API description, when treated this way, becomes lipstick on a pig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re composing music, one doesn’t wait until the entire song is done before writing something down. In the same way, we need to think about API descriptions as not something that comes at the end but a means at the center of creating a better result in multiple ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_08.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A standardized representation of intent, or an API description, can be used for more than documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we start treating our API description as our central source of truth about the API, rather than an afterthought or “nice-to-have” documentation, a whole host of options open up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of this presentation, I am going to detail four areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code Generation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I’m going to extrapolate a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_09.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s talk about code generation. If you have an API description, whether yours or an API you wish to consume, you are well on your way to having code generated for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_10.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of client code generators available. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/openapitools/openapi-generator&quot;&gt;Open-API generator&lt;/a&gt; supports an incredible number of programming languages. I had to make the type super, super tiny on this slide to fit them all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit that generators won’t write everything. However, getting the tedious, non-differentiated boilerplate out of the way through generation is a huge time saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_11.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it isn’t just client code! You can also stub out a server implementation if you have an OpenAPI description of how an API works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the slide, I have a picture of Postman’s interface. I’ve loaded an OpenAPI 3.0 description. Next to the YAML syntax, I have a button that allows me to create the beginnings of my server code with just a couple of clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servers include Go (Chi), NodeJS (Express), Java (JAX-RS), and Python (Flask). That is a compelling way to kickstart new development and the next logical step with what we can do with these API descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_12.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to generate SDKs from OpenAPI descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with SDKs is finding the team bandwidth to keep feature parity across multiple languages, especially during rapid change. &lt;a href=&quot;https://plaid.com/blog/adopting-the-openapi-schema-to-generate-plaids-sdks&quot;&gt;Plaid has a fantastic case study&lt;/a&gt; detailing how they automatically keep a broad suite of beneficial SDKs in sync and up to date from their OpenAPI sources of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_13.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not just code that we can generate. Let’s take it to the next level and talk about generating code to test code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_14.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing an API is one of the most important things to do. However, not all testing is created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of this pyramid of testing needs, we need to make sure our response payload is as expected; making sure that when we make a request we get the response we intended in the shape expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, we have chaining HTTP calls. Once we know that one request works the way we assume, we start using it in conjunction with other calls as part of more advanced workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving upwards, we have data-driven requests. This level is where we take our static requests and begin to change the data provided. In doing so, we being discovering the rough edges and uncovering assumptions about ongoing usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearing the top are negative tests and error flows. In other words, at this level we’re purposely stepping off the “happy path” and evaluating how gracefully the API fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, at the top of the pyramid, we have contract testing. Testing at this level is no longer about the API we’re creating but verifying the consistent behavior of other APIs we might be dependent on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many pyramids, every level is sized in approximate proportion to how much effort should be expended. So, for example, companies should spend a large amount of effort verifying that the response payloads are structured correctly or at the bottommost level before moving upwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, where people should put the bulk of their effort also happens to be some of the most tedious work. Therefore, it is a no-brainer that we leverage an API description to provide the necessary coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://netapinotes.com/p/net-api-notes-for-2021-08-04-issue-170&quot;&gt;This version of the API testing pyramid inspired by the test pyramid featured in Net API Notes Issue 170&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_15.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A valid OpenAPI document inside Postman can be used to create test cases to be run across multiple endpoints. Or you can customize on a per-endpoint basis. Like code generation, generating tests free brain cycles on solving higher-level, more challenging problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That generation is possible because we have a standardized notation that conveys our intent even if we haven’t seen the API before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_16.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things get really interesting when we take that code and tests that we previously created and connect it to automation. We are now able to aggregate and monitor a complex system. We can “see” not just individual APIs for the trees they are. Instead, monitoring whole collections of APIs gives us a sense of the larger forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_17.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Postman’s founder, Abhinav, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.postman.com/new-postman-api-platform-redefining-api-management-for-api-first-world/&quot;&gt;shared a vision of the API platform landscape&lt;/a&gt;. And there are many companies in that view that perform what we call API monitoring: using a remote computer to send requests to an API on a scheduled basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ensuring that an API is running or not is the same thing we were doing a decade ago. It is important, but it also scratches the surface of the complex automation possible with API descriptions and some simple bridge code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_18.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many are familiar with the website, If-This-Then-That (IFTTT). With API descriptions, creating workflows via the Postman monitor is nearly as easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, the purpose of the Postman Open Technology Program is to elevate API practice across all industries. As you might imagine, that entails a lot of writing. Rather than just using a monitor to tell me whether services I care about are up or down, I created a workflow to prompt me to complete my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used an OpenAPI description to create a call to my cloud-hosted markdown editor. That gets me the words I’ve written so far daily. I put together some logic to not worry about weekends because the worst thing is stress-inducing notifications during recovery time. Finally, I merged that with the results from another OpenAPI description that gets and parses US holidays - again, alarms aren’t going off when I am recuperating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does require a &lt;em&gt;bit&lt;/em&gt; more work than dragging lines between colorful chicklets (Rest In Peace, Yahoo! Pipes!). However, if you have standardized service representation, exciting workflow automation is at your fingertips. We’ve gone beyond just testing APIs to creating &lt;strong&gt;low-code solutions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s empowering for the people in your organizations who may not be full-blown developers but still want to take advantage of information and services already available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_19.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An API journey doesn’t start with a cast of thousands. For most companies, their first API began as a targeted means to a specific business end. Scaling architectures, processes, training, and tooling was far from the minds of all involved at the onset, as it should be - a town doesn’t build its public works department when there are only a few homesteads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, with more people creating APIs more experiences, architectural styles, and bespoke infrastructure are introduced into the growing API ecosystem. In the absence of repeatable processes, preferred techniques, or uniform tooling, the results from API production will become unpredictable - coordination costs across unaligned pockets of practice increase along with inefficiency. Higher-order alignment suffers. As described in the book Accelerate, “teams become adrift, concentrated on micro-optimizations disconnected from aligned business delivery”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody needs to be concerned with those higher-order concerns and the health of the ecosystem. Many might assume that necessitates a cumbersome, gatekeeping API review. However, with API descriptions, there are several lightweight, helpful things we can do to encourage alignment while maintaining team autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_20.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create consistency in approaches, many companies create API style guides. But just having a proposal of what people should do is not enough. Just because something is written down does not mean it will be interpreted and presented in an API description the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the slide, in gray, I have an example suggestion for pagination that you might find in a style guide. It encourages the developer to use the words “limit” and “offset” when giving callers the ability to page through a collection of items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may seem straightforward. However, what happens in practice is something akin to what appears on the left side of the slide, in purple. Yes, the author included the words “limit” and “offset”. But the articulation of how these two keywords are used is still vague. As a caller of this API, we may assume that both are numeric values with some certainty. However, several questions remain. Is there a maximum value for “limit”? Is offset 0-indexed? What is the default page size?  Are these values to be passed only as query params, or do they also work as header values?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The API description on the left meets the letter of the law, but not the spirit; this API’s user has to spend additional time and energy to figure out how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should we berate an API designer, especially one new to the company, for not magically including all the additional verbiage of the right-hand example? OF COURSE NOT!  “Just knowing” is hard. The style guide should make doing the right thing easy! Rather than leaving the right thing up to interpretation, the style guide should provide the desired YAML or JSON representations for anyone to copy and paste into their designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds straightforward because it is! Creating meaningful templates and snippets that solve everyday problems creates alignment because you’ve made doing the right thing easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/08/18/OneWayToImproveAPIGuidance&quot;&gt;I’m written more about these approaches on my website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_21.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, several tools can parse an API description and nudge practice to a healthier place. Using tools in this way is a much healthier practice than manual reviews, where suddenly it is a contest of will over who is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of API validators. &lt;a href=&quot;https://openapi.tools/&quot;&gt;OpenAPI.tools&lt;/a&gt;, the picture on the left, does a fantastic job of categorizing many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mermade.org.uk/openapi-converter&quot;&gt;OpenAPI Converter&lt;/a&gt; can also take an API description in a variety of formats. Both can be used to ensure an API description adherence to expectations, thus avoiding fragmentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_22.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is a pressing issue at the moment. As I’m showing here in the slide, the tool is warning the API author that not only are they not providing any authorization for these endpoints, but the entirety of communication is happening over unsecured HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll continue to see tooling get more opinionated. Thus better supporting API designers with insights when it is most beneficial - while they are designing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_23.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a quick run through four areas - code gen, testing, monitoring, and governance that can benefit today from a description-centric approach. But let’s go even further. What happens when entire industries can sing from the same songbook?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_24.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=csHOifygBA0&quot;&gt;I love this story that Jean Yang, founder and CEO of Akita software, shared recently&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Akita software was to help developers make sense of their complex distributed systems. They began to approach the problem in a systems way and briefly considered integration with open telemetry or maybe integrate with a service mesh like Envoy. The problem was that there had been no standardization; not everybody uses a service mesh, and when they do, it isn’t always Envoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akita realized that APIs provided a standardized point that was uniformly consistent across all providers, architectures, and languages. Because services had adopted this common lingua franca, they were able to build a new set of observations and insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_25.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stedi.com/&quot;&gt;a company called Stedi is doing some fantastic things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDI, or Electronic Data Interchange, has been around since the 1970s. It attempts to standardize the exchange of business information, like purchase orders and invoices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stedi applies modern approaches to schema validation, like JSON schema, to EDI. In the process, a whole suite of modern tooling can be leveraged for working with legacy formats; unlocking new value and opportunities in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_26.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, back to this guy - back to Guido.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the centuries since Guido invented standardized musical notation, there were many additions. First there was duration. Then barlines, stylized clefs, dynamic markings, ties, and slurs were added. These changes supported a growing number of instruments and vocal styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music grew beyond liturgical chants. The Renaissance era, where music tended to remain on a single tempo for the duration of the piece, gave way to the Baroque period, one marked by increased composition creativity. Baroque also established the opera, concerto, and sonata as musical genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This expansion didn’t happen in isolation. It is no coincidence that this creativity occurred when people had a greater ability to capture and share their intent. The development of a standardized notation, a specification, allowed composers to cross-pollinate, enrich, and evolve each others’ work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_27.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But unless you’re a music nerd, that may be trivia. Let’s make this less abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help students remember his new standard, Guido also invented something else you might be familiar with; a mnemonic that helps people remember the steps between tones on his staff. You probably know it: do-re-mi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mnemonic is featured prominently in the 1965 film Sound of Music. That film, and the von Trapp children within, was seen by millions - including my wife and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have a Gretl, but I have a Greta. I also have a Liesel. Guido, in 1000 AD, wouldn’t know what a movie was, let alone comprehend his influence on it. Furthermore, he couldn’t conceive how a standard representation would ultimately influence my daughters’ names. &lt;em&gt;But it did&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swagger, the predecessor of the OpenAPI specification, came out in 2010, a little more than a decade ago! It’s not even a teenager yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emergence from complex systems is an unpredictable thing. Our APIs ecosystems are complex systems. Who knows what future will emerge from the API descriptions that we create and share today? Whatever it is, I can’t wait to see what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_28.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your time. If you want to get ahold of me, you can go to my website. You can also check out my email newsletter, and I’m pretty responsive on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/10/ASC 2021 - Wrote an API Description, Now What_29.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/10/01/WeMadeAnAPIDescription</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/10/01/WeMadeAnAPIDescription</guid>
                
                <category>Presentations</category>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Overcoming Change Resistance</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2021/09/lets-change.png&quot; alt=&quot;A sign outside a building that says &apos;Let&apos;s Change&apos;.&quot; /&gt;
Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@visualsbybrad?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Brad Starkey&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/change?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve got an excellent idea for your organization. You’ve spent time &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/10/CreatingCompellingStories&quot;&gt;carefully crafting your story&lt;/a&gt; and begin to share it. Then something begins to happen; perhaps there isn’t anything as dramatic as a slammed door or “NO” screamed in all caps. But there’s a hesitation, an avoidance, or an ongoing series of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whataboutism&quot;&gt;whataboutism&lt;/a&gt;” that increasingly frustrates and drains energy. Congratulations, change agent! You’ve met &lt;strong&gt;resistance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workplace changes are &lt;em&gt;sociotechnical&lt;/em&gt;, or having both a technical and a social aspect. The technical change part is the mechanics of how a task is performed. There might be technical detail and nuance to be debated. However, what is a far more significant source of resistance is the social aspect of the change. &lt;em&gt;Social&lt;/em&gt; refers to how those affected by the change believe it will &lt;em&gt;alter their organizational relationships&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change, even wholesome, necessary, and positive, can provoke a sense of loss in individuals. Sometimes this sense of loss is legitimate, like when a company closes down its “innovation hub” or no longer recognizes “Quality Assurance (QA)” as distinct from the engineering job family. In other situations, the change is perceived as a loss of dominance, control, power, and/or a sense of familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People react to loss in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resisting-change&quot;&gt;Resisting Change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one case, they dig in and close down. Those resisting demand what is lost be returned. &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/10/CreatingCompellingStories&quot;&gt;Without a recognized, new identity for the participants&lt;/a&gt;, our change narrative induces a counter-narrative: an energetic incitement to &lt;em&gt;return to the way things were&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1969/01/how-to-deal-with-resistance-to-change&quot;&gt;As this classic 1969 Harvard Business Review article by American sociologist Paul R. Lawrence states&lt;/a&gt;, resistance manifests as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“persistent reduction in output, an increase in the number of “quits” and requests for transfer, chronic quarrels, sullen hostility, wildcat or slowdown strikes, and, of course, the expression of a lot of pseudological reasons why the change will not work. Even the more petty forms of this resistance can be troublesome.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This response is so typical that many executives assume resistance to anything is inevitable. Yet, changes must occur for businesses to thrive. This doubly for the all-important “little” changes that constantly take place: changes in work methods, in routine office procedures, in the location of a machine or a desk, in personnel assignments and job titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You never want a perfectly fit, coherent, and therefore stable system (therein lies stasis and death)… for a system to evolve and thereby persist over time requires a certain (unspecified!) resilience more so than stability.” – Alicia Juarrero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opening-oneself-and-others-to-change&quot;&gt;Opening Oneself (And Others) To Change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; way people might respond is to &lt;strong&gt;open up&lt;/strong&gt;. This opening requires a shared assumption that there is something new here and that we will find our way into that newness together. What does that mean, practically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to getting buy-in to a change is when those affected by it are co-creators. While this participation may sound simple in theory, in practice, it does entail careful handling. Participation &lt;em&gt;is a feeling on the part of people&lt;/em&gt;, a belief that their needs are being heard and concerns addressed. Participation &lt;em&gt;is not&lt;/em&gt; inviting people to comment or attend a meeting and checking the box ‘done’. Employees must be treated as having treasured insight and opinions rather than a target to be pumped for carefully calculated questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why the identity piece of our storytelling is so critical. A future vision they can relate to, and the relationships it entails, will mitigate the sense of social loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-api-governance-example&quot;&gt;An API Governance Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As companies grow, the complexity introduced due to fragmented API design approaches and ad-hoc, laissez-faire governance drowns any benefit the API ecosystem had while new. In this state, integrations take longer, meetings go up, and estimates get more untrustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, leadership may move to establish one of any number of groups: Centers of Excellence, Design Guilds, Architectural Review Board, or API Champions. The expectation is that these specialists are inserted between the “doers” and the production environment. Their job is to ensure that designs are “done right”, mitigating the mishmash (and related overhead) that the organization increasingly toils under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this approach, if done unilaterally, is that leadership has introduced not only a technical change - the specific THOU SHALL and THOU SHALL NOT that moves an architectural style from &lt;em&gt;descriptive&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;prescriptive&lt;/em&gt;. They have also changed an API developer’s relationship with the organization by inserting an oversite group in the pipeline. The usual work relationships, not just between developers and their peers, but developers and their environments, were changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discussed above, changing the social relationships nets more than just “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Moved_My_Cheese%3F&quot;&gt;who moved my cheese&lt;/a&gt;” or “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftrain.com/wwic&quot;&gt;why wasn’t I consulted&lt;/a&gt;” whinging. The sense of loss breeds resentment, resentment creates low morale, and the quality and alignment initiative meets resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean the idea to decrease fragmentation and improve design cohesion was a bad one! What it means, instead, is that a different approach is needed. Rather than a top-down directive that changes the entire organization’s working relationships, the affected parts of the organization should be invited to co-create the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That includes &lt;em&gt;listening first, talking second&lt;/em&gt;. It could be that not everyone agrees on what the problem &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt;. If people are given a chance to come up with ideas, discuss the ideas of others, or otherwise be involved in the process, they’ll become invested in the change and understand it better. It is also easier to build a future inclusive identity in your narrative if those people were involved in defining that identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change has both a technical and a social aspect. The technical aspect of change is about making a measurable modification in the job’s routines or practices. Change’s social aspect refers to the way those affected by change think it will alter relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can get better about addressing the social needs of people during change, we will better positioned for long term success. Again, from the 1969 article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The significance of these research findings, from management’s point of view, is that executives and staff experts need not expertness in using the devices of participation but a real understanding, in depth and detail, of the specific social arrangements that will be sustained or threatened by the change or by the way in which it is introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologies come and go. But people remain the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/22/OvercomingChangeResistance</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matthewreinbold.com/2021/09/22/OvercomingChangeResistance</guid>
                
                <category>Software Governance</category>
                
                <category>Software Change</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>